<theme>
    <variables>
        <systemName>Adventure Game Studio</systemName>
        <systemDescription>Adventure Game Studio (AGS) is an open source development tool primarily used to create graphic adventure games. It is aimed at intermediate-level game designers, and combines an integrated development environment (IDE) with a scripting language based on the C programming language to process game logic.</systemDescription>
        <systemManufacturer>Chris Jones</systemManufacturer>
        <systemReleaseYear>1997</systemReleaseYear>
        <systemReleaseDate>1997</systemReleaseDate>
        <systemReleaseDateFormated>1997</systemReleaseDateFormated>
        <systemHardwareType>Engine</systemHardwareType>
        <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
        <systemCoverSizeType>square</systemCoverSizeType>
        <systemColor>4B73E0</systemColor>
        <systemColorPalette1>9FCFFF</systemColorPalette1>
        <systemColorPalette2>63B6FF</systemColorPalette2>
        <systemColorPalette3>2C90FF</systemColorPalette3>
        <systemColorPalette4>9FCFFF</systemColorPalette4>
        <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
    </variables>
    <language name="ar_SA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>استوديو ألعاب المغامرات (AGS) هو أداة تطوير مفتوحة المصدر تُستخدم بشكل أساسي لإنشاء ألعاب المغامرات الرسومية. وهو موجه لمصممي الألعاب ذوي المستوى المتوسط، ويجمع بين بيئة تطوير متكاملة (IDE) ولغة برمجة نصية تستند إلى لغة البرمجة C لمعالجة منطق اللعبة.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>المحرك</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="bs_BA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Avanturistički igra Studio (AGS) je otvoreni razvojni alat za razvoj sova koji se prvenstveno koristi za stvaranje grafičkih avantura. Cilja je na dizajnere igre u razini i kombinira integrirani razvojni okruženje (IDE) sa skriptnim jezikom na osnovu jezika C programiranja za obradu logike igre.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Motor</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ca_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Adventure Game Studio (AGS) és una eina de desenvolupament de codi obert que s’utilitza principalment per crear jocs d’aventura gràfiques. Està dirigit a dissenyadors de jocs de nivell intermedi i combina un entorn integrat de desenvolupament (IDE) amb un llenguatge de script basat en el llenguatge de programació C per processar la lògica del joc.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Engine</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="de_DE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Adventure Game Studio (AGS) ist ein Open-Source-Entwicklungstool, das in erster Linie zur Erstellung von grafischen Abenteuerspielen verwendet wird. Es richtet sich an fortgeschrittene Spieleentwickler und kombiniert eine integrierte Entwicklungsumgebung (IDE) mit einer auf der Programmiersprache C basierenden Skriptsprache zur Verarbeitung der Spiellogik.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Motor</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="es_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Adventure Game Studio (AGS) es una herramienta de desarrollo de código abierto utilizada principalmente para crear aventuras gráficas. Está dirigida a diseñadores de juegos de nivel intermedio y combina un entorno de desarrollo integrado (IDE) con un lenguaje de scripting basado en el lenguaje de programación C para procesar la lógica del juego.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Motor</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="fr_FR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Adventure Game Studio (AGS) est un outil de développement open source principalement utilisé pour créer des jeux d'aventure graphiques. Il s'adresse aux concepteurs de jeux de niveau intermédiaire et combine un environnement de développement intégré (IDE) avec un langage de script basé sur le langage de programmation C pour traiter la logique du jeu.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Moteur</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="hr_HR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Adventure Game Studio (AGS) je alat za razvoj otvorenog koda koji se prvenstveno koristi za stvaranje grafičkih avanturističkih igara. Namijenjen je dizajnerima igara na srednjoj razini i kombinira integrirano razvojno okruženje (IDE) s jezikom skriptiranja na temelju programskih jezika C za obradu logike igara.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Motor</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="it_IT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Adventure Game Studio (AGS) è uno strumento di sviluppo open source utilizzato principalmente per creare giochi di avventura grafica. Si rivolge a progettisti di giochi di livello intermedio e combina un ambiente di sviluppo integrato (IDE) con un linguaggio di scripting basato sul linguaggio di programmazione C per elaborare la logica di gioco.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Motore</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ja_JP">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Adventure Game Studio（AGS）は、主にグラフィックアドベンチャーゲームの制作に使用されるオープンソースの開発ツールである。中級レベルのゲームデザイナーを対象としており、統合開発環境（IDE）と、ゲームロジックを処理するためのCプログラミング言語をベースとしたスクリプト言語を組み合わせています。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>エンジン</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ko_KR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>어드벤처 게임 스튜디오(AGS)는 주로 그래픽 어드벤처 게임을 제작하는 데 사용되는 오픈 소스 개발 도구입니다. 중급 수준의 게임 디자이너를 대상으로 하며, 통합 개발 환경(IDE)과 게임 로직을 처리하는 C 프로그래밍 언어 기반의 스크립팅 언어를 결합한 툴입니다.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>엔진</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="nl_NL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Adventure Game Studio (AGS) is een open source ontwikkeltool die voornamelijk wordt gebruikt om grafische avonturenspellen te maken. Het is gericht op gamedesigners van gemiddeld niveau en combineert een geïntegreerde ontwikkelomgeving (IDE) met een scripttaal gebaseerd op de programmeertaal C om gamelogica te verwerken.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Motor</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pl_PL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Adventure Game Studio (AGS) to narzędzie programistyczne typu open source, wykorzystywane głównie do tworzenia graficznych gier przygodowych. Jest przeznaczone dla średnio zaawansowanych projektantów gier i łączy zintegrowane środowisko programistyczne (IDE) z językiem skryptowym opartym na języku programowania C do przetwarzania logiki gry.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Silnik</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_BR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O Adventure Game Studio (AGS) é uma ferramenta de desenvolvimento de código aberto usada principalmente para criar jogos gráficos de aventura. Destina-se a designers de jogos de nível intermediário e combina um ambiente de desenvolvimento integrado (IDE) com uma linguagem de script baseada na linguagem de programação C para processar a lógica do jogo.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Motor</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_PT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O Adventure Game Studio (AGS) é uma ferramenta de desenvolvimento de código aberto usado principalmente para criar jogos de aventura gráfica. Ele visa os designers de jogos de nível intermediário e combina um ambiente de desenvolvimento integrado (IDE) com uma linguagem de script com base na linguagem de programação C para processar a lógica do jogo.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Motor</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ro_RO">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Adventure Game Studio (AGS) este un instrument de dezvoltare open source utilizat în principal pentru a crea jocuri de aventuri grafice. Acesta se adresează designerilor de jocuri de nivel mediu și combină un mediu de dezvoltare integrat (IDE) cu un limbaj de scripting bazat pe limbajul de programare C pentru a procesa logica jocului.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Motor</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ru_RU">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Adventure Game Studio (AGS) - это инструмент разработки с открытым исходным кодом, используемый в основном для создания графических приключенческих игр. Он ориентирован на гейм-дизайнеров среднего уровня и сочетает в себе интегрированную среду разработки (IDE) и скриптовый язык, основанный на языке программирования C, для обработки игровой логики.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Двигатель</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sr_RS">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Авантуристички игри студио (АГС) је средство за развој отвореног кода који се првенствено користи за креирање графичких авантуристичких игара.Циљ то је намењено дизајнерима игара на нивоу и комбинује интегрисано развојно окружење (ИДЕ) са језиком скрипта заснован на програмирању програма за обраду логике игре.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Мотор</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sv_SE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Adventure Game Studio (AGS) är ett utvecklingsverktyg med öppen källkod som främst används för att skapa grafiska äventyrsspel. Det riktar sig till speldesigners på mellannivå och kombinerar en integrerad utvecklingsmiljö (IDE) med ett skriptspråk baserat på programmeringsspråket C för att bearbeta spellogik.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Motor</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_CN">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Adventure Game Studio（AGS）是一款开源开发工具，主要用于创建图形冒险游戏。它面向中级游戏设计师，将集成开发环境（IDE）与基于 C 编程语言的脚本语言相结合，用于处理游戏逻辑。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>发动机</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_TW">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Adventure Game Studio (AGS) 是一款開放原始碼開發工具，主要用來製作圖形冒險遊戲。它針對中階遊戲設計師，結合了整合開發環境 (IDE) 與基於 C 程式語言的腳本語言來處理遊戲邏輯。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>引擎</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
</theme>
