<theme>
    <variables>
        <systemName>Philips CD-i</systemName>
        <systemDescription>The Philips CD-i (Compact Disc Interactive) is an interactive multimedia CD player developed and marketed by Royal Philips Electronics N.V. This category of device was created to provide more functionality than an audio CD player or game console, but at a lower price than a personal computer with CD-ROM drive at the time. The cost savings were due to the lack of a hard drive, floppy drive, keyboard, mouse, monitor (a standard television was used), and less operating system software. In addition to games, educational and multimedia reference titles were produced, such as interactive encyclopedias, museum tours, etc. before public Internet access was widespread. Competitors included the Tandy VIS and Commodore CDTV. Seen as a game console, the CD-i format proved to be a commercial failure. The company lost nearly one billion dollars on the entire project. The failure of the CD-i caused Philips to leave the video game industry after it was discontinued. The CD-i is also one of the earliest consoles to implement internet features, including subscriptions, web browsing, downloading, e-mail, and online play. This was facilitated by the use of an additional hardware modem that Philips released in 1996.</systemDescription>
        <systemManufacturer>Philips</systemManufacturer>
        <systemReleaseYear>1991</systemReleaseYear>
        <systemReleaseDate>1991-12-03</systemReleaseDate>
        <systemReleaseDateFormated>December 3, 1991</systemReleaseDateFormated>
        <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
        <systemCoverSizeType>square</systemCoverSizeType>
        <systemColor>c47ca6</systemColor>
        <systemColorPalette1>000000</systemColorPalette1>
        <systemColorPalette2>E70000</systemColorPalette2>
        <systemColorPalette3>FFFFFF</systemColorPalette3>
        <systemColorPalette4>0B5ED8</systemColorPalette4>
        <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
    </variables>
    <language name="ar_SA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>جهاز CD-i (القرص المضغوط التفاعلي) من فيليبس هو مشغل أقراص مضغوطة تفاعلي متعدد الوسائط تم تطويره وتسويقه من قبل شركة رويال فيليبس للإلكترونيات (Royal Philips Electronics N.V.) وقد تم إنشاء هذه الفئة من الأجهزة لتوفير وظائف أكثر من مشغل الأقراص المضغوطة الصوتية أو وحدة التحكم في الألعاب، ولكن بسعر أقل من سعر الكمبيوتر الشخصي المزود بمحرك أقراص مضغوطة في ذلك الوقت. ويرجع التوفير في التكلفة إلى عدم وجود محرك أقراص صلبة ومحرك أقراص مرنة ولوحة مفاتيح وفأرة وشاشة (تم استخدام تلفاز قياسي) وبرامج نظام تشغيل أقل. وبالإضافة إلى الألعاب، تم إنتاج عناوين مرجعية تعليمية ومتعددة الوسائط، مثل الموسوعات التفاعلية والجولات في المتاحف وما إلى ذلك قبل انتشار الوصول العام إلى الإنترنت. وكان من بين المنافسين جهاز Tandy VIS و Commodore CDTV. وقد ثبت أن تنسيق CD-i، الذي كان يُنظر إليه كوحدة تحكم في الألعاب، كان فاشلاً تجارياً. فقد خسرت الشركة ما يقرب من مليار دولار على المشروع بأكمله. وتسبب فشل CD-i في ترك فيليبس لصناعة ألعاب الفيديو بعد توقفها. يعد CD-i أيضًا من أوائل وحدات التحكم التي طبقت ميزات الإنترنت، بما في ذلك الاشتراكات وتصفح الويب والتنزيل والبريد الإلكتروني واللعب عبر الإنترنت. وقد تم تسهيل ذلك من خلال استخدام مودم إضافي للأجهزة أصدرته Philips في عام 1996.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>وحدة التحكم</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="bs_BA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Philips CD-I (kompaktni disk interaktivni) je interaktivni multimedijalni CD player razvijen i marketirao Royal Philips Electronics N. V. Ova kategorija uređaja stvorena je za pružanje više funkcionalnosti od audio CD uređaja ili na nižoj cijeni od ličnog računala s CD-ROM uređajem u to vrijeme. Ušteda troškova nastala je zbog nedostatka tvrdog diska, diskete, tipkovnice, miša, monitora (korištena standardna televizija) i manje softvera operativnog sistema. Pored igara, proizvedene su edukativne i multimedijske referentne naslove, poput interaktivnih enciklopedija, muzejskih tura itd. Prije javnog interneta bio je rasprostranjen. Natjecatelji su uključivali Tandy Vis i Commodore CDTV. Gledano kao igračka konzola, CD-I format se pokazao kao komercijalni kvar. Kompanija je na cijelom projektu izgubila gotovo milijardu dolara. Neuspjeh CD-a - izazvao sam Philips da napuste industriju video igara nakon što je prekinuta. CD-I je takođe jedna od najranijih konzola za implementaciju internetskih značajki, uključujući pretplate, web pretraživanje, preuzimanje, e-poštu i online reprodukciju. To je olakšalo korištenje dodatnog hardverskog modema koji je Philips objavio 1996. godine.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Konzola</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ca_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>El Philips CD-I (Compact Disc Interactive) és un reproductor de CD multimèdia interactiu desenvolupat i comercialitzat per Royal Philips Electronics N. V. Aquesta categoria de dispositiu va ser creada per proporcionar més funcionalitat que un reproductor de CD o consola de jocs d'àudioordinador personal amb unitat de CD-ROM en aquell moment. L’estalvi de costos es va deure a la manca d’un disc dur, disquet, teclat, ratolí, monitor (es va utilitzar un televisor estàndard) i menys programari del sistema operatiu. A més dels jocs, es van produir títols de referència educatius i multimèdia, com enciclopèdies interactives, visites museístiques, etc. abans que l’accés públic a Internet fos generalitzat. Entre els competidors es van incloure el CDTV de Tandy Vis i Commodore. Vist com una consola de jocs, el format CD-I va resultar ser un fracàs comercial. La companyia va perdre prop de mil milions de dòlars en tot el projecte. El fracàs del CD-I va fer que Philips abandonés la indústria dels videojocs un cop es va suspendre. El CD-I també és una de les primeres consoles per implementar funcions a Internet, incloses subscripcions, navegació web, descàrrega, correu electrònic i joc en línia. Això es va facilitar per l’ús d’un mòdem de maquinari addicional que Philips va publicar el 1996.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="de_DE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Der Philips CD-i (Compact Disc Interactive) ist ein interaktiver Multimedia-CD-Spieler, der von der Royal Philips Electronics N.V. entwickelt und vermarktet wurde. Diese Gerätekategorie wurde geschaffen, um mehr Funktionen als ein Audio-CD-Spieler oder eine Spielkonsole zu bieten, aber zu einem niedrigeren Preis als ein Personal Computer mit CD-ROM-Laufwerk zu dieser Zeit. Die Kosteneinsparungen ergaben sich aus dem Fehlen einer Festplatte, eines Diskettenlaufwerks, einer Tastatur, einer Maus, eines Monitors (es wurde ein Standardfernseher verwendet) und einer geringeren Anzahl von Betriebssystemen. Neben Spielen wurden auch Bildungs- und Multimedia-Nachschlagewerke produziert, wie z. B. interaktive Enzyklopädien, Museumsführungen usw., bevor der öffentliche Internetzugang weit verbreitet war. Zu den Konkurrenten gehörten der Tandy VIS und der Commodore CDTV. Als Spielkonsole betrachtet, erwies sich das CD-i-Format als kommerzieller Misserfolg. Das Unternehmen verlor fast eine Milliarde Dollar mit dem gesamten Projekt. Der Misserfolg des CD-i veranlasste Philips, die Videospielindustrie zu verlassen, nachdem das Produkt eingestellt wurde. Die CD-i ist auch eine der ersten Konsolen, die Internetfunktionen wie Abonnements, Surfen im Internet, Herunterladen, E-Mail und Online-Spielen bietet. Dies wurde durch die Verwendung eines zusätzlichen Hardware-Modems ermöglicht, das Philips 1996 auf den Markt brachte.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Konsole</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="es_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>El Philips CD-i (Compact Disc Interactive) es un reproductor de CD multimedia interactivo desarrollado y comercializado por Royal Philips Electronics N.V. Esta categoría de dispositivo se creó para ofrecer más funciones que un reproductor de CD de audio o una consola de juegos, pero a un precio inferior al de un ordenador personal con unidad de CD-ROM de la época. El ahorro de costes se debía a la ausencia de disco duro, disquetera, teclado, ratón, monitor (se utilizaba un televisor estándar) y menos software del sistema operativo. Además de juegos, se produjeron títulos de referencia educativos y multimedia, como enciclopedias interactivas, visitas a museos, etc., antes de que se generalizara el acceso público a Internet. Entre sus competidores se encontraban el Tandy VIS y el Commodore CDTV. Considerado como una consola de juegos, el formato CD-i resultó ser un fracaso comercial. La empresa perdió casi mil millones de dólares en todo el proyecto. El fracaso del CD-i hizo que Philips abandonara la industria del videojuego tras su interrupción. El CD-i fue también una de las primeras consolas en incorporar funciones de Internet, como suscripciones, navegación web, descargas, correo electrónico y juego en línea. Esto se vio facilitado por el uso de un módem de hardware adicional que Philips puso a la venta en 1996.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Consola</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="fr_FR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Le Philips CD-i (Compact Disc Interactive) est un lecteur de CD multimédia interactif développé et commercialisé par Royal Philips Electronics N.V. Cette catégorie d'appareils a été créée pour offrir plus de fonctionnalités qu'un lecteur de CD audio ou une console de jeu, mais à un prix inférieur à celui d'un ordinateur personnel doté d'un lecteur de CD-ROM à l'époque. Les économies réalisées sont dues à l'absence de disque dur, de lecteur de disquette, de clavier, de souris, d'écran (un téléviseur standard était utilisé) et de logiciel d'exploitation. Outre les jeux, des titres de référence éducatifs et multimédias ont été produits, tels que des encyclopédies interactives, des visites de musées, etc. avant que l'accès public à l'internet ne soit largement répandu. Les concurrents comprenaient le Tandy VIS et le Commodore CDTV. Considéré comme une console de jeu, le format CD-i s'est avéré être un échec commercial. La société a perdu près d'un milliard de dollars sur l'ensemble du projet. L'échec du CD-i a poussé Philips à quitter l'industrie du jeu vidéo après son abandon. Le CD-i est également l'une des premières consoles à intégrer des fonctions Internet, notamment des abonnements, la navigation sur le web, le téléchargement, le courrier électronique et le jeu en ligne. Cela a été facilité par l'utilisation d'un modem matériel supplémentaire que Philips a mis sur le marché en 1996.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="hr_HR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Philips CD-I (Compact Disc Interactive) interaktivni je multimedijski CD player koji je razvio i plasirao na tržište Royal Philips Electronics N. V. Ova je kategorija uređaja stvorena kako bi osigurala više funkcionalnosti od audio CD playera ili konzole za igru, ali po nižoj cijeni od osobnog računala s CD-ROM pogonom u to vrijeme. Ušteda troškova nastala je zbog nedostatka tvrdog diska, diskete, tipkovnice, miša, monitora (korištena je standardna televizija) i manje softvera operativnog sustava. Pored igara, izrađeni su edukativni i multimedijski referentni naslovi, poput interaktivnih enciklopedija, turneja muzeja itd. Prije nego što je javni pristup internetu bio široko rasprostranjen. Natjecatelji su uključivali Tandy Vis i Commodore CDTV. Gledano kao igračka konzola, CD-I format pokazao se kao komercijalni neuspjeh. Tvrtka je izgubila gotovo milijardu dolara na cijelom projektu. Neuspjeh CD-I uzrokovao je Philips da napusti industriju videoigara nakon što je ukinut. CD-I je također jedna od najranijih konzola za implementaciju internetskih značajki, uključujući pretplate, pregledavanje web mjesta, preuzimanje, e-poštu i internetsku igru. To je olakšano korištenjem dodatnog hardverskog modema koji je Philips objavio 1996. godine.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Konzola</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="it_IT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Il Philips CD-i (Compact Disc Interactive) è un lettore CD multimediale interattivo sviluppato e commercializzato da Royal Philips Electronics N.V. Questa categoria di dispositivi è stata creata per fornire più funzionalità di un lettore CD audio o di una console per videogiochi, ma a un prezzo inferiore rispetto a quello di un personal computer con unità CD-ROM dell'epoca. La riduzione dei costi era dovuta all'assenza di disco rigido, unità floppy, tastiera, mouse, monitor (si utilizzava un televisore standard) e una minore quantità di software del sistema operativo. Oltre ai giochi, furono prodotti titoli di riferimento educativi e multimediali, come enciclopedie interattive, visite ai musei, ecc. prima che l'accesso pubblico a Internet fosse diffuso. Tra i concorrenti vi erano il Tandy VIS e il Commodore CDTV. Considerato come una console per videogiochi, il formato CD-i si rivelò un fallimento commerciale. L'azienda perse quasi un miliardo di dollari per l'intero progetto. L'insuccesso del CD-i portò Philips ad abbandonare il settore dei videogiochi dopo la sua dismissione. Il CD-i è anche una delle prime console a implementare le funzionalità di Internet, tra cui abbonamenti, navigazione sul Web, download, e-mail e gioco online. Ciò è stato facilitato dall'uso di un modem hardware aggiuntivo che Philips ha rilasciato nel 1996.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ja_JP">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Philips CD-i（Compact Disc Interactive）は、Royal Philips Electronics N.V.が開発・販売したインタラクティブ・マルチメディアCDプレーヤーである。このカテゴリの機器は、オーディオCDプレーヤーやゲーム機よりも高機能でありながら、当時のCD-ROMドライブ付きパソコンよりも低価格を実現するために作られた。ハードドライブ、フロッピードライブ、キーボード、マウス、モニター（標準的なテレビが使われた）がなく、オペレーティングシステムソフトウェアも少なかったため、コスト削減ができた。ゲームだけでなく、インタラクティブな百科事典や博物館ツアーなど、教育的でマルチメディアなレファレンス・タイトルも、一般のインターネット・アクセスが普及する前に制作された。競合機種としては、タンディVISやコモドールCDTVがあった。ゲーム機として見られたCD-iフォーマットは、商業的には失敗に終わった。同社はプロジェクト全体で10億ドル近い損失を出した。CD-iの失敗により、フィリップスは製造中止後、ビデオゲーム業界から撤退した。CD-iはまた、定額制、ウェブブラウジング、ダウンロード、電子メール、オンラインプレイなどのインターネット機能を実装した初期のゲーム機のひとつでもある。これは、フィリップスが1996年に発売した追加ハードウェアモデムの使用によって実現した。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>コンソール</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ko_KR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>필립스 CD-i(컴팩트 디스크 인터랙티브)는 로열 필립스 일렉트로닉스에서 개발 및 판매한 대화형 멀티미디어 CD 플레이어로, 오디오 CD 플레이어나 게임 콘솔보다 더 많은 기능을 제공하면서도 당시 CD-ROM 드라이브가 장착된 개인용 컴퓨터보다 저렴한 가격으로 제작되었습니다. 하드 드라이브, 플로피 드라이브, 키보드, 마우스, 모니터(표준 텔레비전이 사용됨)가 없고 운영 체제 소프트웨어가 적었기 때문에 비용을 절감할 수 있었습니다. 공용 인터넷이 보급되기 전에는 게임 외에도 대화형 백과사전, 박물관 투어 등 교육용 및 멀티미디어 참고용 타이틀이 제작되었습니다. 경쟁 제품으로는 탠디 VIS와 코모도어 CDTV가 있었습니다. 게임 콘솔로 여겨졌던 CD-i 포맷은 상업적으로 실패로 돌아갔습니다. 회사는 전체 프로젝트에서 10억 달러에 가까운 손실을 입었습니다. CD-i의 실패로 인해 필립스는 단종 후 비디오 게임 산업에서 철수했습니다. CD-i는 구독, 웹 브라우징, 다운로드, 이메일, 온라인 플레이 등 인터넷 기능을 가장 먼저 구현한 콘솔 중 하나이기도 합니다. 이는 필립스가 1996년에 출시한 추가 하드웨어 모뎀을 사용함으로써 가능했습니다.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>콘솔</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="nl_NL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>De Philips CD-i (Compact Disc Interactive) is een interactieve multimedia CD-speler, ontwikkeld en op de markt gebracht door Koninklijke Philips Electronics N.V. Deze categorie apparaten was bedoeld om meer functionaliteit te bieden dan een audio CD-speler of spelconsole, maar tegen een lagere prijs dan een personal computer met CD-ROM drive in die tijd. De kostenbesparing was te danken aan het ontbreken van een harde schijf, floppy drive, toetsenbord, muis, monitor (er werd een standaard televisie gebruikt) en minder besturingssysteemsoftware. Naast spelletjes werden er ook educatieve en multimediale naslagwerken geproduceerd, zoals interactieve encyclopedieën, museumtours, etc., nog voordat internet wijdverspreid was. Concurrenten waren onder andere de Tandy VIS en Commodore CDTV. Het CD-i formaat, gezien als een spelconsole, bleek een commerciële mislukking te zijn. Het bedrijf verloor bijna een miljard dollar op het hele project. De mislukking van de CD-i zorgde ervoor dat Philips de videogame-industrie verliet nadat het werd stopgezet. De CD-i is ook een van de eerste consoles met internetfuncties, zoals abonnementen, surfen op het web, downloaden, e-mail en online spelen. Dit werd mogelijk gemaakt door het gebruik van een extra hardwaremodem die Philips in 1996 uitbracht.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pl_PL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Philips CD-i (Compact Disc Interactive) to interaktywny multimedialny odtwarzacz CD opracowany i sprzedawany przez Royal Philips Electronics N.V. Ta kategoria urządzeń została stworzona, aby zapewnić większą funkcjonalność niż odtwarzacz audio CD lub konsola do gier, ale w niższej cenie niż komputer osobisty z napędem CD-ROM w tamtym czasie. Oszczędność kosztów wynikała z braku dysku twardego, stacji dyskietek, klawiatury, myszy, monitora (używano standardowego telewizora) i mniejszej ilości oprogramowania systemu operacyjnego. Oprócz gier, produkowano również edukacyjne i multimedialne tytuły referencyjne, takie jak interaktywne encyklopedie, wycieczki po muzeach itp. zanim publiczny dostęp do Internetu stał się powszechny. Konkurenci obejmowali Tandy VIS i Commodore CDTV. Postrzegany jako konsola do gier, format CD-i okazał się komercyjną porażką. Firma straciła prawie miliard dolarów na całym projekcie. Niepowodzenie CD-i spowodowało, że Philips opuścił branżę gier wideo po zaprzestaniu jej produkcji. CD-i jest również jedną z najwcześniejszych konsol, które wdrożyły funkcje internetowe, w tym subskrypcje, przeglądanie stron internetowych, pobieranie, e-mail i grę online. Było to ułatwione dzięki zastosowaniu dodatkowego modemu sprzętowego, który Philips wypuścił w 1996 roku.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Konsola</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_BR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O Philips CD-i (Compact Disc Interactive) é um CD player multimídia interativo desenvolvido e comercializado pela Royal Philips Electronics N.V. Essa categoria de dispositivo foi criada para oferecer mais funcionalidade do que um CD player de áudio ou um console de jogos, mas a um preço mais baixo do que um computador pessoal com unidade de CD-ROM na época. A economia de custos deveu-se à falta de um disco rígido, unidade de disquete, teclado, mouse, monitor (foi usada uma televisão padrão) e menos software de sistema operacional. Além de jogos, foram produzidos títulos de referência educacionais e multimídia, como enciclopédias interativas, visitas a museus etc., antes da disseminação do acesso público à Internet. Os concorrentes eram o Tandy VIS e o Commodore CDTV. Visto como um console de jogos, o formato CD-i provou ser um fracasso comercial. A empresa perdeu quase um bilhão de dólares em todo o projeto. O fracasso do CD-i fez com que a Philips deixasse o setor de videogames depois que ele foi descontinuado. O CD-i também é um dos primeiros consoles a implementar recursos de Internet, incluindo assinaturas, navegação na Web, download, e-mail e jogos on-line. Isso foi facilitado pelo uso de um modem de hardware adicional que a Philips lançou em 1996.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_PT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O Philips CD-I (Compact Disc Interactive) é um CD player interativo multimídia desenvolvido e comercializado pela Royal Philips Electronics N. V. Esta categoria de dispositivo foi criada para fornecer mais funcionalidade do que um CD player ou console de jogo, mas a um preço mais baixo do que um computador pessoal com unidade de CD-ROM na época. A economia de custos foi devida à falta de disco rígido, disquete, teclado, mouse, monitor (uma televisão padrão foi usada) e menos software de sistema operacional. Além dos jogos, foram produzidos títulos de referência educacional e multimídia, como enciclopédias interativas, passeios de museus etc. antes que o acesso público à Internet fosse generalizado. Os concorrentes incluíram o Tandy Vis e o Commodore CDTV. Visto como um console de jogo, o formato CD-I provou ser um fracasso comercial. A empresa perdeu quase um bilhão de dólares em todo o projeto. O fracasso do CD-I fez com que a Philips deixasse a indústria de videogames depois que ela foi interrompida. O CD-I também é um dos primeiros consoles para implementar recursos da Internet, incluindo assinaturas, navegação na Web, download, e-mail e reprodução on-line. Isso foi facilitado pelo uso de um modem de hardware adicional lançado em 1996.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ro_RO">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Philips CD-i (Compact Disc Interactive) este un CD player multimedia interactiv dezvoltat și comercializat de Royal Philips Electronics N.V. Această categorie de dispozitive a fost creată pentru a oferi mai multe funcționalități decât un CD player audio sau o consolă de jocuri, dar la un preț mai mic decât un computer personal cu unitate CD-ROM la acea vreme. Reducerea costurilor se datora lipsei unui hard disk, a unei unități de dischetă, a unei tastaturi, a unui mouse, a unui monitor (se folosea un televizor standard) și a mai puțin software pentru sistemul de operare. În plus față de jocuri, au fost produse titluri de referință educaționale și multimedia, cum ar fi enciclopedii interactive, tururi ale muzeelor etc. înainte ca accesul public la internet să fie larg răspândit. Printre concurenți se numărau Tandy VIS și Commodore CDTV. Văzut ca o consolă de jocuri, formatul CD-i s-a dovedit a fi un eșec comercial. Compania a pierdut aproape un miliard de dolari pe întregul proiect. Eșecul CD-i a determinat Philips să părăsească industria jocurilor video după ce a fost abandonat. CD-i este, de asemenea, una dintre primele console care a implementat funcții de internet, inclusiv abonamente, navigare pe internet, descărcare, e-mail și jocuri online. Acest lucru a fost facilitat de utilizarea unui modem hardware suplimentar pe care Philips l-a lansat în 1996.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Consolă</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ru_RU">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Philips CD-i (Compact Disc Interactive) - интерактивный мультимедийный CD-плеер, разработанный и продаваемый компанией Royal Philips Electronics N.V. Эта категория устройств была создана, чтобы обеспечить большую функциональность, чем проигрыватель аудио CD или игровая консоль, но по более низкой цене, чем персональный компьютер с приводом CD-ROM в то время. Экономия объяснялась отсутствием жесткого диска, флоппи-дисковода, клавиатуры, мыши, монитора (использовался обычный телевизор) и меньшим количеством программного обеспечения операционной системы. Помимо игр, до широкого распространения Интернета выпускались образовательные и мультимедийные справочные издания, такие как интерактивные энциклопедии, музейные экскурсии и т. д. Среди конкурентов были Tandy VIS и Commodore CDTV. Рассматриваемый как игровая консоль, формат CD-i оказался коммерческим провалом. Компания потеряла около миллиарда долларов на всем проекте. Неудача CD-i заставила Philips покинуть индустрию видеоигр после того, как она была снята с производства. CD-i - одна из самых ранних консолей, в которой были реализованы интернет-функции, включая подписку, просмотр веб-страниц, загрузку файлов, электронную почту и онлайн-игры. Этому способствовало использование дополнительного аппаратного модема, который Philips выпустила в 1996 году.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Консоль</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sr_RS">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>ПХИЛИПС ЦД-И (компактни дисков интерактиван) је интерактивни мултимедијални ЦД плејер који је развио и продао Роиал Пхилипс Елецтроницс Н.В. Ова категорија уређаја је створена да пружи више функционалности него аудио ЦД плејер или у нижој цени од личног рачунара у то време.Уштеда трошкова била је последица недостатка тврдог диска, дискете, тастатуре, миша, монитора (коришћена је стандардна телевизија) и мање софтвера за оперативни систем.Поред игара, произведени су образовни и мултимедијални референтни наслови, као што су интерактивне енциклопедије, музејске туре итд. Пре јавног приступа Интернету је распрострањен.Такмичари су укључивали Танди Вис и Цоммодоре ЦДТВ.Гледано као конзола игара, формат ЦД-ја показао се комерцијалним неуспехом.Компанија је изгубила скоро милијарду долара на целом пројекту.Неуспјех ЦД-ја сам изазвао Пхилипс да напусте индустрију видео игара након што је прекинута.ЦД-И је такође један од најранијих конзола за примену Интернет функција, укључујући претплате, веб прегледање, преузимање, е-пошту и интернетску игру.То је олакшано употребом додатног хардверског модема који је Пхилипс објавио 1996. године.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Конзола</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sv_SE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Philips CD-i (Compact Disc Interactive) är en interaktiv multimedia-CD-spelare som utvecklats och marknadsförs av Royal Philips Electronics N.V. Denna typ av enhet skapades för att erbjuda fler funktioner än en ljud-CD-spelare eller spelkonsol, men till ett lägre pris än en persondator med CD-ROM-enhet på den tiden. Kostnadsbesparingarna berodde på avsaknaden av hårddisk, diskettenhet, tangentbord, mus, bildskärm (en vanlig TV användes) och mindre programvara för operativsystemet. Förutom spel producerades även utbildnings- och multimediareferenser, t.ex. interaktiva uppslagsverk, museiturer m.m. innan Internet var allmänt tillgängligt för allmänheten. Konkurrenter var bland annat Tandy VIS och Commodore CDTV. CD-iformatet, som sågs som en spelkonsol, visade sig vara ett kommersiellt misslyckande. Företaget förlorade nästan en miljard dollar på hela projektet. Misslyckandet med CD-i ledde till att Philips lämnade videospelbranschen efter att den tagits ur drift. CD-i är också en av de första konsolerna med internetfunktioner, inklusive prenumerationer, webbsurfning, nedladdning, e-post och onlinespel. Detta underlättades genom att använda ett extra hårdvarumodem som Philips släppte 1996.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Konsol</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_CN">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>飞利浦 CD-i（交互式光盘）是一种交互式多媒体 CD 播放器，由皇家飞利浦电子公司开发和销售。这类设备的诞生是为了提供比音频 CD 播放器或游戏机更多的功能，但价格却低于当时带有 CD-ROM 驱动器的个人电脑。节省成本的原因是没有硬盘、软驱、键盘、鼠标、显示器（使用标准电视机）和较少的操作系统软件。除游戏外，在公共互联网接入普及之前，还制作了教育和多媒体参考资料，如交互式百科全书、博物馆导览等。竞争对手包括 Tandy VIS 和 Commodore CDTV。作为一种游戏机，CD-i 格式被证明是商业上的失败。公司在整个项目上损失了近 10 亿美元。CD-i 的失败导致飞利浦公司在其停产后退出了视频游戏行业。CD-i 也是最早实现互联网功能的游戏机之一，包括订阅、网页浏览、下载、电子邮件和在线游戏。飞利浦公司于 1996 年发布了一款附加硬件调制解调器，为实现这一功能提供了便利。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>控制台</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_TW">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Philips CD-i (Compact Disc Interactive) 是由 Royal Philips Electronics N.V. 所開發及行銷的互動式多媒體 CD 播放器，此類裝置的創造是為了提供比音訊 CD 播放器或遊戲控制台更多的功能，但價格卻比當時配備 CD-ROM 光碟機的個人電腦還要低。節省成本的原因在於沒有硬碟、軟碟、鍵盤、滑鼠、螢幕（使用標準電視），以及較少的作業系統軟體。除了遊戲之外，還製作了教育與多媒體參考書籍，例如互動式百科全書、博物館導覽等，當時公共網際網路尚未普及。競爭對手包括 Tandy VIS 和 Commodore CDTV。CD-i 格式被視為一種遊戲控制台，但事實證明它在商業上是失敗的。公司在整個項目上損失了近 10 億美元。CD-i 的失敗使 Philips 在停產後退出了視訊遊戲產業。CD-i 也是最早實現網路功能的遊戲機之一，包括訂閱、網頁瀏覽、下載、電子郵件和線上遊戲。這是因為使用了 Philips 於 1996 年推出的附加硬體數據機。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>控制台</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
</theme>
