<theme>
    <variables>
        <systemName>Famicom Disk System</systemName>
        <systemDescription>The Family Computer Disk System, sometimes shortened as the Famicom Disk System or simply the Disk System, and abbreviated as the FDS or FCD, is a peripheral for Nintendo's Family Computer home video game console, released in Japan on February 21, 1986. It uses proprietary floppy disks called "Disk Cards" for data storage. Through its entire production span, 1986–2003, 4.44 million units were sold. The device is connected to the Famicom deck by plugging a special cartridge known as the RAM Adapter into the system's cartridge port, and attaching that cartridge's cable to the disk drive. The RAM adapter contains 32 kilobytes (KB) of RAM for temporary program storage, 8 KB of RAM for tile and sprite data storage, and an ASIC known as the 2C33. The ASIC acts as a disk controller for the floppy drive, and also includes additional sound hardware featuring a single-cycle wavetable-lookup synthesizer. Finally, embedded in the 2C33 is an 8KB BIOS ROM. The Disk Cards used are double-sided, with a total capacity of 112 KB per disk. Many games span both sides of a disk, requiring the user to switch sides at some point during gameplay. A few games use two full disks, totaling four sides. The Disk System is capable of running on six C-cell batteries or the supplied AC adapter. Batteries usually last five months with daily game play. The battery option is due to the likelihood of a standard set of AC plugs already being occupied by a Famicom and a television.</systemDescription>
        <systemManufacturer>Nintendo</systemManufacturer>
        <systemReleaseYear>1986</systemReleaseYear>
        <systemReleaseDate>1986-11</systemReleaseDate>
        <systemReleaseDateFormated>February 21, 1986</systemReleaseDateFormated>
        <systemHardwareType>Peripheral</systemHardwareType>
        <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
        <systemCoverSizeType>square</systemCoverSizeType>
        <systemColor>c43d41</systemColor>
        <systemColorPalette1>A71636</systemColorPalette1>
        <systemColorPalette2>C7AF89</systemColorPalette2>
        <systemColorPalette3>3C3C3B</systemColorPalette3>
        <systemColorPalette4>F4B600</systemColorPalette4>
        <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
    </variables>
    <language name="ar_SA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>نظام أقراص كمبيوتر العائلة (Family Computer Disk System)، الذي يُختصر أحياناً باسم نظام الأقراص فاميكوم أو ببساطة نظام الأقراص، ويُختصر باسم FDS أو FCD، هو جهاز طرفي لوحدة تحكم ألعاب الفيديو المنزلية الخاصة بكمبيوتر العائلة من نينتندو، وقد تم إصداره في اليابان في 21 فبراير 1986. يستخدم أقراص مرنة خاصة تسمى "بطاقات القرص" لتخزين البيانات. تم بيع 4.44 مليون وحدة خلال فترة إنتاجه بالكامل، 1986-2003، تم بيع 4.44 مليون وحدة. يتم توصيل الجهاز بمنصة Famicom عن طريق توصيل خرطوشة خاصة تعرف باسم محول ذاكرة الوصول العشوائي (RAM Adapter) بمنفذ خرطوشة النظام، وتوصيل كابل تلك الخرطوشة بمحرك الأقراص. يحتوي محول RAM على 32 كيلو بايت (KB) من ذاكرة الوصول العشوائي (RAM) للتخزين المؤقت للبرامج، و8 كيلو بايت من ذاكرة الوصول العشوائي (RAM) لتخزين بيانات البلاط والعفاريت، و ASIC المعروف باسم 2C33. يعمل ASIC كوحدة تحكم في القرص لمحرك الأقراص المرنة، ويتضمن أيضًا أجهزة صوت إضافية تتميز بمركب بحث عن الموجات أحادية الدورة. وأخيراً، يوجد في 2C33 ذاكرة ROM BIOS سعة 8 كيلوبايت مدمجة في 2C33. بطاقات الأقراص المستخدمة مزدوجة الوجهين، بسعة إجمالية تبلغ 112 كيلوبايت لكل قرص. تمتد العديد من الألعاب على كلا جانبي القرص، مما يتطلب من المستخدم تبديل الجانبين في مرحلة ما أثناء اللعب. وتستخدم بعض الألعاب قرصين كاملين، بإجمالي أربعة جوانب. نظام الأقراص قادر على العمل على ست بطاريات C-c-cell أو محول التيار المتردد المرفق. تدوم البطاريات عادةً خمسة أشهر مع اللعب اليومي. ويرجع خيار البطارية إلى احتمال أن تكون مجموعة قياسية من مقابس التيار المتردد مشغولة بالفعل بواسطة جهاز فاميكوم وتلفزيون.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>محيطي</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="bs_BA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Porodični kompjuterski sistem, ponekad je skratio kao sistemski sustav diska ili jednostavno diskovni sistem, a skraćen je FDS ili FCD, je periferna konzola za porodičnu računaru Nintendo, objavljena u Japanu 21. februara 1986. godine. Koristi vlasničke diskete za pohranu podataka nazvanim "Disk karticama". Kroz cijeli proizvodni raspon, 1986-2003, prodato je 4,44 miliona jedinica. Uređaj je spojen na palubu za porodicu priključivanjem posebnog uloška poznatog kao RAM adapter u sistemski priključak za spremnik i pričvršćivanje kabela u kertridžju na disk. Ram adapter sadrži 32 kilobObytes (KB) RAM-a za privremeno skladištenje programa, 8 KB RAM-a za pohranu podataka o ploči i sprite, a asic poznat kao 2c33. ASIC djeluje kao diskovni kontroler za disketu, a uključuje i dodatni zvučni hardver sa jednim ciklusom sintetizatorom za lomljivu. Konačno, ugrađeni u 2c33 je 8kb BIOS ROM. Korišćene kartice diskova su dvostrane, ukupnog kapaciteta 112 KB po disku. Mnoge igre obuhvataju obje strane diska, zahtijevajući od korisnika da prebaci strane u nekom trenutku tokom igre. Nekoliko igara koriste dva puna diskova, ukupne četiri strane. Sustav diska može se pokrenuti na šest C-Cell baterija ili isporučenog ispravljača. Baterije obično traju pet meseci sa dnevnim igrama za igru. Opcija baterije je zbog vjerojatnosti standardnog skupa izmjeničnih utikača koji su već zauzeli porodica i televizija.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Periferni</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ca_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>El sistema de disc de l’ordinador familiar, de vegades escurçat com el sistema de disc Famicom o simplement el sistema de disc, i abreujat com a FDS o FCD, és un perifèric per a la consola de videojocs de la llar familiar de Nintendo, publicat al Japó el 21 de febrer de 1986. Utilitzadisquets propietaris anomenats "targetes de disc" per a l'emmagatzematge de dades. A través de tota la seva producció de producció, 1986–2003, es van vendre 4,44 milions d’unitats. El dispositiu està connectat a la coberta Famicom connectant un cartutx especial conegut com a adaptador de memòria RAM al port del cartutx del sistema i adjuntant el cable del cartutx a la unitat de disc. L’adaptador RAM conté 32 quilobytes (KB) de RAM per a l’emmagatzematge temporal del programa, 8 kb de RAM per a l’emmagatzematge de dades de rajoles i sprite i un ASIC conegut com el 2C33. L’ASIC actua com a controlador de disc per a la unitat de disquet, i també inclou un maquinari de so addicional amb un sintetitzador d’aspecte ondulat d’un cicle d’un sol cicle. Finalment, incrustat al 2C33 és una ROM de BIOS de 8KB. Les targetes de disc utilitzades són de doble cara, amb una capacitat total de 112 kb per disc. Molts jocs abasten els dos costats d’un disc, exigint a l’usuari canviar de costat en algun moment durant el joc. Alguns jocs utilitzen dos discos complets, per un total de quatre cares. El sistema de disc és capaç de funcionar amb sis bateries de cèl·lules C o l'adaptador de CA subministrat. Les bateries solen durar cinc mesos amb un joc diari. L’opció de la bateria es deu a la probabilitat d’un conjunt estàndard de taps de CA que ja ocupen un Famicom i una televisió.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Peripheral</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="de_DE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Das Family Computer Disk System, manchmal auch als Famicom Disk System oder einfach als Disk System abgekürzt und mit FDS oder FCD abgekürzt, ist ein Peripheriegerät für Nintendos Heimvideospielkonsole Family Computer, das am 21. Februar 1986 in Japan veröffentlicht wurde. Es verwendet proprietäre Disketten namens "Disk Cards" zur Datenspeicherung. Während der gesamten Produktionszeit (1986-2003) wurden 4,44 Millionen Einheiten verkauft. Das Gerät wird an das Famicom-Deck angeschlossen, indem eine spezielle Kassette, der so genannte RAM-Adapter, in den Kassettenanschluss des Systems gesteckt und das Kabel dieser Kassette mit dem Diskettenlaufwerk verbunden wird. Der RAM-Adapter enthält 32 Kilobytes (KB) RAM für die temporäre Programmspeicherung, 8 KB RAM für die Speicherung von Kachel- und Sprite-Daten und einen ASIC, der als 2C33 bekannt ist. Der ASIC fungiert als Diskettencontroller für das Diskettenlaufwerk und enthält außerdem zusätzliche Sound-Hardware mit einem Single-Cycle-Wavetable-Lookup-Synthesizer. Schließlich ist in den 2C33 ein 8KB großes BIOS-ROM integriert. Die verwendeten Diskettenkarten sind doppelseitig, mit einer Gesamtkapazität von 112 KB pro Diskette. Viele Spiele nutzen beide Seiten einer Diskette, so dass der Benutzer irgendwann während des Spiels die Seite wechseln muss. Einige wenige Spiele verwenden zwei volle Disketten, also insgesamt vier Seiten. Das Disk System kann mit sechs C-Zellen-Batterien oder dem mitgelieferten Netzgerät betrieben werden. Die Batterien halten in der Regel fünf Monate bei täglichem Spielbetrieb. Die Batterieoption ist darauf zurückzuführen, dass die Wahrscheinlichkeit besteht, dass ein Standard-Netzstecker bereits durch ein Famicom und einen Fernseher belegt ist.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Peripherie</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="es_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>El Family Computer Disk System, a veces abreviado como Famicom Disk System o simplemente Disk System, y abreviado como FDS o FCD, es un periférico para la videoconsola doméstica Family Computer de Nintendo, que salió a la venta en Japón el 21 de febrero de 1986. Utiliza disquetes patentados llamados "Disk Cards" para el almacenamiento de datos. Durante todo su periodo de producción, 1986-2003, se vendieron 4,44 millones de unidades. El dispositivo se conecta a la consola Famicom enchufando un cartucho especial conocido como adaptador de RAM al puerto de cartuchos del sistema y conectando el cable de dicho cartucho a la unidad de disco. El adaptador de RAM contiene 32 kilobytes (KB) de RAM para el almacenamiento temporal de programas, 8 KB de RAM para el almacenamiento de datos de tiles y sprites, y un ASIC conocido como 2C33. El ASIC actúa como controlador de disco para la disquetera e incluye hardware de sonido adicional con un sintetizador de un solo ciclo con tabla de ondas. Por último, el 2C33 incorpora una BIOS ROM de 8 KB. Las tarjetas de disco utilizadas son de doble cara, con una capacidad total de 112 KB por disco. Muchos juegos abarcan ambos lados de un disco, requiriendo que el usuario cambie de lado en algún momento durante el juego. Algunos juegos utilizan dos discos completos, con un total de cuatro caras. El Disk System puede funcionar con seis pilas C o con el adaptador de CA suministrado. Las pilas suelen durar cinco meses con juego diario. La opción de las pilas se debe a la probabilidad de que un juego estándar de enchufes de CA ya esté ocupado por una Famicom y un televisor.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Periférico</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="fr_FR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Le Family Computer Disk System, parfois abrégé en Famicom Disk System ou simplement Disk System, et abrégé en FDS ou FCD, est un périphérique pour la console de jeux vidéo Family Computer de Nintendo, sorti au Japon le 21 février 1986. Il utilise des disquettes propriétaires appelées "Disk Cards" pour le stockage des données. Pendant toute la durée de sa production, de 1986 à 2003, 4,44 millions d'unités ont été vendues. L'appareil est connecté à la platine Famicom en branchant une cartouche spéciale appelée adaptateur RAM dans le port cartouche du système, et en attachant le câble de cette cartouche au lecteur de disquettes. L'adaptateur RAM contient 32 kilo-octets (Ko) de RAM pour le stockage temporaire des programmes, 8 Ko de RAM pour le stockage des données des tuiles et des sprites, et un ASIC appelé 2C33. L'ASIC fait office de contrôleur de disque pour le lecteur de disquette et comprend également du matériel audio supplémentaire, notamment un synthétiseur à table d'ondes et à lookup à cycle unique. Enfin, le 2C33 intègre une ROM BIOS de 8 Ko. Les cartes-disques utilisées sont à double face, avec une capacité totale de 112 Ko par disque. De nombreux jeux utilisent les deux faces d'un disque, ce qui oblige l'utilisateur à changer de côté à un moment ou à un autre de la partie. Quelques jeux utilisent deux disques complets, soit quatre faces au total. Le Disk System peut fonctionner avec six piles C ou avec l'adaptateur secteur fourni. Les piles durent généralement cinq mois en cas de jeu quotidien. L'option des piles est due au fait qu'il est probable qu'un jeu de prises secteur standard soit déjà occupé par une Famicom et un téléviseur.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Périphérique</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="hr_HR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Sustav obiteljskog računalnog diska, koji se ponekad skraćuje kao sustav diska Famicom ili jednostavno sustav diska, i skraćen kao FDS ili FCD, periferni je za Nintendoovu obiteljsku konzolu za kućne video igre, objavljen u Japanu 21. veljače 1986. godine. Koristi vlasničke diskete nazvane "Disk Cards" za podatke. Kroz cijeli svoj proizvodni raspon, 1986–2003. Prodano je 4,44 milijuna jedinica. Uređaj je spojen na palubu Famicom priključivši poseban uložak poznat kao Adapter RAM -a u priključak za uložak sustava i pričvršćivanje kabela tog uloška na pogon diska. Adapter RAM -a sadrži 32 kilobajta (KB) RAM -a za privremeni program za pohranu, 8 kb RAM -a za pohranu podataka i sprite i ASIC poznat kao 2C33. ASIC djeluje kao kontroler diska za disketni pogon, a uključuje i dodatni zvučni hardver koji sadrži jednociklistički sintetizator valovitog izgleda. Konačno, ugrađen u 2C33 je 8kb BIOS ROM. Korištene diskovne kartice su dvostrane, s ukupnim kapacitetom od 112 kb po disku. Mnoge igre obuhvaćaju obje strane diska, što zahtijeva od korisnika da prebaci strane u nekom trenutku tijekom igranja. Nekoliko igara koristi dva puna diska, ukupno četiri strane. Sustav diska može se pokrenuti na šest C-staničnih baterija ili isporučenog AC adaptera. Baterije obično traju pet mjeseci uz dnevnu igru. Opcija baterija nastaje zbog vjerojatnosti da će standardni set izmjeničnih čepova već zauzeti Famicom i televizija.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Periferni</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="it_IT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Il Family Computer Disk System, talvolta abbreviato in Famicom Disk System o semplicemente Disk System e abbreviato in FDS o FCD, è una periferica per la console per videogiochi domestica Family Computer di Nintendo, uscita in Giappone il 21 febbraio 1986. Utilizza dischi floppy proprietari chiamati "Disk Card" per la memorizzazione dei dati. Nel corso della sua intera produzione, dal 1986 al 2003, sono state vendute 4,44 milioni di unità. Il dispositivo viene collegato al deck del Famicom inserendo una cartuccia speciale, nota come RAM Adapter, nella porta cartucce del sistema e collegando il cavo della cartuccia all'unità disco. L'adattatore RAM contiene 32 kilobyte (KB) di RAM per la memorizzazione temporanea dei programmi, 8 KB di RAM per la memorizzazione dei dati di tile e sprite e un ASIC noto come 2C33. L'ASIC funge da controller del disco per l'unità floppy e include anche hardware audio aggiuntivo con un sintetizzatore wavetable-lookup a ciclo singolo. Infine, nel 2C33 è incorporata una ROM BIOS da 8KB. Le schede disco utilizzate sono a doppia faccia, con una capacità totale di 112 KB per disco. Molti giochi utilizzano entrambi i lati del disco, richiedendo all'utente di cambiare lato a un certo punto del gioco. Alcuni giochi utilizzano due dischi interi, per un totale di quattro lati. Il Disk System può funzionare con sei batterie C o con l'adattatore CA in dotazione. Le batterie durano in genere cinque mesi con un gioco quotidiano. L'opzione delle batterie è dovuta alla probabilità che un set standard di prese CA sia già occupato da un Famicom e da un televisore.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Periferica</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ja_JP">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>ファミリーコンピュータ ディスクシステム（Family Computer Disk System）は、1986年2月21日に日本で発売された任天堂の家庭用ゲーム機「ファミリーコンピュータ」の周辺機器である。データ保存用に「ディスクカード」と呼ばれる独自のフロッピーディスクを使用している。1986年から2003年までの全生産期間を通じて、444万台が販売された。ファミコンのカートリッジポートにRAMアダプタと呼ばれる特殊なカートリッジを差し込み、そのカートリッジのケーブルをディスクドライブに取り付けることで、ファミコンのデッキに接続される。RAMアダプターには、プログラムの一時保存用に32キロバイト（KB）のRAM、タイルとスプライトのデータ保存用に8KBのRAM、そして2C33として知られるASICが搭載されている。このASICは、フロッピードライブ用のディスクコントローラとして機能するほか、シングルサイクルのウェーブテーブル・ルックアップ・シンセサイザを備えたサウンドハードウェアも搭載しています。最後に、2C33には8KBのBIOS ROMが内蔵されている。使用されるディスクカードは両面タイプで、ディスク1枚あたりの総容量は112KBである。多くのゲームは、ディスクの両面にまたがっており、ゲームプレイ中に両面を切り替える必要がある。2枚のディスクをフルに使い、合計4面を使用するゲームもある。ディスク・システムは、6本の単二電池または付属のACアダプターで動作する。電池は通常、毎日のゲームプレイで5ヶ月持つ。乾電池を選択するのは、標準的なACプラグのセットがすでにファミコンとテレビで占められている可能性が高いためである。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>ペリフェラル</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ko_KR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>패미컴 디스크 시스템 또는 간단히 디스크 시스템으로 줄여서 FDS 또는 FCD로 약칭하기도 하는 패밀리 컴퓨터 디스크 시스템은 1986년 2월 21일 일본에서 출시된 닌텐도의 패밀리 컴퓨터 가정용 비디오 게임 콘솔용 주변기기입니다. 데이터 저장을 위해 "디스크 카드"라는 독점 플로피 디스크를 사용합니다. 1986년부터 2003년까지 전체 생산 기간 동안 444만 대가 판매되었습니다. 이 장치는 RAM 어댑터라고 하는 특수 카트리지를 시스템의 카트리지 포트에 꽂고 해당 카트리지의 케이블을 디스크 드라이브에 연결하여 패미컴 데크에 연결합니다. RAM 어댑터에는 임시 프로그램 저장을 위한 32KB의 RAM, 타일 및 스프라이트 데이터 저장을 위한 8KB의 RAM, 2C33으로 알려진 ASIC이 포함되어 있습니다. 이 ASIC은 플로피 드라이브의 디스크 컨트롤러 역할을 하며, 단일 사이클 웨이브테이블 룩업 신디사이저를 갖춘 추가 사운드 하드웨어도 포함되어 있습니다. 마지막으로 2C33에는 8KB 바이오스 롬이 내장되어 있습니다. 사용된 디스크 카드는 양면으로, 디스크당 총 용량은 112KB입니다. 많은 게임이 디스크의 양면에 걸쳐 있기 때문에 게임 플레이 중 어느 시점에서 사용자가 양면을 전환해야 합니다. 일부 게임은 2개의 전체 디스크를 사용하여 총 4개의 면을 사용합니다. 디스크 시스템은 6개의 C셀 배터리 또는 제공된 AC 어댑터로 작동할 수 있습니다. 배터리는 보통 매일 게임을 플레이할 경우 5개월 동안 지속됩니다. 배터리 옵션은 표준 AC 플러그 세트가 이미 패미컴과 TV에 의해 점유되고 있을 가능성이 있기 때문입니다.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>주변기기</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="nl_NL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Het Family Computer Disk System, soms afgekort als het Famicom Disk System of gewoon het Disk System, en afgekort als de FDS of FCD, is een randapparaat voor Nintendo's Family Computer home video game console, uitgebracht in Japan op 21 februari 1986. Het maakt gebruik van eigen floppydisks genaamd "Disk Cards" voor de opslag van gegevens. Tijdens de gehele productieperiode, 1986-2003, werden er 4,44 miljoen exemplaren van verkocht. Het apparaat wordt op de Famicom aangesloten door een speciale cartridge, de RAM-adapter, in de cartridgepoort van het systeem te steken en de kabel van de cartridge aan het diskettestation te bevestigen. De RAM-adapter bevat 32 kilobytes (KB) RAM voor tijdelijke programmaopslag, 8 KB RAM voor de opslag van tile- en spritegegevens en een ASIC die bekend staat als de 2C33. De ASIC fungeert als schijfcontroller voor het diskettestation en bevat ook extra geluidshardware met een single-cycle wavetable-lookup synthesizer. Tenslotte is in de 2C33 een 8KB BIOS ROM ingebouwd. De gebruikte schijfkaarten zijn dubbelzijdig, met een totale capaciteit van 112 KB per schijf. Veel spellen beslaan beide kanten van een schijf, waardoor de gebruiker op een bepaald moment tijdens het spelen van kant moet wisselen. Een paar spellen gebruiken twee volledige schijven, in totaal vier kanten. Het Disksysteem werkt op zes C-cel batterijen of de meegeleverde wisselstroomadapter. De batterijen gaan meestal vijf maanden mee bij dagelijks spelen. De batterijoptie is te wijten aan de kans dat een standaard set wisselstroomstekkers al bezet is door een Famicom en een televisie.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Perifeer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pl_PL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Family Computer Disk System, czasami skracany jako Famicom Disk System lub po prostu Disk System, a w skrócie FDS lub FCD, to urządzenie peryferyjne dla domowej konsoli do gier wideo Nintendo Family Computer, wydane w Japonii 21 lutego 1986 roku. Do przechowywania danych wykorzystuje opatentowane dyskietki zwane "Disk Cards". W całym okresie produkcji, 1986-2003, sprzedano 4,44 miliona sztuk. Urządzenie jest podłączane do konsoli Famicom poprzez podłączenie specjalnego kartridża znanego jako adapter RAM do portu kartridża systemu i podłączenie kabla tego kartridża do stacji dysków. Adapter RAM zawiera 32 kilobajty (KB) pamięci RAM do tymczasowego przechowywania programów, 8 KB pamięci RAM do przechowywania danych kafelków i sprite'ów oraz układ ASIC znany jako 2C33. ASIC działa jako kontroler dysku dla stacji dyskietek, a także zawiera dodatkowy sprzęt dźwiękowy z syntezatorem wavetable-lookup z pojedynczym cyklem. Wreszcie, wbudowany w 2C33 jest 8KB BIOS ROM. Używane karty dyskowe są dwustronne, o łącznej pojemności 112 KB na dysk. Wiele gier wykorzystuje obie strony dysku, wymagając od użytkownika przełączania stron w pewnym momencie rozgrywki. Kilka gier wykorzystuje dwa pełne dyski, w sumie cztery strony. Disk System może działać na sześciu bateriach typu C lub na dostarczonym zasilaczu sieciowym. Baterie zwykle wystarczają na pięć miesięcy codziennej gry. Opcja baterii wynika z prawdopodobieństwa, że standardowy zestaw wtyczek AC jest już zajęty przez Famicom i telewizor.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Peryferyjne</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_BR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O Family Computer Disk System, às vezes abreviado como Famicom Disk System ou simplesmente Disk System, e abreviado como FDS ou FCD, é um periférico para o console de videogame doméstico Family Computer da Nintendo, lançado no Japão em 21 de fevereiro de 1986. Ele usa disquetes proprietários chamados "Disk Cards" para armazenamento de dados. Durante toda a sua produção, de 1986 a 2003, foram vendidas 4,44 milhões de unidades. O dispositivo é conectado ao deck do Famicom conectando um cartucho especial conhecido como adaptador de RAM na porta de cartucho do sistema e conectando o cabo desse cartucho à unidade de disco. O adaptador de RAM contém 32 kilobytes (KB) de RAM para armazenamento temporário de programas, 8 KB de RAM para armazenamento de dados de tile e sprite e um ASIC conhecido como 2C33. O ASIC atua como um controlador de disco para a unidade de disquete e também inclui hardware de som adicional com um sintetizador de ciclo único com aparência de tabela de ondas. Por fim, o 2C33 incorpora uma ROM de BIOS de 8 KB. Os cartões de disco usados são de dupla face, com uma capacidade total de 112 KB por disco. Muitos jogos abrangem os dois lados de um disco, exigindo que o usuário troque de lado em algum momento do jogo. Alguns jogos usam dois discos completos, totalizando quatro lados. O Disk System é capaz de funcionar com seis baterias de célula C ou com o adaptador CA fornecido. As baterias geralmente duram cinco meses com jogos diários. A opção de bateria se deve à probabilidade de um conjunto padrão de plugues CA já estar ocupado por um Famicom e uma televisão.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Periférico</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_PT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O sistema de disco de computador da família, às vezes reduzido como o sistema de disco Famicom ou simplesmente o sistema de disco, e abreviado como FDS ou FCD, é um periférico para o console de videogame em casa de computador de família da Nintendo, lançado no Japão em 21 de fevereiro de 1986. Durante todo o seu período de produção, 1986–2003, 4,44 milhões de unidades foram vendidas. O dispositivo está conectado ao baralho Famicom, conectando um cartucho especial conhecido como adaptador RAM na porta do cartucho do sistema e conectando o cabo desse cartucho à unidade de disco. O adaptador RAM contém 32 kilobytes (KB) de RAM para armazenamento temporário do programa, 8 kb de RAM para armazenamento de dados de ladrilhos e sprite e um ASIC conhecido como 2C33. O ASIC atua como um controlador de disco para a unidade de disquete e também inclui hardware de som adicional com um sintetizador de visita a ondas de ciclo único. Finalmente, incorporado no 2C33 é uma ROM de 8kb. As placas de disco usadas são duplos, com uma capacidade total de 112 kb por disco. Muitos jogos abrangem os dois lados de um disco, exigindo que o usuário mude de lado em algum momento durante a jogabilidade. Alguns jogos usam dois discos completos, totalizando quatro lados. O sistema de disco é capaz de executar em seis baterias de células C ou o adaptador CA fornecido. As baterias geralmente duram cinco meses com jogo diário. A opção da bateria se deve à probabilidade de um conjunto padrão de plugues CA já sendo ocupados por um Famicom e uma televisão.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Peripheral</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ro_RO">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Family Computer Disk System, uneori prescurtat ca Famicom Disk System sau pur și simplu Disk System, și prescurtat ca FDS sau FCD, este un periferic pentru consola de jocuri video de acasă Family Computer de la Nintendo, lansat în Japonia la 21 februarie 1986. Folosește dischete brevetate numite "Disk Cards" pentru stocarea datelor. De-a lungul întregii sale perioade de producție, 1986-2003, au fost vândute 4,44 milioane de unități. Dispozitivul este conectat la puntea Famicom prin conectarea unui cartuș special cunoscut sub numele de adaptor RAM în portul de cartușe al sistemului și prin atașarea cablului cartușului la unitatea de disc. Adaptorul RAM conține 32 kilobytes (KB) de RAM pentru stocarea temporară a programului, 8 KB de RAM pentru stocarea datelor tile și sprite și un ASIC cunoscut sub numele de 2C33. ASIC-ul acționează ca un controler de disc pentru unitatea de dischetă și include, de asemenea, hardware de sunet suplimentar cu un sintetizator cu un singur ciclu wavetable-lookup. În cele din urmă, în 2C33 este încorporat un BIOS ROM de 8KB. Cardurile de disc utilizate sunt cu două fețe, cu o capacitate totală de 112 KB pe disc. Multe jocuri utilizează ambele fețe ale unui disc, cerând utilizatorului să schimbe partea la un moment dat în timpul jocului. Câteva jocuri utilizează două discuri complete, totalizând patru fețe. Disk System poate funcționa cu șase baterii C-cell sau cu adaptorul AC furnizat. Bateriile durează, de obicei, cinci luni cu jocuri zilnice. Opțiunea bateriei se datorează probabilității ca un set standard de prize AC să fie deja ocupat de un Famicom și un televizor.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Periferic</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ru_RU">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Family Computer Disk System, иногда сокращенно называемая Famicom Disk System или просто Disk System, а также сокращенно FDS или FCD, - периферийное устройство для домашней видеоигровой консоли Family Computer от Nintendo, выпущенное в Японии 21 февраля 1986 года. Для хранения данных в нем используются фирменные дискеты под названием "Disk Cards". За все время производства, с 1986 по 2003 год, было продано 4,44 миллиона устройств. Устройство подключается к деке Famicom путем установки специального картриджа, известного как RAM Adapter, в порт картриджа системы и подключения кабеля картриджа к дисководу. Адаптер RAM содержит 32 килобайта (КБ) оперативной памяти для временного хранения программ, 8 КБ оперативной памяти для хранения данных тайлов и спрайтов, а также ASIC, известный как 2C33. ASIC выполняет функции дискового контроллера для флоппи-дисковода, а также содержит дополнительное звуковое оборудование с одноцикличным синтезатором. Наконец, в 2C33 встроено 8 КБ ПЗУ BIOS. Дисковые карты используются двусторонние, общая емкость одного диска составляет 112 КБ. Многие игры занимают обе стороны диска, требуя от пользователя переключать стороны в определенный момент игры. Некоторые игры используют два полных диска, в общей сложности четыре стороны. Дисковая система может работать от шести батареек типа C или от прилагаемого адаптера переменного тока. Батареи обычно хватает на пять месяцев при ежедневной игре. Вариант с батареями объясняется тем, что стандартный набор сетевых вилок может быть занят Famicom и телевизором.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Периферийное устройство</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sr_RS">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Породични систем рачунара, понекад се скраћује као Фамицом дисковни систем или једноставно систем диска и скраћено је ФДС или ФЦД, је периферна за Нинтендо-овог породичног рачунарског домаћег видео игара, објављена у Јапану 21. фебруара 1986. године. Користи се у Јапану, 21. фебруара 1986. године. Користи се власничке дискете на складиштење података.Кроз цео свој распон производње, продато је 1986-2003, 4,44 милиона јединица.Уређај је повезан на палубу Фамицом прикључивањем посебне кертриџа познат као РАМ адаптер у порт системске улоге и причвршћивање кабла кертриџа на диск погон.РАМ адаптер садржи 32 килобајта (КБ) РАМ-а за привремени програм програма, 8 КБ РАМ-а за складиштење података плочица и Сприте и АСИЦ познат као 2Ц33.АСИЦ делује као контролер диска за дискету, а такође укључује додатни звучни хардвер са једним циклусом синтетизатора за претрагу.Коначно, уграђени у 2Ц33 је 8КБ БИОС РОМ.Коришћене дисковне картице су двостране, са укупним капацитетом од 112 Кб по диску.Многе игре спаниле су обе стране диска, захтевајући да корисник пребацује стране у неком тренутку током играња.Неколико игара користи два пуна дискова, укупно четири стране.Диск систем је у стању да ради на шест батерија Ц-ћелије или испорученог исправљача.Батерије обично трају пет месеци са свакодневном играњем игре.Опција батерије је последица вероватноће стандардног скупа АЦ утикача који су већ заузели породицом и телевизијом.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Периферни</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sv_SE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Family Computer Disk System, ibland förkortat Famicom Disk System eller bara Disk System, och förkortat FDS eller FCD, är en kringutrustning till Nintendos Family Computer-videospelskonsol som släpptes i Japan den 21 februari 1986. Den använder egenutvecklade disketter som kallas "Disk Cards" för datalagring. Under hela produktionsperioden, 1986-2003, såldes 4,44 miljoner enheter. Enheten ansluts till Famicom genom att en speciell kassett, RAM-adaptern, sätts in i systemets kassettport och kassettens kabel ansluts till diskettenheten. RAM-adaptern innehåller 32 kilobyte (KB) RAM-minne för tillfällig programlagring, 8 KB RAM-minne för lagring av data från tiles och sprites samt en ASIC som kallas 2C33. ASIC:en fungerar som diskettkontroll för diskettenheten och innehåller också extra ljudhårdvara med en encykels wavetable-lookup-synthesizer. Slutligen finns ett 8KB BIOS ROM inbäddat i 2C33. De diskettkort som används är dubbelsidiga och har en total kapacitet på 112 KB per diskett. Många spel använder båda sidorna av en diskett, vilket innebär att användaren måste byta sida någon gång under spelets gång. Några få spel använder två hela diskar, totalt fyra sidor. Disk System kan drivas med sex C-cellsbatterier eller den medföljande nätadaptern. Batterierna håller vanligtvis i fem månader vid dagligt spelande. Batterialternativet beror på att det är troligt att en vanlig uppsättning nätkontakter redan är upptagna av en Famicom och en TV.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Tillbehör</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_CN">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>家庭电脑磁盘系统（Family Computer Disk System），有时简称为 "Famicom Disk System "或 "Disk System"，缩写为 "FDS "或 "FCD"，是任天堂家庭电脑家用视频游戏机的外围设备，于 1986 年 2 月 21 日在日本发布。它使用名为 "磁盘卡 "的专有软盘来存储数据。在 1986-2003 年的整个生产过程中，共售出 444 万台。将一个名为 "RAM 适配器 "的特殊盒式磁带插入系统的盒式磁带端口，并将该盒式磁带的电缆连接到磁盘驱动器，即可将该设备连接到 Famicom 主机。RAM 适配器包含用于临时程序存储的 32 KB RAM、用于磁贴和精灵数据存储的 8 KB RAM，以及一个名为 2C33 的 ASIC。ASIC 充当软驱的磁盘控制器，还包括额外的声音硬件，具有单周期波表查找合成器。最后，2C33 内嵌有一个 8KB BIOS ROM。使用的磁盘卡是双面的，每个磁盘的总容量为 112KB。许多游戏都是双面磁盘，要求用户在游戏过程中随时切换磁盘。少数游戏使用两个完整的磁盘，共计四面。磁盘系统可使用六节 C 型电池或随附的交流适配器运行。在每天玩游戏的情况下，电池通常可以使用五个月。选择使用电池是因为 Famicom 和电视机可能已经占用了一套标准的交流电插头。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>外围设备</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_TW">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>家庭電腦磁碟系統（Family Computer Disk System），通常簡稱為 Famicom Disk System 或 Disk System，是任天堂家庭電腦家用視訊遊戲機的周邊設備，於 1986 年 2 月 21 日僅在日本發售。它使用稱為「Disk Cards」的專屬軟碟來儲存較便宜的資料，並新增了支援 Disk System 遊戲的高傳真聲道。

基本上，磁碟系統只是加強了基本 Famicom 系統的某些固有功能，提供更好的音效和更便宜的遊戲，但也有初始價格高、速度慢和可靠性低的缺點。不過，這種可負擔、可寫的大容量儲存設備對市場的推動，暫時成為創造新型視訊遊戲的有利技術。這包括最暢銷的 The Legend of Zelda (1986) 和 Metroid (1986)，遼闊、開放世界、省進度的冒險遊戲，具有成本效益且發行迅速的遊戲，例如最暢銷的「超級馬里奧兄弟 2」，以及透過店內 Disk Fax kiosk 進行的全國性排行榜和競賽，這些都被視為今日線上成就和發行系統的先驅。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>周邊設備</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
</theme>
