<theme>
    <variables>
        <systemName>FM-7</systemName>
        <systemDescription>The FM-7 ("Fujitsu Micro 7") is a home computer created by Fujitsu. It was first released in 1982 and was sold in Japan and Spain. It is a stripped-down version of Fujitsu's earlier FM-8 computer, and during development it was referred to as the "FM-8 Jr.".</systemDescription>
        <systemManufacturer>Fujitsu</systemManufacturer>
        <systemReleaseYear>1982</systemReleaseYear>
        <systemReleaseDate>1982-11</systemReleaseDate>
        <systemReleaseDateFormated>November 1982</systemReleaseDateFormated>
        <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        <systemCoverSize>3-4</systemCoverSize>
        <systemCoverSizeType>portrait</systemCoverSizeType>
        <systemColor>E8B229</systemColor>
        <systemColorPalette1>999999</systemColorPalette1>
        <systemColorPalette2>777777</systemColorPalette2>
        <systemColorPalette3>555555</systemColorPalette3>
        <systemColorPalette4>333333</systemColorPalette4>
        <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
    </variables>
    <language name="ar_SA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>FM-7 ("فوجيتسو مايكرو 7") هو كمبيوتر منزلي من إنتاج فوجيتسو. تم إصداره لأول مرة في عام 1982 وتم بيعه في اليابان وإسبانيا. وهو نسخة مجردة من كمبيوتر فوجيتسو السابق FM-8، وكان يشار إليه أثناء تطويره باسم "FM-8 جونيور".</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>الحاسب الآلي</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="bs_BA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>FM-7 ("Fujitsu Micro 7") je kućni računar koji je stvorio Fujitsu. Prvo je pušten 1982. godine i prodat je u Japanu i Španiji. To je oduzeta verzija Fujitsua ranijeg FM-8 računara, a tokom razvoja naziva se "FM-8 Jr.".</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Računar</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ca_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>El FM-7 ("Fujitsu Micro 7") és un ordinador domèstic creat per Fujitsu. Va ser llançat per primera vegada el 1982 i es va vendre al Japó i Espanya.És una versió despullada de l'anterior ordinador FM-8 de Fujitsu, i durant el desenvolupament es coneixia com a "FM-8 Jr.".</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="de_DE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Der FM-7 ("Fujitsu Micro 7") ist ein von Fujitsu entwickelter Heimcomputer. Er wurde erstmals 1982 veröffentlicht und in Japan und Spanien verkauft. Er ist eine abgespeckte Version des früheren FM-8-Computers von Fujitsu und wurde während der Entwicklung als "FM-8 Jr." bezeichnet.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="es_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>El FM-7 ("Fujitsu Micro 7") es un ordenador doméstico creado por Fujitsu. Salió al mercado en 1982 y se vendió en Japón y España. Se trata de una versión reducida del anterior ordenador FM-8 de Fujitsu, y durante su desarrollo se le denominó "FM-8 Jr".</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Ordenador</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="fr_FR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Le FM-7 ("Fujitsu Micro 7") est un ordinateur domestique créé par Fujitsu. Il a été commercialisé pour la première fois en 1982 au Japon et en Espagne. Il s'agit d'une version simplifiée de l'ordinateur FM-8 de Fujitsu, et pendant son développement, il a été appelé "FM-8 Jr".</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Ordinateur</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="hr_HR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>FM-7 ("Fujitsu Micro 7") je kućno računalo koje je stvorio Fujitsu. Prvi put je objavljen 1982. godine, a prodat je u Japanu i Španjolskoj. To je srušena verzija ranijeg FM-8 računala Fujitsu, a tijekom razvoja naziva se "FM-8 Jr.".</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Računalo</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="it_IT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>L'FM-7 ("Fujitsu Micro 7") è un home computer creato da Fujitsu. È stato rilasciato per la prima volta nel 1982 ed è stato venduto in Giappone e in Spagna. Si tratta di una versione ridotta del precedente computer FM-8 di Fujitsu, e durante lo sviluppo veniva chiamato "FM-8 Jr.".</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ja_JP">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>FM-7（「富士通マイクロ7」）は富士通が作った家庭用コンピュータである。1982年に発売され、日本とスペインで販売された。富士通の初期のコンピュータFM-8の縮小版であり、開発中は「FM-8 Jr.」と呼ばれていた。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>コンピューター</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ko_KR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>FM-7("후지쯔 마이크로 7")은 후지쯔에서 만든 가정용 컴퓨터입니다. 1982년에 처음 출시되어 일본과 스페인에서 판매되었습니다. 이 제품은 후지쯔의 초기 FM-8 컴퓨터의 축소 버전으로, 개발 당시에는 "FM-8 주니어"라고 불렸습니다.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>컴퓨터</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="nl_NL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>De FM-7 ("Fujitsu Micro 7") is een thuiscomputer gemaakt door Fujitsu. Hij werd voor het eerst uitgebracht in 1982 en werd verkocht in Japan en Spanje. Het is een uitgeklede versie van Fujitsu's eerdere FM-8 computer, die tijdens de ontwikkeling de "FM-8 Jr." werd genoemd.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pl_PL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>FM-7 ("Fujitsu Micro 7") to komputer domowy stworzony przez firmę Fujitsu. Po raz pierwszy został wydany w 1982 roku i był sprzedawany w Japonii i Hiszpanii. Jest to okrojona wersja wcześniejszego komputera Fujitsu FM-8, a podczas rozwoju był określany jako "FM-8 Jr.".</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Komputer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_BR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O FM-7 ("Fujitsu Micro 7") é um computador doméstico criado pela Fujitsu. Foi lançado pela primeira vez em 1982 e foi vendido no Japão e na Espanha. É uma versão reduzida do computador FM-8 anterior da Fujitsu e, durante o desenvolvimento, foi chamado de "FM-8 Jr.".</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computador</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_PT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O FM-7 ("Fujitsu Micro 7") é um computador doméstico criado por Fujitsu. Foi lançado pela primeira vez em 1982 e foi vendido no Japão e na Espanha.É uma versão despojada do computador FM-8 anterior da Fujitsu e, durante o desenvolvimento, foi chamado de "FM-8 Jr.".</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computador</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ro_RO">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>FM-7 ("Fujitsu Micro 7") este un computer de casă creat de Fujitsu. A fost lansat pentru prima dată în 1982 și a fost vândut în Japonia și Spania. Este o versiune simplificată a computerului Fujitsu FM-8, iar în timpul dezvoltării a fost denumit "FM-8 Jr.".</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ru_RU">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>FM-7 ("Fujitsu Micro 7") - домашний компьютер, созданный компанией Fujitsu. Впервые он был выпущен в 1982 году и продавался в Японии и Испании. Он является урезанной версией более раннего компьютера Fujitsu FM-8, и во время разработки его называли "FM-8 Jr.".</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Компьютер</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sr_RS">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>ФМ-7 ("Фујитсу Мицро 7") је кућни рачунар који је створио Фујитсу.Прво је објављен 1982. године и продат је у Јапану и Шпанији.То је лишена верзија ФУЈИТСУ-а ранијег рачунара ФМ-8, а током развоја назива се "ФМ-8 Јр".</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Рачунар</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sv_SE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>FM-7 ("Fujitsu Micro 7") är en hemdator som skapades av Fujitsu. Den släpptes första gången 1982 och såldes i Japan och Spanien. Den är en nedbantad version av Fujitsus tidigare FM-8-dator och under utvecklingen kallades den för "FM-8 Jr.".</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Dator</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_CN">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>FM-7（"Fujitsu Micro 7"）是富士通公司推出的一款家用电脑。它于 1982 年首次发布，在日本和西班牙销售。它是富士通早期 FM-8 计算机的精简版，在开发过程中被称为 "FM-8 Jr."。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>计算机</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_TW">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>FM-7 (「Fujitsu Micro 7」) 是由 Fujitsu 製造的家用電腦。它於 1982 年首次推出，並在日本和西班牙銷售。它是 Fujitsu 早期 FM-8 電腦的精簡版本，在開發過程中被稱為 "FM-8 Jr."。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>電腦</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
</theme>
