<theme>
    <variables>
        <systemName>Game.com</systemName>
        <systemDescription>The Game.com is a fifth-generation handheld game console released by Tiger Electronics in August 1997. A smaller version, the Game.com Pocket Pro, was released in mid-1999.
The first version of the Game.com can be connected to a 14.4 kbit/s modem for Internet connectivity, hence its name referencing the top level domain .com.

It was the first video game console to include a touchscreen and the first handheld console to include Internet connectivity.</systemDescription>
        <systemManufacturer>Tiger Elec.</systemManufacturer>
        <systemReleaseYear>1997</systemReleaseYear>
        <systemReleaseDate>1997-08</systemReleaseDate>
        <systemReleaseDateFormated>August 1997</systemReleaseDateFormated>
        <systemHardwareType>Portable</systemHardwareType>
        <systemCoverSize>3-4</systemCoverSize>
        <systemCoverSizeType>portrait</systemCoverSizeType>
        <systemColor>54a4b6</systemColor>
        <systemColorPalette1>71829A</systemColorPalette1>
        <systemColorPalette2>293039</systemColorPalette2>
        <systemColorPalette3>AE2B2B</systemColorPalette3>
        <systemColorPalette4>186DA4</systemColorPalette4>
        <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
    </variables>
    <language name="ar_SA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>جهاز Game.com هو جهاز ألعاب محمول باليد من الجيل الخامس أصدرته شركة Tiger Electronics في أغسطس 1997. وصدرت نسخة أصغر، Game.com Pocket Pro، في منتصف عام 1999.
يمكن توصيل الإصدار الأول من Game.com بمودم 14.4 كيلوبايت/ثانية للاتصال بالإنترنت، ومن هنا جاء اسمه الذي يشير إلى نطاق المستوى الأعلى .com.

وكان أول جهاز ألعاب فيديو يتضمن شاشة تعمل باللمس وأول جهاز محمول باليد يتضمن اتصالاً بالإنترنت.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>محمول</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="bs_BA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Game.com je peta generacija ručna igra koja je puštena od tigra elektronike koja je puštena u kolovozu 1997. manja verzija, Igrac.c.chove Pro, puštena je sredinom 1999. godine.
Prva verzija igre.com može se povezati sa modemom od 14,4 kbit / s za internetsku povezanost, otuda i njegovo ime referenciranje gornjeg domena .com .com.

Bila je to prva konzola za video igru koja je uključila dodirnu ekranu i prvu ručnu konzolu za uključivanje internetske povezanosti.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Prenosiv</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ca_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>El Game.com és una consola de joc de cinquena generació de mà publicada per Tiger Electronics l’agost de 1997. Una versió més petita, el Game.com Pocket Pro, es va publicar a mitjan 1999.
La primera versió del joc.com es pot connectar a un mòdem de 14,4 kbit/s per a la connectivitat a Internet, per tant, el seu nom fa referència al domini de primer nivell .com.

Va ser la primera consola de videojocs que va incloure una pantalla tàctil i la primera consola de mà que va incloure la connectivitat a Internet.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Portable</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="de_DE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Der Game.com ist eine Handheld-Spielkonsole der fünften Generation, die von Tiger Electronics im August 1997 auf den Markt gebracht wurde. Eine kleinere Version, der Game.com Pocket Pro, wurde Mitte 1999 auf den Markt gebracht.
Die erste Version des Game.com kann mit einem 14,4 kbit/s-Modem an das Internet angeschlossen werden, daher auch der Name, der sich auf die Top Level Domain .com bezieht.

Es war die erste Videospielkonsole mit einem Touchscreen und die erste Handheld-Konsole mit Internet-Anschlussmöglichkeit.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Tragbar</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="es_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>La Game.com es una videoconsola portátil de quinta generación lanzada por Tiger Electronics en agosto de 1997. A mediados de 1999 salió al mercado una versión más pequeña, la Game.com Pocket Pro.
La primera versión de la Game.com puede conectarse a un módem de 14,4 kbit/s para conectarse a Internet, de ahí que su nombre haga referencia al dominio de primer nivel .com.

Fue la primera videoconsola en incluir una pantalla táctil y la primera consola portátil en incluir conectividad a Internet.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Portátil</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="fr_FR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Le Game.com est une console de jeu portable de cinquième génération lancée par Tiger Electronics en août 1997. Une version plus petite, le Game.com Pocket Pro, a été lancée à la mi-1999.
La première version du Game.com peut être connectée à un modem de 14,4 kbit/s pour la connectivité Internet, d'où son nom qui fait référence au domaine de premier niveau .com.

C'est la première console de jeux vidéo à inclure un écran tactile et la première console portable à inclure une connectivité Internet.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Portable</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="hr_HR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Game.com je ručna konzola za igru pete generacije koju je Tiger Electronics objavila u kolovozu 1997. godine. Manja verzija, Game.com Pocket Pro, objavljena je sredinom 1999.
Prva verzija Game.com može se povezati s modemom od 14,4 kbit/s za internetsku povezanost, pa otuda i njegovo ime upućivanje na domenu najviše razine .com.

Bila je to prva konzola za video igre koja je uključivala zaslon osjetljiv na dodir i prvu ručnu konzolu koja uključuje internetsku povezanost.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Prenosiv</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="it_IT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Game.com è una console portatile di quinta generazione rilasciata da Tiger Electronics nell'agosto 1997. Una versione più piccola, il Game.com Pocket Pro, è stata rilasciata a metà del 1999.
La prima versione del Game.com può essere collegata a un modem a 14,4 kbit/s per la connettività a Internet, da cui il nome che fa riferimento al dominio di primo livello .com.

È stata la prima console per videogiochi a includere un touchscreen e la prima console portatile a includere la connettività Internet.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Portatile</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ja_JP">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>ゲームコムは、1997年8月にタイガー魔法瓶から発売された第5世代の携帯ゲーム機。1999年半ばには、より小型の「ゲーム・コム・ポケット・プロ」が発売された。
ゲーム・ドット・コムの最初のバージョンは、インターネット接続用に14.4kビット/秒のモデムに接続することができ、これがトップ・レベル・ドメイン.comにちなんだ名前の由来となっている。

タッチスクリーンを搭載した初のゲーム機であり、インターネット接続機能を搭載した初の携帯ゲーム機でもある。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>ポータブル</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ko_KR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Game.com은 1997년 8월에 타이거 일렉트로닉스에서 출시한 5세대 휴대용 게임 콘솔입니다. 더 작은 버전인 Game.com 포켓 프로는 1999년 중반에 출시되었습니다.
Game.com의 첫 번째 버전은 인터넷 연결을 위해 14.4kbit/s 모뎀에 연결할 수 있었기 때문에 최상위 도메인 .com을 참조하여 이름이 붙여졌습니다.

이 제품은 터치스크린이 포함된 최초의 비디오 게임 콘솔이자 인터넷 연결 기능이 포함된 최초의 휴대용 콘솔이었습니다.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>휴대성</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="nl_NL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>De Game.com is een handheld spelconsole van de vijfde generatie die in augustus 1997 werd uitgebracht door Tiger Electronics. Een kleinere versie, de Game.com Pocket Pro, werd midden 1999 uitgebracht.
De eerste versie van de Game.com kan worden aangesloten op een 14,4 kbit/s modem voor internetverbinding, vandaar de naam die verwijst naar het top level domein .com.

Het was de eerste videogameconsole met een aanraakscherm en de eerste handheldconsole met internetconnectiviteit.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Draagbaar</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pl_PL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Game.com to przenośna konsola do gier piątej generacji wydana przez Tiger Electronics w sierpniu 1997 roku. Mniejsza wersja, Game.com Pocket Pro, została wydana w połowie 1999 roku.
Pierwsza wersja Game.com może być podłączona do modemu 14,4 kbit/s w celu połączenia z Internetem, stąd jej nazwa nawiązująca do domeny najwyższego poziomu .com.

Była to pierwsza konsola do gier wideo z ekranem dotykowym i pierwsza konsola przenośna z łącznością z Internetem.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Przenośny</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_BR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O Game.com é um console de jogos portátil de quinta geração lançado pela Tiger Electronics em agosto de 1997. Uma versão menor, o Game.com Pocket Pro, foi lançada em meados de 1999.
A primeira versão do Game.com pode ser conectada a um modem de 14,4 kbit/s para conectividade com a Internet, daí seu nome fazer referência ao domínio de nível superior .com.

Foi o primeiro console de videogame a incluir uma tela sensível ao toque e o primeiro console portátil a incluir conectividade com a Internet.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Portátil</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_PT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O Game.com é um console de jogo portátil de quinta geração lançado pela Tiger Electronics em agosto de 1997. Uma versão menor, o Game.com Pocket Pro, foi lançada em meados de 1999.
A primeira versão do Game.com pode ser conectada a um modem de 14,4 kbit/s para conectividade à Internet, portanto, seu nome referenciando o domínio de nível superior .com.

Foi o primeiro console de videogame a incluir uma tela sensível ao toque e o primeiro console portátil a incluir conectividade à Internet.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Portátil</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ro_RO">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Game.com este o consolă de jocuri portabilă de generația a cincea lansată de Tiger Electronics în august 1997. O versiune mai mică, Game.com Pocket Pro, a fost lansată la mijlocul anului 1999.
Prima versiune a Game.com poate fi conectată la un modem de 14,4 kbit/s pentru conectivitate la internet, de unde și numele său care face referire la domeniul de nivel superior .com.

A fost prima consolă de jocuri video care a inclus un ecran tactil și prima consolă portabilă care a inclus conectivitate la internet.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Portabil</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ru_RU">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Game.com - это портативная игровая консоль пятого поколения, выпущенная компанией Tiger Electronics в августе 1997 года. Уменьшенная версия, Game.com Pocket Pro, была выпущена в середине 1999 года.
Первая версия Game.com может быть подключена к модему со скоростью 14,4 кбит/с для выхода в Интернет, поэтому ее название отсылает к домену верхнего уровня .com.

Это была первая игровая консоль с сенсорным экраном и первая портативная консоль с возможностью подключения к Интернету.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Портативный</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sr_RS">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Гаме.цом је ручна игара пете генерације коју је у августу 1997. године објавила мања верзија, мања верзија, утакмицу ИГРЕ.ЦОМ Поцкет Про, слобода је пуштена средином 1999. године.
Прва верзија игре.цом може се повезати на 14,4 кбит / с модем за интернетску повезаност, отуда и назив референцирајући домен највишег нивоа .цом.

Била је то прва видео игарска конзола која укључује екран осетљив на додир и прву ручну конзолу која укључује интернетску повезаност.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Преносив</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sv_SE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Game.com är en femte generationens handhållen spelkonsol som lanserades av Tiger Electronics i augusti 1997. En mindre version, Game.com Pocket Pro, släpptes i mitten av 1999.
Den första versionen av Game.com kan anslutas till ett 14,4 kbit/s modem för Internetuppkoppling, därav namnet som refererar till toppdomänen .com.

Det var den första videospelskonsolen med pekskärm och den första handhållna konsolen med Internetanslutning.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Bärbar</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_CN">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Game.com 是虎牌电子公司于 1997 年 8 月发布的第五代掌上游戏机。1999 年年中发布了一个较小的版本 Game.com Pocket Pro。
Game.com 的第一个版本可以连接到 14.4 kbit/s 的调制解调器上进行互联网连接，因此其名称引用了顶级域名 .com。

它是第一款带有触摸屏的视频游戏机，也是第一款带有互联网连接功能的掌上游戏机。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>便携式</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_TW">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Game.com 是 Tiger Electronics 於 1997 年 8 月推出的第五代掌上遊戲機。1999 年中推出了較小的版本 Game.com Pocket Pro。
Game.com 的第一個版本可連接 14.4 kbit/s 的數據機進行網際網路連線，因此其名稱參考了頂級網域名稱 .com。

它是第一款包含觸控螢幕的視訊遊戲機，也是第一款包含網際網路連線功能的掌上型遊戲機。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>可攜式</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
</theme>
