<theme>
    <variables>
        <systemName>GameCube</systemName>
        <systemDescription>The Nintendo GameCube is a home video game console released by Nintendo in Japan and North America in 2001 and in PAL territories in 2002. The GameCube is Nintendo's entry in the sixth generation of video game consoles and is the successor to their previous console, the Nintendo 64. The GameCube competed with Sony's PlayStation 2 and Microsoft's Xbox.

The GameCube is the first Nintendo console to use optical discs as its primary storage medium. The discs are in a miniDVD-based format but the system was not designed to play full-sized DVDs or audio CDs unlike its competitors, and mainly focused on gaming instead. The console supports limited online gaming for a small number of games via a GameCube broadband or modem adapter and can connect to a Game Boy Advance with a link cable, which allows players to access exclusive in-game features using the handheld as a second screen and controller like a Wii U.</systemDescription>
        <systemManufacturer>Nintendo</systemManufacturer>
        <systemReleaseYear>2001</systemReleaseYear>
        <systemReleaseDate>2001-08-14</systemReleaseDate>
        <systemReleaseDateFormated>November 18, 2001</systemReleaseDateFormated>
        <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        <systemCoverSize>243-340</systemCoverSize>
        <systemCoverSizeType>portrait</systemCoverSizeType>
        <systemColor>958bf4</systemColor>
        <systemColorPalette1>7B79AA</systemColorPalette1>
        <systemColorPalette2>524C82</systemColorPalette2>
        <systemColorPalette3>CBC9E0</systemColorPalette3>
        <systemColorPalette4>1E1C11</systemColorPalette4>
        <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
    </variables>
    <language name="ar_SA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>جهاز نينتندو جيم كيوب هو جهاز ألعاب فيديو منزلي أصدرته شركة نينتندو في اليابان وأمريكا الشمالية في عام 2001 وفي مناطق PAL في عام 2002. GameCube هو جهاز نينتندو في الجيل السادس من أجهزة ألعاب الفيديو، وهو خليفة لوحدة التحكم السابقة Nintendo 64. تنافس GameCube مع PlayStation 2 من سوني وXbox من مايكروسوفت.

GameCube هو أول وحدة تحكم من نينتندو تستخدم الأقراص الضوئية كوسيط تخزين أساسي. الأقراص بتنسيق يعتمد على أقراص ميني دي في دي، لكن النظام لم يصمم لتشغيل أقراص دي في دي كاملة الحجم أو أقراص صوتية مدمجة على عكس منافسيه، وركز بشكل أساسي على الألعاب بدلاً من ذلك. وتدعم وحدة التحكم الألعاب المحدودة عبر الإنترنت لعدد قليل من الألعاب عبر محول النطاق العريض أو المودم GameCube ويمكنها الاتصال بجهاز Game Boy Advance باستخدام كابل رابط، مما يسمح للاعبين بالوصول إلى ميزات حصرية داخل اللعبة باستخدام الجهاز المحمول كشاشة ثانية ووحدة تحكم مثل Wii U.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>وحدة التحكم</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="bs_BA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Nintendo Gamecube je konzola za video igre koja je u Japanu i u Sjevernoj Americi 2001. godine objavila u Japanu i na PAL teritorijama 2002. godine. Gamecube je ulazak Nintendoa u šestoj generaciji video igara, a nintendo 64. Gamecube se natjecala sa Sonyjevim igralištem 2 i Microsoftovom Xboxom.

Gamecube je prva Nintendona konzola za korištenje optičkih diskova kao svog primarnog skladišta. Diskovi su u miniDVD-temeljenom formatu, ali sustav nije dizajniran za reprodukciju DVD-a ili audio CD-a za razliku od svojih konkurenata, a uglavnom se fokusira na igranje. Konzola podržava mrežno igranje za mali broj igara putem Gamecube širokopojasne ili modemske adapterom i može se povezati s avansom za igru pomoću kabla za povezivanje, što omogućava igračima da pristupe ekskluzivnim funkcijama u igri koristeći kao drugi ekran i kontroler poput wii u.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Konzola</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ca_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>La Nintendo Gamecube és una consola de videojocs a casa llançada per Nintendo a Japó i Amèrica del Nord el 2001 i als territoris PAL el 2002. El Gamecube és l’entrada de Nintendo a la sisena generació de consoles de videojocs i és el successor de la seva consola anterior, la Nintendo, la Nintendo64. El GameCube va competir amb PlayStation 2 de Sony i Microsoft's Xbox.

El GameCube és la primera consola de Nintendo a utilitzar discos òptics com a mitjà d'emmagatzematge principal. Els discos es troben en un format basat en MINIDVD, però el sistema no va ser dissenyat per reproduir DVD de mida completa o CD d'àudio a diferència dels seus competidors i es va centrar principalment en el joc. La consola admet un joc en línia limitat per a un nombre reduït de jocs mitjançant un adaptador de banda ampla o mòdem GameCube i pot connectar-se a un Game Boy Advance amb un cable d’enllaç, que permet als jugadors accedir a funcions exclusives del joc mitjançant el Handheld com a segona pantalla icontrolador com un wii U.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="de_DE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Der Nintendo GameCube ist eine Videospielkonsole für den Heimgebrauch, die von Nintendo 2001 in Japan und Nordamerika und 2002 in PAL-Gebieten auf den Markt gebracht wurde. Der GameCube ist Nintendos Einstieg in die sechste Generation von Videospielkonsolen und ist der Nachfolger der vorherigen Konsole, des Nintendo 64. Der GameCube konkurrierte mit der PlayStation 2 von Sony und der Xbox von Microsoft.

Der GameCube ist die erste Nintendo-Konsole, die optische Discs als primäres Speichermedium verwendet. Die Discs sind in einem miniDVD-basierten Format, aber das System wurde im Gegensatz zu seinen Konkurrenten nicht zum Abspielen von DVDs oder Audio-CDs in voller Größe entwickelt und konzentrierte sich stattdessen auf das Spielen. Die Konsole unterstützt begrenztes Online-Gaming für eine kleine Anzahl von Spielen über einen GameCube-Breitband- oder -Modemadapter und kann mit einem Link-Kabel an einen Game Boy Advance angeschlossen werden, was es den Spielern ermöglicht, auf exklusive In-Game-Funktionen zuzugreifen, indem sie den Handheld als zweiten Bildschirm und Controller wie eine Wii U verwenden.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Konsole</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="es_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>La Nintendo GameCube es una videoconsola doméstica lanzada por Nintendo en Japón y Norteamérica en 2001 y en territorios PAL en 2002. La GameCube es la entrada de Nintendo en la sexta generación de consolas de videojuegos y es la sucesora de su anterior consola, la Nintendo 64. La GameCube compitió con la PlayStation 2 de Sony y la Xbox de Microsoft. La GameCube compitió con la PlayStation 2 de Sony y la Xbox de Microsoft.

La GameCube es la primera consola de Nintendo que utiliza discos ópticos como principal medio de almacenamiento. Los discos tienen un formato basado en miniDVD, pero la consola no se diseñó para reproducir DVD de tamaño completo ni CD de audio, como sus competidoras, y se centró principalmente en los juegos. La consola admite un número limitado de juegos en línea a través de un adaptador de banda ancha o módem para GameCube y puede conectarse a una Game Boy Advance con un cable de enlace, lo que permite a los jugadores acceder a funciones exclusivas del juego utilizando la consola portátil como segunda pantalla y mando, al igual que una Wii U.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Consola</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="fr_FR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>La Nintendo GameCube est une console de jeux vidéo de salon commercialisée par Nintendo au Japon et en Amérique du Nord en 2001 et dans les territoires PAL en 2002. La GameCube est l'entrée de Nintendo dans la sixième génération de consoles de jeux vidéo et le successeur de la console précédente, la Nintendo 64. La GameCube était en concurrence avec la PlayStation 2 de Sony et la Xbox de Microsoft.

La GameCube est la première console Nintendo à utiliser des disques optiques comme principal support de stockage. Les disques sont au format miniDVD, mais la console n'a pas été conçue pour lire des DVD ou des CD audio de taille normale, contrairement à ses concurrents, et s'est plutôt concentrée sur les jeux. La console prend en charge un nombre limité de jeux en ligne via un adaptateur modem ou large bande GameCube et peut se connecter à un Game Boy Advance à l'aide d'un câble de liaison, ce qui permet aux joueurs d'accéder à des fonctions exclusives en jeu en utilisant l'ordinateur de poche comme second écran et manette, à l'instar d'une Wii U.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="hr_HR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Nintendo Gamecube je konzola za kućne video igre koju je Nintendo objavio u Japanu i Sjevernoj Americi 2001. godine, a na teritorijama PAL -a 2002. godine. Gamecube je Nintendov unos u šestoj generaciji konzola za video igre i nasljednik njihove prethodne konzole, Nintendo 64.

GameCube je prva Nintendo konzola koja je koristila optičke diskove kao svoj primarni medij za pohranu. Diskovi su u formatu utemeljenom na miniDVD-u, ali sustav nije osmišljen za reprodukciju DVD-a ili audio CD-a u punoj veličini, za razliku od konkurenta, a umjesto toga uglavnom usredotočeni na igranje. Konzola podržava ograničeno internetsko igranje za mali broj igara putem širokopojasnog ili modemskog adaptera GameCube i može se povezati s igračem Advance s kablom s vezama, koji omogućuje igračima pristup ekskluzivnim značajkama u igri pomoću ručnog zaslona i kontrolera poput Wii U.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Konzola</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="it_IT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Il Nintendo GameCube è una console per videogiochi domestica pubblicata da Nintendo in Giappone e Nord America nel 2001 e nei territori PAL nel 2002. Il GameCube rappresenta l'ingresso di Nintendo nella sesta generazione di console per videogiochi ed è il successore della console precedente, il Nintendo 64. Il GameCube ha fatto concorrenza alla PlayStation 2 di Sony e alla Xbox di Microsoft.

Il GameCube è la prima console Nintendo a utilizzare dischi ottici come supporto di memorizzazione principale. I dischi sono in formato miniDVD, ma la console non è stata progettata per riprodurre DVD o CD audio a grandezza naturale, a differenza dei suoi concorrenti, e si è concentrata principalmente sul gioco. La console supporta un numero limitato di giochi online tramite un adattatore GameCube a banda larga o modem e può essere collegata a un Game Boy Advance con un cavo di collegamento, che consente ai giocatori di accedere a funzioni esclusive del gioco utilizzando il palmare come secondo schermo e controller come una Wii U.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ja_JP">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>ニンテンドーゲームキューブは、任天堂が2001年に日本と北米で、2002年にPAL地域で発売した家庭用ゲーム機である。ゲームキューブは任天堂の第6世代ビデオゲーム機への参入であり、以前のゲーム機であるNINTENDO64の後継機である。ゲームキューブはソニーのプレイステーション2とマイクロソフトのXboxと競合した。

ゲームキューブは、主記憶媒体として光ディスクを採用した任天堂初のゲーム機である。ディスクはminiDVDベースのフォーマットだが、競合他社とは異なり、フルサイズのDVDやオーディオCDを再生するようには設計されておらず、代わりにゲームに主眼を置いていた。また、ゲームボーイアドバンスとリンクケーブルで接続することができ、ゲームボーイアドバンスをWii Uのようなセカンドスクリーンやコントローラーとして使用することで、専用のゲーム内機能にアクセスすることができる。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>コンソール</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ko_KR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>닌텐도 게임큐브는 닌텐도가 2001년 일본과 북미에서, 2002년 PAL 지역에서 출시한 가정용 비디오 게임 콘솔입니다. 게임큐브는 닌텐도의 6세대 비디오 게임 콘솔로, 이전 콘솔인 닌텐도 64의 후속작입니다. 게임큐브는 소니의 플레이스테이션 2와 마이크로소프트의 엑스박스와 경쟁했습니다.

게임큐브는 광 디스크를 기본 저장 매체로 사용한 최초의 닌텐도 콘솔입니다. 디스크는 미니DVD 기반 형식이지만 경쟁사와 달리 풀 사이즈 DVD나 오디오 CD를 재생하도록 설계되지 않았고, 대신 주로 게임에 중점을 두었습니다. 이 콘솔은 GameCube 광대역 또는 모뎀 어댑터를 통해 소수의 게임에 대한 제한된 온라인 게임을 지원하며, 링크 케이블로 Game Boy Advance에 연결하면 플레이어가 핸드헬드를 Wii U처럼 세컨드 스크린 및 컨트롤러로 사용하여 게임 내 독점 기능에 액세스할 수 있습니다.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>콘솔</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="nl_NL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>De Nintendo GameCube is een videogameconsole voor thuisgebruik die in 2001 door Nintendo werd uitgebracht in Japan en Noord-Amerika en in 2002 in PAL-gebieden. De GameCube is Nintendo's entree in de zesde generatie videogameconsoles en is de opvolger van hun vorige console, de Nintendo 64. De GameCube concurreerde met Sony's PlayStation 2 en Microsoft's Xbox.

De GameCube is de eerste Nintendo-console die optische schijven gebruikt als primair opslagmedium. De schijven zijn in een miniDVD-gebaseerd formaat, maar het systeem was niet ontworpen om full-sized DVD's of audio CD's af te spelen, in tegenstelling tot zijn concurrenten, en richtte zich voornamelijk op gaming. Het systeem ondersteunt beperkt online gamen voor een klein aantal spellen via een GameCube breedband- of modemadapter en kan worden aangesloten op een Game Boy Advance met een linkkabel, waardoor spelers toegang krijgen tot exclusieve functies in het spel door de handheld te gebruiken als een tweede scherm en controller, zoals bij een Wii U.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pl_PL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Nintendo GameCube to domowa konsola do gier wideo wydana przez Nintendo w Japonii i Ameryce Północnej w 2001 roku oraz na terytoriach PAL w 2002 roku. GameCube to wejście Nintendo do szóstej generacji konsol do gier wideo i jest następcą ich poprzedniej konsoli, Nintendo 64. GameCube konkurował z konsolami PlayStation 2 firmy Sony i Xbox firmy Microsoft.

GameCube jest pierwszą konsolą Nintendo, która wykorzystuje dyski optyczne jako główny nośnik pamięci. Dyski są w formacie miniDVD, ale system nie został zaprojektowany do odtwarzania pełnowymiarowych płyt DVD lub audio CD, w przeciwieństwie do swoich konkurentów, i skupiał się głównie na grach. Konsola obsługuje ograniczoną liczbę gier online dla niewielkiej liczby gier za pośrednictwem adaptera szerokopasmowego lub modemu GameCube i może łączyć się z Game Boy Advance za pomocą kabla łączącego, który umożliwia graczom dostęp do ekskluzywnych funkcji w grze przy użyciu handhelda jako drugiego ekranu i kontrolera, takiego jak Wii U.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Konsola</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_BR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O Nintendo GameCube é um console de videogame doméstico lançado pela Nintendo no Japão e na América do Norte em 2001 e nos territórios PAL em 2002. O GameCube é a entrada da Nintendo na sexta geração de consoles de videogame e é o sucessor do console anterior, o Nintendo 64. O GameCube competiu com o PlayStation 2 da Sony e o Xbox da Microsoft.

O GameCube é o primeiro console da Nintendo a usar discos ópticos como seu principal meio de armazenamento. Os discos estão em um formato baseado em miniDVD, mas o sistema não foi projetado para reproduzir DVDs de tamanho normal ou CDs de áudio, ao contrário de seus concorrentes, e se concentrou principalmente em jogos. O console suporta jogos on-line limitados para um pequeno número de jogos por meio de um adaptador de banda larga ou modem GameCube e pode se conectar a um Game Boy Advance com um cabo de conexão, o que permite que os jogadores acessem recursos exclusivos do jogo usando o dispositivo portátil como uma segunda tela e controle, como um Wii U.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_PT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O Nintendo Gamecube é um console de videogame caseiro lançado pela Nintendo no Japão e na América do Norte em 2001 e nos territórios da PAL em 2002. O Gamecube é a entrada da Nintendo na sexta geração de consoles de videogame e é o sucessor de Sony 2 e o Nintendo 64.

O GameCube é o primeiro console da Nintendo a usar discos ópticos como seu principal meio de armazenamento. Os discos estão em um formato baseado em MinIDVD, mas o sistema não foi projetado para jogar DVDs de tamanho normal ou CDs de áudio, ao contrário de seus concorrentes, e focados principalmente nos jogos. O console suporta jogos on-line limitados para um pequeno número de jogos por meio de um adaptador de banda larga ou modem da GameCube e pode se conectar a um Game Boy Advance com um cabo de link, que permite que os jogadores acessem recursos exclusivos no jogo usando o computador de mão como uma segunda tela e controlador como um Wii U.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ro_RO">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Nintendo GameCube este o consolă de jocuri video pentru acasă lansată de Nintendo în Japonia și America de Nord în 2001 și în teritoriile PAL în 2002. GameCube este intrarea Nintendo în a șasea generație de console de jocuri video și este succesorul consolei lor anterioare, Nintendo 64. GameCube a concurat cu PlayStation 2 de la Sony și Xbox de la Microsoft.

GameCube este prima consolă Nintendo care utilizează discuri optice ca mediu principal de stocare. Discurile sunt în format miniDVD, dar consola nu a fost concepută pentru a reda DVD-uri de dimensiuni normale sau CD-uri audio, spre deosebire de concurenții săi, și s-a axat în principal pe jocuri. Consola acceptă jocuri online limitate pentru un număr mic de jocuri prin intermediul unui adaptor GameCube de bandă largă sau modem și se poate conecta la un Game Boy Advance cu un cablu de legătură, ceea ce permite jucătorilor să acceseze funcții exclusive în jocuri folosind consola portabilă ca un al doilea ecran și controler, precum un Wii U.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Consolă</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ru_RU">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Nintendo GameCube - домашняя игровая приставка, выпущенная компанией Nintendo в Японии и Северной Америке в 2001 году, а в странах PAL - в 2002 году. GameCube является представителем шестого поколения игровых приставок Nintendo и преемником предыдущей консоли, Nintendo 64. GameCube конкурировала с PlayStation 2 от Sony и Xbox от Microsoft.

GameCube - первая консоль Nintendo, в которой в качестве основного носителя информации используются оптические диски. Диски имеют формат miniDVD, но в отличие от своих конкурентов консоль не предназначалась для воспроизведения полноразмерных DVD или аудио CD, а была ориентирована в основном на игры. Консоль поддерживает ограниченный онлайн-гейминг для небольшого количества игр через широкополосный или модемный адаптер GameCube и может подключаться к Game Boy Advance с помощью соединительного кабеля, что позволяет игрокам получать доступ к эксклюзивным игровым функциям, используя портативную консоль в качестве второго экрана и контроллера, как Wii U.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Консоль</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sr_RS">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Нинтендо Гамецубе је хоме видео игарска конзола коју је Нинтендо у Јапанској и северној Америци у 2002. години и у Пал Територији у 2002. години. Гамецубе је Нинтендо улазак у шесту генерацију видео игара у шестој генерацији њихове претходне конзоле, Нинтендо 64. ГамеЦубе је такмичио се са Сони-овом ПлаиСтатион 2 и Мицрософтовом Ксбок-ом и Мицрософтовом Ксбок-ом и Мицрософтовом Ксбок-ом и Мицрософтовим Ксбок-ом и Мицрософтовим Ксбок-ом и Мицрософтовим Ксбок-ом и Мицрософтовим Ксбок-ом и Мицрософтовом Ксбок и Мицрософтовом Ксбок и Мицрософтовом Ксбоку и Мицрософтовом Ксбоку и Мицрософтовом Ксбоку.

Гамецубе је прва Нинтендо конзола за коришћење оптичких дискова као њен примарни медијум за складиштење.Дискови су у формату у МиниДВД-у, али систем није дизајниран за репродукцију ДВД-а или аудио ЦД-ова за разлику од својих такмичара, а углавном се фокусира на играње.Конзола подржава ограничено играње на мрежи за мали број игара путем ГАМЕЦУБЕ широкопојасне или модемског адаптера и може да се повеже са игараним каблом, који омогућава играчима да приступе ексклузивним функцијама у игри у игри и контролору као и други екран и контролер.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Конзола</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sv_SE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Nintendo GameCube är en hemkonsol för videospel som släpptes av Nintendo i Japan och Nordamerika 2001 och i PAL-områden 2002. GameCube är Nintendos inträde i den sjätte generationen av videospelskonsoler och är efterföljaren till deras tidigare konsol, Nintendo 64. GameCube konkurrerade med Sonys PlayStation 2 och Microsofts Xbox.

GameCube är den första Nintendo-konsolen som använder optiska skivor som sitt primära lagringsmedium. Skivorna är i ett miniDVD-baserat format men systemet var inte utformat för att spela fullstora DVD-skivor eller ljud-CD-skivor till skillnad från sina konkurrenter, utan fokuserade främst på spel istället. Konsolen stöder begränsat onlinespelande för ett litet antal spel via en GameCube bredbands- eller modemadapter och kan anslutas till en Game Boy Advance med en länkkabel, vilket gör att spelarna kan få tillgång till exklusiva funktioner i spelet genom att använda handenheten som en andra skärm och handkontroll som en Wii U.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Konsol</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_CN">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>任天堂 GameCube 是任天堂于 2001 年在日本和北美地区推出的家用视频游戏机，2002 年在 PAL 地区推出。GameCube 是任天堂推出的第六代视频游戏机，也是上一代游戏机任天堂 64 的后继机。GameCube 与索尼的 PlayStation 2 和微软的 Xbox 竞争。

GameCube 是任天堂第一款使用光盘作为主要存储介质的游戏机。光盘采用迷你 DVD 格式，但与竞争对手不同的是，该系统并不设计用于播放全尺寸 DVD 或音频 CD，而是主要侧重于游戏。该游戏机通过 GameCube 宽带或调制解调器适配器支持少量游戏的有限在线游戏，并可通过连接线与 Game Boy Advance 连接，这样玩家就可以像 Wii U 一样将手持设备作为第二屏幕和控制器来访问独有的游戏功能。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>控制台</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_TW">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Nintendo GameCube 是 Nintendo 於 2001 年在日本和北美發行的家用視訊遊戲主機，並於 2002 年在 PAL 區域發行。GameCube 是任天堂推出的第六代視訊遊戲主機，也是上一代主機 Nintendo 64 的後繼機種。GameCube 的競爭對手是 Sony 的 PlayStation 2 和 Microsoft 的 Xbox。

GameCube 是第一台使用光碟作為主要儲存媒體的任天堂遊戲機。光碟的格式以 miniDVD 為主，但與競爭對手不同的是，該系統並非設計用來播放全尺寸 DVD 或音訊 CD，而是主要專注於遊戲。控制台透過 GameCube 寬頻或數據機轉接器，支援少數遊戲的有限線上遊戲，並可透過連結線連接 Game Boy Advance，讓玩家可以像 Wii U 一樣，使用掌上型裝置作為第二個螢幕和控制器，存取遊戲中的獨家功能。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>控制台</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
</theme>
