<theme>
    <variables>
        <systemName>Kodi</systemName>
        <systemDescription>Kodi is a free and open-source media player software application developed by the XBMC Foundation, a non-profit technology consortium. Kodi is available for multiple operating systems and hardware platforms, with a software 10-foot user interface for use with televisions and remote controls.</systemDescription>
        <systemManufacturer>XBMC Fdn.</systemManufacturer>
        <systemReleaseYear>2002</systemReleaseYear>
        <systemReleaseDate>2002</systemReleaseDate>
        <systemReleaseDateFormated>2002</systemReleaseDateFormated>
        <systemHardwareType>Folder</systemHardwareType>
        <systemCoverSize>3-4</systemCoverSize>
        <systemCoverSizeType>portrait</systemCoverSizeType>
        <systemColor>00141F</systemColor>
        <systemColorPalette1>186AAC</systemColorPalette1>
        <systemColorPalette2>36A2CD</systemColorPalette2>
        <systemColorPalette3>448F38</systemColorPalette3>
        <systemColorPalette4>BF2E31</systemColorPalette4>
        <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
    </variables>
    <language name="ar_SA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Kodi هو تطبيق برمجيات مشغل وسائط مجاني ومفتوح المصدر طورته مؤسسة XBMC، وهي اتحاد تكنولوجي غير ربحي. يتوفر Kodi للعديد من أنظمة التشغيل ومنصات الأجهزة، مع واجهة مستخدم برمجية ذات 10 أقدام للاستخدام مع أجهزة التلفاز وأجهزة التحكم عن بعد.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>المجلد</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="bs_BA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Kodi je besplatan i open-medijski softver za medijsku plejeru razvijen od strane XBMC fondacije, neprofitnog tehnološkog konzorcijuma. Kodi je dostupan za više operativnih sistema i hardverske platforme, sa softverom za korisničko sučelje 10 stopa za upotrebu sa televizorima i daljinskim upravljačem.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Mapa</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ca_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Kodi és una aplicació de programari de reproductors de mitjans de comunicació gratuït i de codi obert desenvolupat per la XBMC Foundation, un consorci tecnològic sense ànim de lucre. Kodi està disponible per a diversos sistemes operatius i plataformes de maquinari, amb una interfície d'usuari de programari de 10 peus per utilitzar-los amb televisors i controls remots.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Folder</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="de_DE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Kodi ist eine kostenlose und quelloffene Media-Player-Software, die von der XBMC Foundation, einem gemeinnützigen Technologiekonsortium, entwickelt wurde. Kodi ist für mehrere Betriebssysteme und Hardware-Plattformen verfügbar und verfügt über eine Software-Benutzeroberfläche für die Verwendung mit Fernsehern und Fernbedienungen.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Mappe</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="es_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Kodi es una aplicación de software de reproducción multimedia gratuita y de código abierto desarrollada por la Fundación XBMC, un consorcio tecnológico sin ánimo de lucro. Kodi está disponible para múltiples sistemas operativos y plataformas de hardware, con una interfaz de usuario de 10 pies de software para su uso con televisores y mandos a distancia.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Carpeta</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="fr_FR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Kodi est un logiciel de lecture multimédia libre et gratuit développé par la Fondation XBMC, un consortium technologique à but non lucratif. Kodi est disponible pour plusieurs systèmes d'exploitation et plates-formes matérielles, avec une interface utilisateur logicielle à 10 pieds à utiliser avec les téléviseurs et les télécommandes.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Dossier</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="hr_HR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Kodi je besplatna aplikacija softvera Media Player softvera s otvorenim kodom koju je razvio XBMC Foundation, neprofitni tehnološki konzorcij. Kodi je dostupan za više operativnih sustava i hardverskih platformi, s softverskim korisničkim sučeljem od 10 stopa za upotrebu s televizorima i daljinskim upravljanjima.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Mapa</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="it_IT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Kodi è un'applicazione software per lettori multimediali gratuita e open-source sviluppata dalla XBMC Foundation, un consorzio tecnologico senza scopo di lucro. Kodi è disponibile per diversi sistemi operativi e piattaforme hardware, con un'interfaccia utente software a 10 piedi da utilizzare con televisori e telecomandi.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Cartella</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ja_JP">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Kodiは、非営利の技術コンソーシアムであるXBMC財団によって開発されたフリーでオープンソースのメディアプレーヤーソフトウェアアプリケーションです。Kodiは、複数のオペレーティングシステムとハードウェアプラットフォームで利用可能で、テレビやリモコンで使用するためのソフトウェア10フィートユーザーインターフェイスを備えています。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>フォルダ</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ko_KR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Kodi는 비영리 기술 컨소시엄인 XBMC 재단에서 개발한 무료 오픈 소스 미디어 플레이어 소프트웨어 애플리케이션입니다. Kodi는 여러 운영 체제 및 하드웨어 플랫폼에서 사용할 수 있으며, TV 및 리모컨과 함께 사용할 수 있는 10피트 소프트웨어 사용자 인터페이스를 제공합니다.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>폴더</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="nl_NL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Kodi is een gratis en open-source softwaretoepassing voor mediaspelers, ontwikkeld door de XBMC Foundation, een non-profit technologieconsortium. Kodi is beschikbaar voor meerdere besturingssystemen en hardwareplatforms, met een software 10-voet gebruikersinterface voor gebruik met televisies en afstandsbedieningen.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Map</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pl_PL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Kodi to darmowy odtwarzacz multimedialny o otwartym kodzie źródłowym, opracowany przez XBMC Foundation, konsorcjum technologiczne non-profit. Kodi jest dostępny dla wielu systemów operacyjnych i platform sprzętowych, z interfejsem użytkownika 10-foot do użytku z telewizorami i pilotami zdalnego sterowania.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Folder</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_BR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O Kodi é um aplicativo de software reprodutor de mídia gratuito e de código aberto desenvolvido pela XBMC Foundation, um consórcio de tecnologia sem fins lucrativos. O Kodi está disponível para vários sistemas operacionais e plataformas de hardware, com uma interface de usuário de 10 pés de software para uso com televisores e controles remotos.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Pasta</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_PT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>A Kodi é um aplicativo de software de media player gratuito e de código aberto desenvolvido pela XBMC Foundation, um consórcio de tecnologia sem fins lucrativos. O KODI está disponível para vários sistemas operacionais e plataformas de hardware, com uma interface de usuário de 10 pés de software para uso com televisores e controles remotos.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Pasta</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ro_RO">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Kodi este o aplicație software media player gratuită și open-source dezvoltată de Fundația XBMC, un consorțiu tehnologic non-profit. Kodi este disponibil pentru mai multe sisteme de operare și platforme hardware, cu o interfață utilizator software de 10 picioare pentru utilizarea cu televizoare și telecomenzi.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Dosar</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ru_RU">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Kodi - это бесплатный медиаплеер с открытым исходным кодом, разработанный некоммерческим технологическим консорциумом XBMC Foundation. Kodi доступен для различных операционных систем и аппаратных платформ, имеет программный 10-футовый пользовательский интерфейс для использования с телевизорами и пультами дистанционного управления.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Папка</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sr_RS">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Коди је бесплатна и отворена софтверска апликација Медиа Плаиер софтвера који је развио Фондација КСБМЦ, конзорцијум непрофитне технологије.Коди је доступан за више оперативних система и хардверских платформи, са корисничким интерфејсом софтвера 10 стопа за употребу са телевизорима и даљинским управљачима.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Мапа</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sv_SE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Kodi är en mediaspelare med fri och öppen källkod som utvecklats av XBMC Foundation, ett icke vinstdrivande teknikkonsortium. Kodi finns tillgänglig för flera operativsystem och hårdvaruplattformar, med ett 10-fots användargränssnitt för användning med TV-apparater och fjärrkontroller.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Mapp</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_CN">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Kodi 是由非营利技术联盟 XBMC 基金会开发的一款免费开源媒体播放器软件应用程序。Kodi 可用于多种操作系统和硬件平台，其软件用户界面为 10 英尺，可与电视机和遥控器配合使用。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>文件夹</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_TW">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Kodi 是由 XBMC 基金會 (XBMC Foundation) 所開發的免費開放原始碼媒體播放器軟體應用程式，XBMC 基金會是一個非營利的技術聯盟。Kodi 適用於多種作業系統和硬體平台，其軟體 10 呎使用者介面可搭配電視和遙控器使用。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>資料夾</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
</theme>
