<theme>
    <variables>
        <systemName>Sega Model 2</systemName>
        <systemDescription>The Sega Model 2 is an arcade system board originally debuted by Sega in 1993 as a successor to the Sega Model 1 board. It is an extension of the Model 1 hardware, most notably introducing the concept of texture-mapped polygons, allowing for more realistic 3D graphics (for its time). The Model 2 board was an important milestone for the arcade industry, and helped launch several key arcade franchises of the 90s, including Daytona USA, Virtua Cop, Sega Rally Championship, Dead or Alive, Virtua Striker, Cyber Troopers Virtual-On and The House of the Dead. The Model 2 was engineered with help from GE Aerospace (acquired by Martin Marietta in 1993, now part of Lockheed Martin), who designed the texture-mapping technology incorporated by the Model 2. The Model 2's development was led by famed game designer Yu Suzuki. The Model 2 arcade board debuted along with Daytona USA, a game which was finished, copyrighted and debuted at the JAMMA arcade show in 1993. There four versions of the system: the original Model 2 and the Model 2A-CRX, Model 2B-CRX and Model 2C-CRX variants. Model 2 and 2A-CRX used a custom DSP with internal code for the geometrizer while 2B-CRX and 2C-CRX used well documented DSPs and uploaded the geometrizer code at startup to the DSP.</systemDescription>
        <systemManufacturer>Sega</systemManufacturer>
        <systemReleaseYear>1993</systemReleaseYear>
        <systemReleaseDate>1993-01-01</systemReleaseDate>
        <systemReleaseDateFormated>January 1, 1993</systemReleaseDateFormated>
        <systemHardwareType>Arcade</systemHardwareType>
        <systemCoverSize>3-4</systemCoverSize>
        <systemCoverSizeType>portrait</systemCoverSizeType>
        <systemColor>3b96ef</systemColor>
        <systemColorPalette1>034693</systemColorPalette1>
        <systemColorPalette2>F7ED18</systemColorPalette2>
        <systemColorPalette3>F4133D</systemColorPalette3>
        <systemColorPalette4>199A40</systemColorPalette4>
        <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
    </variables>
    <language name="ar_SA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>لوحة نظام Sega Model 2 هي لوحة نظام أركيد ظهرت لأول مرة من قبل Sega في عام 1993 كخلف للوحة Sega Model 1. وهي امتداد لأجهزة الموديل 1، وأبرزها تقديم مفهوم المضلعات ذات الخرائط المبنية على النسيج، مما يسمح برسومات ثلاثية الأبعاد أكثر واقعية (بالنسبة لوقتها). كانت لوحة الطراز 2 علامة فارقة مهمة في صناعة الأركيد، وساعدت في إطلاق العديد من ألعاب الأركيد الرئيسية في التسعينيات، بما في ذلك Daytona USA و Virtua Cop و Sega Rally Championship و Dead or Alive و Virtua Striker و Cyber Troopers Virtual-On و The House of the Dead. تم تصميم الطراز 2 بمساعدة من شركة GE Aerospace (التي استحوذت عليها شركة Martin Marietta في عام 1993، وهي الآن جزء من شركة Lockheed Martin)، التي صممت تقنية رسم خرائط النسيج التي يتضمنها الطراز 2. قاد عملية تطوير الموديل 2 مصمم الألعاب الشهير يو سوزوكي. وظهرت لوحة الموديل 2 لأول مرة مع لعبة Daytona USA، وهي لعبة تم الانتهاء منها وحصلت على حقوق الطبع والنشر وظهرت لأول مرة في معرض JAMMA للألعاب في عام 1993. كانت هناك أربعة إصدارات من النظام: الطراز 2 الأصلي والطراز 2A-CRX والطراز 2B-CRX والطراز 2C-CRX. استخدم الموديل 2 والموديل 2A-CRX معالج DSP مخصص مع كود داخلي للمُعدِّل الهندسي بينما استخدم الموديلان 2B-CRX و2C-CRX معالج DSP موثق جيدًا وتم تحميل كود المُعدِّل الهندسي عند بدء التشغيل إلى DSP.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>أركيد</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="bs_BA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Sega Model 2 je arkadna matična ploča koju je iz 1993. godine izvorno debitovao Sega 1993. kao nasljednik ploče Sega Model 1. To je proširenje hardvera modela 1, što najiskozbivo najvažnije uvodi koncept poligona preslikanih tekstura, koji omogućava realniju 3D grafiku (za svoje vrijeme). Odbor modela 2 bio je važan prekretnica za arkadnu industriju, a pomogao je u pokretanju nekoliko ključnih arcadnih franšiza 90-ih, uključujući Daytona SAD, Virtua COP, Sega Rally Championship, mrtvi ili živ, virtuari, virtual-on i kuću mrtvih. Model 2 je bio dizajniran uz pomoć GE Aerospacea (stekao Martin Marietta 1993. godine, sada dio Lockheed Martina), koji je dizajnirao tehnologiju za mapiranje teksture ugrađenu od strane modela 2. Razvoj modela 2 je vodio poznati dizajner za glavu Yu Suzuki. Model 2 Arcade Board debitovao je zajedno sa Daytonom SAD-om, a debitoran je u ekipu Jamma na Arkadenoj emisiji 1993. godine. Tu su četiri verzije sistema: Originalni model 2A-CRX, model 2B-CRX i model 2C-CRX varijante. Model 2 i 2A-CRX koristili su prilagođeni DSP s internim kodom za geometrizer, dok su 2b-CRX i 2C-CRX koristili dobro dokumentene DSP-ove i učitavali kôd geometrije pri pokretanju na DSP.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Arkada</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ca_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>El SEGA Model 2 és una junta de sistemes d'arcades debutat originalment per SEGA el 1993 com a successor de la junta SEGA Model 1.És una extensió del maquinari Model 1, que introdueix sobretot el concepte de polígons basats en textures, que permeten gràfics 3D més realistes (per al seu temps). El Model 2 Board va ser una fita important per a la indústria de les arcades i va ajudar a llançar diverses franquícies d'arcades clau dels anys 90, incloses Daytona USA, Virtua Cop, Campionat de Rally Sega, Dead Or Alive, Virtua Striker, Cibers Topers Virtual-on i la casa i la casadels morts. El Model 2 va ser dissenyat amb l'ajuda de Ge Aerospace (adquirit per Martin Marietta el 1993, que ara forma part de Lockheed Martin), que va dissenyar la tecnologia de mapatge de textures incorporada pel model 2. El desenvolupament del model 2 va ser dirigit pel famós dissenyador de jocs Yu Suzuki. El Model 2 Arcade Board va debutar juntament amb Daytona USA, un joc que es va acabar, es va acabar amb copyright i va debutar al Jamma Arcade Show el 1993. Hi ha quatre versions del sistema: el Model 2 original i el Model 2A-CRX, Model 2B-CRX-CRXi variants del model 2C-CRX. El model 2 i 2A-CRX van utilitzar un DSP personalitzat amb codi intern per al geometritzador, mentre que 2B-CRX i 2C-CRX utilitzaven DSPs ben documentats i van penjar el codi de geometritzador en startup al DSP.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Arcade</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="de_DE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Das Sega Model 2 ist eine Spielhallen-Systemplatine, die 1993 von Sega als Nachfolger des Sega Model 1 vorgestellt wurde. Es ist eine Erweiterung der Modell 1-Hardware, vor allem die Einführung des Konzepts der texturierten Polygone, die eine realistischere 3D-Grafik (für die damalige Zeit) ermöglichte. Das Model 2 Board war ein wichtiger Meilenstein für die Arcade-Industrie und trug zum Start mehrerer wichtiger Arcade-Franchises der 90er Jahre bei, darunter Daytona USA, Virtua Cop, Sega Rally Championship, Dead or Alive, Virtua Striker, Cyber Troopers Virtual-On und The House of the Dead. Das Model 2 wurde mit Hilfe von GE Aerospace (1993 von Martin Marietta übernommen, heute Teil von Lockheed Martin) entwickelt, das die Texture-Mapping-Technologie für das Model 2 entworfen hat. Die Entwicklung des Modells 2 wurde von dem berühmten Spieldesigner Yu Suzuki geleitet. Das Arcade-Board des Modells 2 wurde zusammen mit Daytona USA vorgestellt, einem Spiel, das fertiggestellt und urheberrechtlich geschützt war und 1993 auf der JAMMA Arcade Show vorgestellt wurde. Es gab vier Versionen des Systems: das ursprüngliche Modell 2 und die Varianten Modell 2A-CRX, Modell 2B-CRX und Modell 2C-CRX. Modell 2 und 2A-CRX verwendeten einen benutzerdefinierten DSP mit internem Code für den Geometrizer, während 2B-CRX und 2C-CRX gut dokumentierte DSPs verwendeten und den Geometrizer-Code beim Starten in den DSP hochluden.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Spielhalle</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="es_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>La Sega Model 2 es una placa de sistema arcade originalmente debutada por Sega en 1993 como sucesora de la Sega Model 1. Se trata de una ampliación del hardware del Model 1, en la que destaca la introducción del concepto de polígonos mapeados con texturas, que permite gráficos 3D más realistas (para su época). La placa Model 2 fue un hito importante para la industria arcade y ayudó a lanzar varias franquicias arcade clave de los 90, como Daytona USA, Virtua Cop, Sega Rally Championship, Dead or Alive, Virtua Striker, Cyber Troopers Virtual-On y The House of the Dead. El Model 2 se diseñó con la ayuda de GE Aerospace (adquirida por Martin Marietta en 1993, ahora parte de Lockheed Martin), que diseñó la tecnología de mapeado de texturas que incorpora el Model 2. El desarrollo del Model 2 corrió a cargo del famoso diseñador de juegos Yu Suzuki. La placa arcade del Model 2 debutó junto con Daytona USA, un juego que se terminó, obtuvo los derechos de autor y debutó en la feria arcade JAMMA de 1993. Hubo cuatro versiones del sistema: el Modelo 2 original y las variantes Modelo 2A-CRX, Modelo 2B-CRX y Modelo 2C-CRX. El Modelo 2 y el 2A-CRX utilizaban un DSP personalizado con código interno para el geometrizador, mientras que el 2B-CRX y el 2C-CRX utilizaban DSP bien documentados y cargaban el código del geometrizador al arrancar en el DSP.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Arcade</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="fr_FR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Le Sega Model 2 est une carte de système d'arcade lancée par Sega en 1993 pour succéder à la carte Sega Model 1. Il s'agit d'une extension du matériel du modèle 1, qui introduit notamment le concept de polygones texturés, permettant des graphismes 3D plus réalistes (pour l'époque). La carte Model 2 a constitué une étape importante pour l'industrie de l'arcade et a contribué au lancement de plusieurs franchises d'arcade clés des années 90, notamment Daytona USA, Virtua Cop, Sega Rally Championship, Dead or Alive, Virtua Striker, Cyber Troopers Virtual-On et The House of the Dead. Le modèle 2 a été conçu avec l'aide de GE Aerospace (racheté par Martin Marietta en 1993, qui fait aujourd'hui partie de Lockheed Martin), qui a mis au point la technologie de cartographie des textures incorporée dans le modèle 2. Le développement de la Model 2 a été dirigé par le célèbre concepteur de jeux Yu Suzuki. La carte d'arcade Model 2 a été lancée en même temps que Daytona USA, un jeu qui a été terminé, protégé par des droits d'auteur et présenté pour la première fois au salon de l'arcade JAMMA en 1993. Il existe quatre versions du système : le Model 2 original et les variantes Model 2A-CRX, Model 2B-CRX et Model 2C-CRX. Les modèles 2 et 2A-CRX utilisaient un DSP personnalisé avec un code interne pour le geometrizer tandis que les modèles 2B-CRX et 2C-CRX utilisaient des DSP bien documentés et téléchargeaient le code du geometrizer au démarrage sur le DSP.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Arcade</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="hr_HR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>SEGA Model 2 je odbor arkadnog sustava koji je SEGA izvorno debitirala 1993. godine kao nasljednik ploče SEGA Model 1. To je produžetak hardvera Model 1, ponajviše uvodeći koncept poligona s teksturom, omogućavajući realnije 3D grafiku (za njegovo vrijeme). Odbor Model 2 bio je važna prekretnica za arkadnu industriju, a pomogla je pokrenuti nekoliko ključnih arkadnih franšiza 90-ih, uključujući Daytona USA, policajac Virtua, prvenstvo u SEGA Rally, mrtva ili živa, virtua, virtualni Cyber Troopers virtualno i kuću mrtvih. Model 2 je izrađen uz pomoć GE Aerospacea (kupio ga je Martin Marietta 1993. godine, koji je sada dio Lockheed Martin), koji je dizajnirao tehnologiju mapiranja teksture koju je ugradio model 2. Razvoj modela 2 vodio je poznati dizajner igara Yu Suzuki. Arcade Board Model 2 debitirao je zajedno s Daytonom USA, igrom koja je završena, zaštićena autorskim pravima i debitirala na sajmu Jamma Arcade 1993. godine. Postoje četiri verzije sustava: Originalni model 2 i model 2A-CRX, Model 2B-CRX i Model 2C-CRX varijante. Model 2 i 2A-CRX koristio je prilagođeni DSP s unutarnjim kodom za Geometrizer, dok je 2B-CRX i 2C-CRX koristili dobro dokumentirane DSP-ove i prenijeli kôd Geometrizer pri pokretanju u DSP.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Arkada</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="it_IT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Il Sega Model 2 è una scheda di sistema arcade originariamente presentata da Sega nel 1993 come successore della scheda Sega Model 1. Si tratta di un'estensione dell'hardware del Model 1, che introduce in particolare il concetto di poligoni mappati con texture, consentendo una grafica 3D più realistica (per l'epoca). La scheda Model 2 è stata un'importante pietra miliare per l'industria arcade e ha contribuito al lancio di diversi franchise arcade chiave degli anni '90, tra cui Daytona USA, Virtua Cop, Sega Rally Championship, Dead or Alive, Virtua Striker, Cyber Troopers Virtual-On e The House of the Dead. Il Model 2 è stato progettato con l'aiuto di GE Aerospace (acquisita da Martin Marietta nel 1993, ora parte di Lockheed Martin), che ha ideato la tecnologia di texture-mapping incorporata nel Model 2. Lo sviluppo del Model 2 è stato guidato dal famoso game designer Yu Suzuki. La scheda arcade del Model 2 debuttò insieme a Daytona USA, un gioco finito, protetto da copyright e presentato alla fiera arcade JAMMA nel 1993. Esistono quattro versioni del sistema: il Model 2 originale e le varianti Model 2A-CRX, Model 2B-CRX e Model 2C-CRX. Il Modello 2 e il Modello 2A-CRX utilizzavano un DSP personalizzato con codice interno per il geometrizzatore, mentre il Modello 2B-CRX e il Modello 2C-CRX utilizzavano DSP ben documentati e caricavano il codice del geometrizzatore all'avvio del DSP.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Arcade</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ja_JP">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>セガ・モデル2は、セガ・モデル1の後継機として1993年にセガからデビューしたアーケードシステム基板である。1型のハードウェアを拡張したもので、特にテクスチャマップポリゴンの概念を導入し、（当時としては）よりリアルな3Dグラフィックを可能にした。Model 2基板はアーケード業界にとって重要なマイルストーンであり、Daytona USA、Virtua Cop、Sega Rally Championship、Dead or Alive、Virtua Striker、Cyber Troopers Virtual-On、The House of the Deadなど、90年代の主要なアーケードフランチャイズの立ち上げに貢献した。Model 2は、GEエアロスペース（1993年にマーティン・マリエッタが買収、現在はロッキード・マーティンの傘下）の協力を得て設計され、Model 2で採用されたテクスチャマッピング技術を設計した。モデル2の開発は、有名なゲームデザイナーの鈴木裕氏が主導した。モデル2のアーケードボードは、1993年のJAMMAアーケードショーで完成し、版権を取得し、デビューしたゲーム「デイトナUSA」とともにデビューした。初代2型と2A-CRX型、2B-CRX型、2C-CRX型の4種類があった。モデル2と2A-CRXはジオメトライザー用の内部コードを持つカスタムDSPを使用し、2B-CRXと2C-CRXはよく文書化されたDSPを使用し、起動時にジオメトライザーのコードをDSPにアップロードした。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>アーケード</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ko_KR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>세가 모델 2는 1993년 세가에서 세가 모델 1 보드의 후속작으로 처음 선보인 아케이드 시스템 보드입니다. 모델 1 하드웨어의 확장판으로, 특히 텍스처 매핑 폴리곤 개념을 도입하여 당시로서는 더욱 사실적인 3D 그래픽을 구현할 수 있었습니다. 모델 2 보드는 아케이드 업계에 중요한 이정표가 되었으며, 90년대의 주요 아케이드 프랜차이즈인 데이토나 USA, 버추어 캅, 세가 랠리 챔피언십, 데드 오어 얼라이브, 버추어 스트라이커, 사이버 트루퍼스 가상 온, 더 하우스 오브 더 데드 등 여러 게임을 출시하는 데 기여했습니다. 모델 2에 적용된 텍스처 매핑 기술을 설계한 GE Aerospace(1993년 마틴 마리에타에 인수되어 현재 록히드 마틴의 일부가 됨)의 도움을 받아 모델 2를 설계했습니다. 모델 2의 개발은 유명한 게임 디자이너 스즈키 유가 주도했습니다. Model 2 아케이드 보드는 1993년 JAMMA 아케이드 쇼에서 완성되어 저작권을 획득하고 데뷔한 게임인 Daytona USA와 함께 데뷔했습니다. 이 시스템에는 오리지널 모델 2와 모델 2A-CRX, 모델 2B-CRX, 모델 2C-CRX 변형 등 네 가지 버전이 있습니다. 모델 2와 2A-CRX는 지오메트리저용 내부 코드가 포함된 맞춤형 DSP를 사용했고, 2B-CRX와 2C-CRX는 잘 문서화된 DSP를 사용했으며 시작 시 지오메트리저 코드를 DSP에 업로드했습니다.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>아케이드</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="nl_NL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Het Sega Model 2 is een arcadesysteembord dat oorspronkelijk door Sega werd uitgebracht in 1993 als opvolger van het Sega Model 1-bord. Het is een uitbreiding van de Model 1 hardware, met name de introductie van het concept van texture-mapped polygonen, waardoor realistischere 3D-graphics mogelijk werden (voor die tijd). Het Model 2-bord was een belangrijke mijlpaal voor de arcade-industrie en hielp bij de lancering van verschillende belangrijke arcadefranchises in de jaren 90, waaronder Daytona USA, Virtua Cop, Sega Rally Championship, Dead or Alive, Virtua Striker, Cyber Troopers Virtual-On en The House of the Dead. De Model 2 werd ontwikkeld met hulp van GE Aerospace (overgenomen door Martin Marietta in 1993, nu onderdeel van Lockheed Martin), die de texture-mapping technologie in de Model 2 ontwierp. De ontwikkeling van Model 2 werd geleid door de beroemde game ontwerper Yu Suzuki. Het Model 2 arcade bord debuteerde samen met Daytona USA, een spel dat was voltooid, auteursrechtelijk beschermd en debuteerde op de JAMMA arcade show in 1993. Er waren vier versies van het systeem: het originele Model 2 en de Model 2A-CRX, Model 2B-CRX en Model 2C-CRX varianten. Model 2 en 2A-CRX gebruikten een eigen DSP met interne code voor de geometrizer, terwijl 2B-CRX en 2C-CRX goed gedocumenteerde DSP's gebruikten en de geometrizercode bij het opstarten uploadden naar de DSP.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Arcade</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pl_PL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Sega Model 2 to zręcznościowa konsola systemowa zadebiutowana przez firmę Sega w 1993 roku jako następca konsoli Sega Model 1. Jest to rozszerzenie sprzętu Model 1, w szczególności wprowadzające koncepcję wielokątów mapowanych teksturami, pozwalając na bardziej realistyczną grafikę 3D (jak na swoje czasy). Płyta Model 2 była kamieniem milowym dla branży gier arcade i pomogła w uruchomieniu kilku kluczowych serii gier arcade w latach 90-tych, w tym Daytona USA, Virtua Cop, Sega Rally Championship, Dead or Alive, Virtua Striker, Cyber Troopers Virtual-On i The House of the Dead. Model 2 został opracowany z pomocą firmy GE Aerospace (przejętej przez Martin Marietta w 1993 roku, obecnie część Lockheed Martin), która zaprojektowała technologię mapowania tekstur zastosowaną w Modelu 2. Rozwój Modelu 2 był prowadzony przez słynnego projektanta gier Yu Suzuki. Płytka zręcznościowa Model 2 zadebiutowała wraz z grą Daytona USA, która została ukończona, objęta prawami autorskimi i zadebiutowała na pokazie gier zręcznościowych JAMMA w 1993 roku. Istniały cztery wersje systemu: oryginalny Model 2 oraz warianty Model 2A-CRX, Model 2B-CRX i Model 2C-CRX. Modele 2 i 2A-CRX korzystały z niestandardowego procesora DSP z wewnętrznym kodem geometryzatora, podczas gdy 2B-CRX i 2C-CRX korzystały z dobrze udokumentowanych procesorów DSP i przesyłały kod geometryzatora podczas uruchamiania do procesora DSP.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Arcade</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_BR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O Sega Model 2 é uma placa de sistema de arcade originalmente lançada pela Sega em 1993 como sucessora da placa Sega Model 1. Ela é uma extensão do hardware do Modelo 1, introduzindo principalmente o conceito de polígonos mapeados por textura, permitindo gráficos 3D mais realistas (para a época). A placa Model 2 foi um marco importante para a indústria de fliperama e ajudou a lançar várias franquias importantes de fliperama dos anos 90, incluindo Daytona USA, Virtua Cop, Sega Rally Championship, Dead or Alive, Virtua Striker, Cyber Troopers Virtual-On e The House of the Dead. O Model 2 foi projetado com a ajuda da GE Aerospace (adquirida pela Martin Marietta em 1993, hoje parte da Lockheed Martin), que projetou a tecnologia de mapeamento de textura incorporada ao Model 2. O desenvolvimento do Model 2 foi liderado pelo famoso designer de jogos Yu Suzuki. A placa de fliperama Model 2 foi lançada junto com Daytona USA, um jogo que foi finalizado, protegido por direitos autorais e lançado na feira de fliperama JAMMA em 1993. Existem quatro versões do sistema: o Modelo 2 original e as variantes Modelo 2A-CRX, Modelo 2B-CRX e Modelo 2C-CRX. O Modelo 2 e o 2A-CRX usavam um DSP personalizado com código interno para o geometrizador, enquanto o 2B-CRX e o 2C-CRX usavam DSPs bem documentados e carregavam o código do geometrizador na inicialização para o DSP.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Fliperama</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_PT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O Sega Model 2 é uma placa do sistema de arcade originalmente estreou pela SEGA em 1993 como sucessor da placa Modelo 1 da SEGA.É uma extensão do hardware do Modelo 1, apresentando principalmente o conceito de polígonos mapeados de textura, permitindo gráficos 3D mais realistas (para o seu tempo). O Conselho do Modelo 2 era um marco importante para a indústria de arcade e ajudou a lançar várias franquias importantes dos anos 90, incluindo Daytona USA, Virtua Cop, Sega Rally Championship, Dead ou Alive, Virtua Striker, Cyber Troopers Virtual-on e The House of the Dead. O Modelo 2 foi projetado com a ajuda da GE Aerospace (adquirida por Martin Marietta em 1993, agora parte de Lockheed Martin), que projetou a tecnologia de mapeamento de textura incorporada pelo Modelo 2. O desenvolvimento do Modelo 2 foi liderado pelo famoso designer de jogos Yu Suzuki. O Modelo 2 Arcade Board estreou junto com Daytona USA, um jogo que foi concluído, protegido por direitos autorais e estreou no Jamma Arcade Show em 1993. Existem quatro versões do sistema: as variantes Modelo 2 e Modelo 2A-CRX, Modelo 2B-CRX e Modelo 2C-CRX. O Modelo 2 e 2A-CRX usaram um DSP personalizado com código interno para o geometriz, enquanto o 2B-CRX e 2C-CRX usou DSPs bem documentados e enviou o código do geometriz na inicialização do DSP.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Arcade</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ro_RO">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Sega Model 2 este o placă de sistem arcade debutat inițial de Sega în 1993 ca succesor al plăcii Sega Model 1. Este o extensie a hardware-ului Model 1, cel mai notabil introducând conceptul de poligoane cu textură, permițând o grafică 3D mai realistă (pentru vremea sa). Placa Model 2 a fost o piatră de hotar importantă pentru industria de arcade și a contribuit la lansarea mai multor francize arcade cheie ale anilor '90, inclusiv Daytona USA, Virtua Cop, Sega Rally Championship, Dead or Alive, Virtua Striker, Cyber Troopers Virtual-On și The House of the Dead. Modelul 2 a fost proiectat cu ajutorul GE Aerospace (achiziționat de Martin Marietta în 1993, în prezent parte a Lockheed Martin), care a proiectat tehnologia de mapare a texturilor încorporată de Modelul 2. Dezvoltarea Modelului 2 a fost condusă de celebrul designer de jocuri Yu Suzuki. Placa arcade Model 2 a debutat împreună cu Daytona USA, un joc care a fost finalizat, protejat prin drepturi de autor și a debutat la expoziția arcade JAMMA din 1993. Au existat patru versiuni ale sistemului: Modelul 2 original și variantele Model 2A-CRX, Model 2B-CRX și Model 2C-CRX. Modelul 2 și 2A-CRX foloseau un DSP personalizat cu cod intern pentru geometrizer, în timp ce 2B-CRX și 2C-CRX foloseau DSP-uri bine documentate și încărcau codul geometrizerului la pornire în DSP.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Arcade</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ru_RU">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Sega Model 2 - это системная плата для аркадных игр, дебютировавшая в 1993 году в качестве преемника платы Sega Model 1. Она стала продолжением аппаратной части Model 1, в частности, ввела концепцию текстурирования полигонов, что позволило создать более реалистичную 3D-графику (для своего времени). Плата Model 2 стала важной вехой для аркадной индустрии и помогла запустить несколько ключевых аркадных франшиз 90-х годов, включая Daytona USA, Virtua Cop, Sega Rally Championship, Dead or Alive, Virtua Striker, Cyber Troopers Virtual-On и The House of the Dead. В разработке Model 2 принимала участие компания GE Aerospace (приобретенная Martin Marietta в 1993 году, ныне часть Lockheed Martin), которая разработала технологию текстурирования, использованную в Model 2. Разработкой Model 2 руководил известный игровой дизайнер Ю Судзуки. Дебют аркадной платы Model 2 состоялся вместе с игрой Daytona USA, которая была закончена, защищена авторскими правами и дебютировала на выставке аркадных игр JAMMA в 1993 году. Существует четыре версии системы: оригинальная Model 2 и варианты Model 2A-CRX, Model 2B-CRX и Model 2C-CRX. Модели 2 и 2A-CRX использовали пользовательский DSP с внутренним кодом для геометризатора, в то время как 2B-CRX и 2C-CRX использовали хорошо документированные DSP и загружали код геометризатора при запуске в DSP.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Аркада</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sr_RS">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Сега Модел 2 је одбор за аркадну системску матичну плочу, првобитно дебитовао Сега 1993. године као наследник одбора Сега Модел 1.То је проширење хардвера модела 1, што најпознатије представља концепт полигона који пресликани текстуре, омогућавајући реалистичнију 3Д графику (за своје време).Модел 2 одбор био је важан прекретница за аркадну индустрију и помогла је да покрене неколико кључних аркадских франшиза од 90-их, укључујући Даитона УСА, Виртуа ЦОП, Сега Ралли Цхампионсхип, мртву или живу нападачу Виртуа, Виртуа нападача, виртуари виртуари виртуални и кућу мртвих.Модел 2 је инседиран уз помоћ ГЕ Аероспаце-а (стекао Мартин Мариетта 1993. године, сада је део Лоцкхеед Мартин), који је дизајнирао технологију мапирања текстуре уграђеног моделом 2. Развој 2. Дизајн 2. Дизајнер 2.Модел 2 Аркадна плоча је дебитовала заједно са Даитона УСА, игром која је била завршена, заштићена ауторским правима и дебитовао на Јамма Арцаде Схов 1993. Постоје четири верзије система: оригинал 2 и модел 2А-ЦРКС, модел 2Б-ЦРКС и модел 2Ц-ЦРКС варијанте 2Ц-ЦРКС.Модел 2 и 2А-ЦРКС користио је прилагођени ДСП са унутрашњим кодом за геометризер док је 2Б-ЦРКС и 2Ц-ЦРКС користио добро документоване ДСПС и пренесен је код геометризатора при покретању у ДСП.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Аркада</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sv_SE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Sega Model 2 är ett arkadsystemkort som ursprungligen lanserades av Sega 1993 som en efterföljare till Sega Model 1-kortet. Det är en förlängning av Model 1-hårdvaran och introducerade framför allt konceptet med texturmappade polygoner, vilket möjliggjorde mer realistisk 3D-grafik (för sin tid). Model 2-kortet var en viktig milstolpe för arkadindustrin och hjälpte till att lansera flera viktiga arkadserier på 90-talet, bland annat Daytona USA, Virtua Cop, Sega Rally Championship, Dead or Alive, Virtua Striker, Cyber Troopers Virtual-On och The House of the Dead. Model 2 konstruerades med hjälp av GE Aerospace (som 1993 förvärvades av Martin Marietta, numera en del av Lockheed Martin), som utformade den texturmappningsteknik som Model 2 bygger på. Utvecklingen av Model 2 leddes av den berömde speldesignern Yu Suzuki. Model 2 arkadkort debuterade tillsammans med Daytona USA, ett spel som var färdigt, upphovsrättsskyddat och debuterade på arkadmässan JAMMA 1993. Det fanns fyra versioner av systemet: den ursprungliga Model 2 och varianterna Model 2A-CRX, Model 2B-CRX och Model 2C-CRX. Model 2 och 2A-CRX använde en egen DSP med intern kod för geometrizer medan 2B-CRX och 2C-CRX använde väldokumenterade DSP:er och laddade upp geometrizerkoden vid start till DSP:en.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Arkad</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_CN">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>世嘉 Model 2 是世嘉公司于 1993 年首次推出的一款街机系统板卡，是世嘉 Model 1 板卡的后续产品。它是 Model 1 硬件的延伸，最显著的特点是引入了纹理映射多边形的概念，使 3D 图形更加逼真（在当时）。Model 2 游戏板是街机行业的一个重要里程碑，帮助推出了 90 年代的几款重要街机特许经营产品，包括《美国代托纳》、《Virtua Cop》、《世嘉拉力锦标赛》、《死或生》、《Virtua Striker》、《虚拟网络部队》和《死亡之屋》。Model 2 的设计得到了通用电气航空航天公司（1993 年被马丁-玛丽埃塔公司收购，现为洛克希德-马丁公司的一部分）的帮助，该公司设计了 Model 2 所采用的纹理映射技术。Model 2 的开发由著名游戏设计师铃木裕领导。Model 2 街机板与《美国代托纳》（Daytona USA）一起首次亮相，该游戏已完成并获得版权，于 1993 年在 JAMMA 街机展上首次亮相。该系统有四个版本：原始的 Model 2 以及 Model 2A-CRX、Model 2B-CRX 和 Model 2C-CRX 变体。2 型和 2A-CRX 使用的是定制的 DSP，带有几何裁剪器的内部代码，而 2B-CRX 和 2C-CRX 使用的是有据可查的 DSP，并在启动时将几何裁剪器代码上传到 DSP。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>商场</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_TW">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Sega Model 2 是 Sega 於 1993 年推出的一款街機系統主機板，是 Sega Model 1 主機板的後繼機種。它是 Model 1 硬體的延伸，最顯著的是引入了紋理映射多邊形的概念，讓 3D 圖形更逼真（在當時而言）。Model 2 遊戲板是街機產業的重要里程碑，並協助推出 90 年代數款重要的街機遊戲，包括《Daytona USA》、《Virtua Cop》、《Sega Rally Championship》、《Dead or Alive》、《Virtua Striker》、《Cyber Troopers Virtual-On》和《The House of the Dead》。Model 2 的設計得到 GE Aerospace (1993 年被 Martin Marietta 收購，現為 Lockheed Martin 的一部份) 的協助，他們設計了 Model 2 所採用的紋理貼圖技術。Model 2 的開發由著名遊戲設計師 Yu Suzuki 領導。Model 2 街機板與 Daytona USA 一同亮相，該遊戲已完成並取得版權，並於 1993 年的 JAMMA 街機展上首次亮相。該系統共有四個版本：原始的 Model 2 以及 Model 2A-CRX、Model 2B-CRX 和 Model 2C-CRX 變體。Model 2 和 2A-CRX 使用自訂的 DSP，並內含幾何分解器的程式碼，而 2B-CRX 和 2C-CRX 則使用記錄完整的 DSP，並在啟動時將幾何分解器程式碼上傳至 DSP。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>街機</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
</theme>
