<theme>
    <variables>
        <systemName>Thomson MOTO</systemName>
        <systemDescription>The Thomson MOTO line of computers were a series of 8-bit computers sold in the 1980s by French electronics company Thomson, which has been nationalized in 1982. The MOTO computers became an integral part of the French Government's plan informatique pour tous (IPT) to make computers widespread throughout France by bringing computers and programming classes to French school children. A number of computer makers, including Apple, were considered before Thomson won the contract.</systemDescription>
        <systemManufacturer>Thomson SA</systemManufacturer>
        <systemReleaseYear>1984</systemReleaseYear>
        <systemReleaseDate>1984</systemReleaseDate>
        <systemReleaseDateFormated>1984</systemReleaseDateFormated>
        <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        <systemCoverSize>3-4</systemCoverSize>
        <systemCoverSizeType>portrait</systemCoverSizeType>
        <systemColor>2a539c</systemColor>
        <systemColorPalette1>E6F0EF</systemColorPalette1>
        <systemColorPalette2>F0C73B</systemColorPalette2>
        <systemColorPalette3>4F8E5C</systemColorPalette3>
        <systemColorPalette4>2C2D2C</systemColorPalette4>
        <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
    </variables>
    <language name="ar_SA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>كانت مجموعة حواسيب Thomson MOTO عبارة عن سلسلة من الحواسيب ذات 8 بت التي تم بيعها في الثمانينيات من قبل شركة الإلكترونيات الفرنسية Thomson، التي تم تأميمها في عام 1982. أصبحت حواسيب MOTO جزءًا لا يتجزأ من خطة الحكومة الفرنسية "معلوماتية للجميع" (IPT) لجعل الحواسيب منتشرة في جميع أنحاء فرنسا من خلال توفير أجهزة الكمبيوتر ودروس البرمجة لأطفال المدارس الفرنسية. تم النظر في عدد من صانعي الحواسيب، بما في ذلك شركة Apple، قبل أن تفوز Thomson بالعقد.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>الحاسب الآلي</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="bs_BA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Thomson Moto linija računara bila je serija 8-bitnih računara prodanih u 1980-ima francuske elektroničke kompanije Thomson, koje je ugrađeno 1982.. Brojni računarski proizvođači, uključujući jabuku, razmatrani su prije nego što je Thomson pobijedio u ugovoru.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Računar</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ca_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>La línia d'ordinadors Thomson Moto va ser una sèrie d'ordinadors de 8 bits venuts a la dècada de 1980 per la companyia d'electrònica francesa Thomson, que ha estat nacionalitzada el 1982. Els ordinadors de Moto es van convertir en part integrant del pla del govern francès Informatique Pour Tous (IPT) per aFeu que els ordinadors siguin generalitzats a tota França, portant ordinadors i classes de programació als escolars francesos. Alguns fabricants informàtics, inclòs Apple, es van considerar abans que Thomson guanyés el contracte.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="de_DE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Die Thomson MOTO-Reihe war eine Serie von 8-Bit-Computern, die in den 1980er Jahren vom französischen Elektronikunternehmen Thomson verkauft wurden, das 1982 verstaatlicht wurde. Die MOTO-Computer wurden zu einem integralen Bestandteil des Plans "Informatique pour tous" (IPT) der französischen Regierung, der darauf abzielte, Computer in ganz Frankreich zu verbreiten, indem den französischen Schulkindern Computer und Programmierunterricht angeboten wurden. Eine Reihe von Computerherstellern, darunter Apple, wurden in Betracht gezogen, bevor Thomson den Zuschlag erhielt.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="es_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>La línea de ordenadores Thomson MOTO fue una serie de ordenadores de 8 bits vendidos en los años 80 por la empresa francesa de electrónica Thomson, nacionalizada en 1982. Los ordenadores MOTO se convirtieron en parte integrante del plan del Gobierno francés "informatique pour tous" (IPT) para generalizar el uso de ordenadores en toda Francia, llevando ordenadores y clases de programación a los escolares franceses. Varios fabricantes de ordenadores, entre ellos Apple, fueron considerados antes de que Thomson obtuviera el contrato.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Ordenador</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="fr_FR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>La gamme d'ordinateurs Thomson MOTO était une série d'ordinateurs 8 bits vendus dans les années 1980 par la société française d'électronique Thomson, qui a été nationalisée en 1982. Les ordinateurs MOTO ont fait partie intégrante du plan informatique pour tous (IPT) du gouvernement français, qui visait à généraliser les ordinateurs dans toute la France en offrant des ordinateurs et des cours de programmation aux écoliers français. Plusieurs fabricants d'ordinateurs, dont Apple, ont été envisagés avant que Thomson ne remporte le contrat.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Ordinateur</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="hr_HR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Thomson Moto linija računala bila je serija 8-bitnih računala koja je 1980-ih prodala francuska kompanija za elektroniku Thomson, koja je nacionalizirana 1982. godine. Moto računala postala su sastavni dio plana francuske vlade Informatique Pour Tous (IPT) kako bi računala širila u cijeloj Francuskoj i programirajućim razredima u francusku djecu. Brojni proizvođači računala, uključujući Apple, razmatrani su prije nego što je Thomson pobijedio u ugovoru.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Računalo</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="it_IT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>La linea di computer Thomson MOTO era una serie di computer a 8 bit venduti negli anni '80 dall'azienda elettronica francese Thomson, nazionalizzata nel 1982. I computer MOTO divennero parte integrante del piano informatique pour tous (IPT) del governo francese, che mirava a diffondere i computer in tutta la Francia portando computer e corsi di programmazione ai bambini delle scuole francesi. Prima che Thomson si aggiudicasse il contratto sono stati presi in considerazione diversi produttori di computer, tra cui Apple.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ja_JP">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>トムソンMOTOシリーズは、1982年に国有化されたフランスのエレクトロニクス企業トムソンが1980年代に販売した8ビットコンピュータのシリーズである。MOTOコンピュータは、フランスの小学生にコンピュータとプログラミングの授業を提供することによって、フランス全土にコンピュータを普及させるというフランス政府の「Informatique pour tous（IPT）」計画の不可欠な一部となった。トムソンが契約を勝ち取るまでには、アップルを含む多くのコンピューター・メーカーが検討された。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>コンピューター</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ko_KR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>톰슨 모토 컴퓨터는 프랑스 전자 회사 톰슨이 1980년대에 판매한 8비트 컴퓨터 시리즈로, 1982년 국유화되었습니다. MOTO 컴퓨터는 프랑스 정부가 프랑스 학교에 컴퓨터와 프로그래밍 수업을 도입하여 프랑스 전역에 컴퓨터를 보급하기 위한 IPT(Plan Informatique pour tous)의 필수적인 부분이 되었습니다. 톰슨이 계약을 따내기 전에는 Apple을 비롯한 여러 컴퓨터 제조업체가 고려되었습니다.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>컴퓨터</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="nl_NL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>De Thomson MOTO-lijn van computers was een serie 8-bit computers die in de jaren 1980 werd verkocht door het Franse elektronicabedrijf Thomson, dat in 1982 werd genationaliseerd. De MOTO-computers werden een integraal onderdeel van het plan informatique pour tous (IPT) van de Franse regering om computers in heel Frankrijk te verspreiden door Franse schoolkinderen computers en programmeerlessen te geven. Een aantal computerfabrikanten, waaronder Apple, werden overwogen voordat Thomson het contract in de wacht sleepte.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pl_PL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Linia komputerów Thomson MOTO była serią 8-bitowych komputerów sprzedawanych w latach 80. przez francuską firmę elektroniczną Thomson, która została znacjonalizowana w 1982 roku. Komputery MOTO stały się integralną częścią francuskiego rządowego planu informatique pour tous (IPT), mającego na celu rozpowszechnienie komputerów w całej Francji poprzez wprowadzenie komputerów i lekcji programowania dla francuskich dzieci w wieku szkolnym. Wielu producentów komputerów, w tym Apple, było branych pod uwagę, zanim Thomson wygrał kontrakt.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Komputer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_BR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>A linha de computadores Thomson MOTO era uma série de computadores de 8 bits vendidos na década de 1980 pela empresa francesa de eletrônicos Thomson, que foi nacionalizada em 1982. Os computadores MOTO tornaram-se parte integrante do plano informatique pour tous (IPT) do governo francês para difundir os computadores em toda a França, levando computadores e aulas de programação às crianças das escolas francesas. Vários fabricantes de computadores, incluindo a Apple, foram considerados antes de a Thomson ganhar o contrato.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computador</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_PT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>A Thomson Moto Line of Computers era uma série de computadores de 8 bits vendidos na década de 1980 pela empresa de eletrônicos franceses Thomson, que foi nacionalizada em 1982. Os Moto Computers se tornaram parte integrante do plano do governo francês, que é um dos computadores do governo francês, trazendo computadores e classes de fãs para os computadores. Vários fabricantes de computadores, incluindo a Apple, foram considerados antes de Thomson vencer o contrato.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computador</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ro_RO">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Linia de calculatoare Thomson MOTO a fost o serie de calculatoare pe 8 biți vândute în anii 1980 de compania franceză de electronice Thomson, care a fost naționalizată în 1982. Computerele MOTO au devenit parte integrantă a planului guvernului francez "informatique pour tous" (IPT) de răspândire a computerelor în toată Franța prin oferirea de computere și cursuri de programare elevilor francezi. O serie de producători de calculatoare, inclusiv Apple, au fost luați în considerare înainte ca Thomson să câștige contractul.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ru_RU">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Линейка компьютеров Thomson MOTO - это серия 8-битных компьютеров, продававшихся в 1980-х годах французской компанией Thomson, которая была национализирована в 1982 году. Компьютеры MOTO стали неотъемлемой частью плана французского правительства "Информатика для всех" (IPT), направленного на повсеместное распространение компьютеров во Франции путем предоставления компьютеров и уроков программирования французским школьникам. Прежде чем Thomson выиграла контракт, рассматривались кандидатуры нескольких производителей компьютеров, включая Apple.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Компьютер</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sr_RS">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>ТХОМСОН МОТО ЛИНЕ ЦОМПУТЕРС-а био је серија од 8-битних рачунара које је продато француском компанијом Елецтроницс Тхомсон, која је национализована 1982. године. Мото рачунари су постали саставни део Француске владе План Информатикуе да се рачунари шире у Француску и програмирајуће класе.Бројни произвођачи рачунара, укључујући Аппле, размотрени су пре него што је Тхомсон освојио уговор.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Рачунар</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sv_SE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Thomson MOTO-serien var en serie 8-bitarsdatorer som såldes under 1980-talet av det franska elektronikföretaget Thomson, som förstatligades 1982. MOTO-datorerna blev en integrerad del av den franska regeringens plan informatique pour tous (IPT) för att sprida datorer i hela Frankrike genom att ge franska skolbarn tillgång till datorer och programmeringskurser. Ett antal datortillverkare, inklusive Apple, övervägdes innan Thomson vann kontraktet.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Dator</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_CN">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>汤姆逊 MOTO 系列计算机是法国电子公司汤姆逊在 20 世纪 80 年代销售的一系列 8 位计算机，该公司已于 1982 年国有化。MOTO 电脑是法国政府 "全民信息化计划"（IPT）的重要组成部分，该计划旨在通过为法国中小学生提供电脑和编程课程，使电脑在全法国得到普及。在汤姆逊赢得合同之前，包括苹果公司在内的许多计算机制造商都曾被考虑过。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>计算机</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_TW">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Thomson MOTO 系列電腦是法國電子公司 Thomson 在 1980 年代銷售的一系列 8 位元電腦，該公司已於 1982 年收歸國有。MOTO 電腦成為法國政府「全民資訊化計劃」（informatique pour tous，簡稱 IPT）不可或缺的一部份，該計劃旨在透過為法國學童提供電腦和程式設計課程，讓電腦在全法普及。在 Thomson 贏得合約之前，包括 Apple 在內的許多電腦製造商都曾被考慮過。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>電腦</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
</theme>
