<theme>
    <variables>
        <systemName>Oric</systemName>
        <systemDescription>Oric was the name used by UK-based Tangerine Computer Systems for a series of 6502-based home computers sold in the 1980s, primarily in Europe. With the success of the ZX Spectrum from Sinclair Research, Tangerine's backers suggested a home computer and Tangerine formed Oric Products International Ltd to develop the Oric-1. The computer was introduced in 1982.[5] During 1983, approximately 160,000 Oric-1 computers were sold in the UK, plus another 50,000 in France (where it was the year's top-selling machine). This resulted in Oric being acquired and given funding for a successor model, the 1984 Oric Atmos.</systemDescription>
        <systemManufacturer>Tangerine</systemManufacturer>
        <systemReleaseYear>1982</systemReleaseYear>
        <systemReleaseDate>1982-09-01</systemReleaseDate>
        <systemReleaseDateFormated>September 1, 1982</systemReleaseDateFormated>
        <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        <systemCoverSize>3-4</systemCoverSize>
        <systemCoverSizeType>portrait</systemCoverSizeType>
        <systemColor>7C848D</systemColor>
        <systemColorPalette1>BFB8A8</systemColorPalette1>
        <systemColorPalette2>207EA4</systemColorPalette2>
        <systemColorPalette3>77776D</systemColorPalette3>
        <systemColorPalette4>9E9C8F</systemColorPalette4>
        <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
    </variables>
    <language name="ar_SA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>كان Oric هو الاسم الذي استخدمته شركة Tangerine Computer Systems ومقرها المملكة المتحدة لسلسلة من الحواسيب المنزلية التي تعتمد على 6502 والتي بيعت في الثمانينيات، في أوروبا بشكل أساسي. مع نجاح ZX Spectrum ZX Spectrum من Sinclair Research، اقترح داعمو Tangerine جهاز كمبيوتر منزلي وشكلت Tangerine شركة Oric Products International Ltd لتطوير Oric-1. طُرح الحاسوب في عام 1982.[5] وخلال عام 1983، تم بيع ما يقرب من 160,000 جهاز كمبيوتر Oric-1 في المملكة المتحدة، بالإضافة إلى 50,000 جهاز آخر في فرنسا (حيث كان الجهاز الأكثر مبيعًا في العام). وقد أدى ذلك إلى الاستحواذ على Oric وتمويل الطراز الذي سيخلفه وهو Oric Atmos لعام 1984.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>الحاسب الآلي</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="bs_BA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Orić je bilo ime koje koristi u Velikoj Britaniji mandarinski računarski sustavi za seriju od 6502 kućnih računara koji se prodaju u 1980-ima, prije svega u Europi. S uspjehom ZX spektra iz istraživanja Sinclair, bacširi za mandarine sugerirali su kućni računar i mandarine formirani Oric proizvodi International Ltd za razvoj Orića-1. Računar je predstavljen 1982. [5]Tokom 1983. godine u Velikoj Britaniji prodano je oko 160.000 računara ORIC-1, plus još 50.000 u Francuskoj (gdje je to bila najveća prodajna mašina). To je rezultiralo stečenim ORIC-om i davanje sredstava za model nasljednika, atmosferu 1984. godine.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Računar</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ca_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>ORIC era el nom que utilitzaven els sistemes informàtics de mandarina basats en el Regne Unit per a una sèrie d’ordinadors domèstics basats en 6502 venuts a la dècada de 1980, principalment a Europa. Amb l’èxit de l’espectre ZX de Sinclair Research, els patrocinadors de Tangerine van suggerir un ordinador domèstic i la mandarina va formar Oric Products International Ltd per desenvolupar l’ORIC-1. L’ordinador es va introduir el 1982. [5]Durant el 1983, es van vendre aproximadament 160.000 ordinadors ORIC-1 al Regne Unit, a més de 50.000 altres a França (on era la màquina més venuda de l'any). Això va donar lloc a que ORIC fos adquirit i donat finançament per a un model successor, els ARIC Atmos de 1984.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="de_DE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Oric war der Name, den das britische Unternehmen Tangerine Computer Systems für eine Reihe von 6502-basierten Heimcomputern verwendete, die in den 1980er Jahren hauptsächlich in Europa verkauft wurden. Nach dem Erfolg des ZX Spectrum von Sinclair Research schlugen die Geldgeber von Tangerine einen Heimcomputer vor, und Tangerine gründete Oric Products International Ltd, um den Oric-1 zu entwickeln. Der Computer wurde 1982 auf den Markt gebracht.[5] Im Laufe des Jahres 1983 wurden etwa 160.000 Oric-1-Computer im Vereinigten Königreich verkauft, plus weitere 50.000 in Frankreich (wo er der meistverkaufte Computer des Jahres war). Dies führte dazu, dass Oric aufgekauft wurde und die Finanzierung für ein Nachfolgemodell, den Oric Atmos von 1984, erhielt.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="es_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Oric fue el nombre utilizado por Tangerine Computer Systems, con sede en el Reino Unido, para una serie de ordenadores domésticos basados en 6502 que se vendieron en la década de 1980, principalmente en Europa. Con el éxito del ZX Spectrum de Sinclair Research, los patrocinadores de Tangerine sugirieron un ordenador doméstico y Tangerine formó Oric Products International Ltd para desarrollar el Oric-1. El ordenador se presentó en 1982[5]. Durante 1983, se vendieron aproximadamente 160.000 ordenadores Oric-1 en el Reino Unido y otros 50.000 en Francia (donde fue la máquina más vendida del año). El resultado fue la adquisición de Oric y la financiación de un modelo sucesor, el Oric Atmos de 1984.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Ordenador</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="fr_FR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Oric est le nom utilisé par la société britannique Tangerine Computer Systems pour une série d'ordinateurs familiaux à base de 6502 vendus dans les années 1980, principalement en Europe. Avec le succès du ZX Spectrum de Sinclair Research, les bailleurs de fonds de Tangerine ont suggéré un ordinateur domestique et Tangerine a formé Oric Products International Ltd pour développer l'Oric-1, qui a été introduit en 1982[5]. L'ordinateur a été lancé en 1982[5] En 1983, environ 160 000 ordinateurs Oric-1 ont été vendus au Royaume-Uni, plus 50 000 en France (où il a été la machine la plus vendue de l'année). Oric a donc été racheté et a reçu des fonds pour la création d'un nouveau modèle, l'Oric Atmos, en 1984.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Ordinateur</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="hr_HR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>ORIC je ime bio naziv koji koristi Computer Systems sa sjedištem u Velikoj Britaniji za seriju od 6502 kućnih računala koji se prodaju u 1980-ima, prvenstveno u Europi. S uspjehom ZX spektra iz Sinclair Research-a, Tangerineovi su podupirači predložili kućno računalo i mandarinu formirane ORIC Products International Ltd kako bi razvili ORIC-1. Računalo je predstavljeno 1982. [5]Tijekom 1983. godine u Velikoj Britaniji je prodano oko 160 000 ORIC-1 računala, plus još 50 000 u Francuskoj (gdje je to bio najprodavaniji stroj godine). To je rezultiralo stečenim i dobivanjem OriC -a za model nasljednika, Oric Atmos iz 1984. godine.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Računalo</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="it_IT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Oric è il nome utilizzato da Tangerine Computer Systems, società con sede nel Regno Unito, per una serie di home computer basati su 6502 venduti negli anni '80, principalmente in Europa. Con il successo dello ZX Spectrum di Sinclair Research, i finanziatori di Tangerine suggerirono un home computer e Tangerine formò Oric Products International Ltd per sviluppare l'Oric-1. Il computer fu presentato nel 1982. Il computer fu presentato nel 1982.[5] Nel corso del 1983 furono venduti circa 160.000 computer Oric-1 nel Regno Unito, più altri 50.000 in Francia (dove fu la macchina più venduta dell'anno). Questo ha portato all'acquisizione di Oric e al finanziamento di un modello successivo, l'Oric Atmos del 1984.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ja_JP">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Oricは、イギリスのTangerine Computer Systemsが1980年代に主にヨーロッパで販売した6502ベースの家庭用コンピュータのシリーズに使用した名前である。シンクレア・リサーチのZXスペクトラムの成功に伴い、タンジェリンの後援者は家庭用コンピュータを提案し、タンジェリンはOric-1を開発するためにOric Products International Ltdを設立した。このコンピュータは1982年に発売され[5]、1983年にはイギリスで約160,000台のOric-1コンピュータが販売され、フランスでも50,000台が販売された（フランスではこの年のトップセラーとなった）。この結果、Oricは買収され、後継モデルである1984年版Oric Atmosのための資金を得ることになった。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>コンピューター</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ko_KR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Oric은 1980년대에 주로 유럽에서 판매된 6502 기반 가정용 컴퓨터 시리즈에 영국에 본사를 둔 Tangerine Computer Systems가 사용한 이름입니다. 싱클레어 리서치의 ZX 스펙트럼이 성공하자 탠저린의 후원자들은 가정용 컴퓨터를 제안했고, 탠저린은 Oric Products International Ltd를 설립하여 Oric-1을 개발했습니다. 이 컴퓨터는 1982년에 출시되었습니다.[5] 1983년에 영국에서 약 16만 대, 프랑스에서 5만 대(그 해 가장 많이 팔린 컴퓨터)의 Oric-1 컴퓨터가 판매되었습니다. 이로 인해 Oric은 인수되었고 후속 모델인 1984년형 Oric Atmos를 위한 자금을 지원받게 되었습니다.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>컴퓨터</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="nl_NL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Oric was de naam die het Britse Tangerine Computer Systems gebruikte voor een serie 6502-gebaseerde thuiscomputers die in de jaren 80 werden verkocht, voornamelijk in Europa. Na het succes van de ZX Spectrum van Sinclair Research stelden de geldschieters van Tangerine een thuiscomputer voor en Tangerine richtte Oric Products International Ltd op om de Oric-1 te ontwikkelen. De computer werd geïntroduceerd in 1982.[5] In 1983 werden er ongeveer 160.000 Oric-1 computers verkocht in de UK, plus nog eens 50.000 in Frankrijk (waar het de best verkochte machine van het jaar was). Dit resulteerde in de overname van Oric en de financiering van een opvolger, de Oric Atmos uit 1984.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pl_PL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Oric to nazwa używana przez brytyjską firmę Tangerine Computer Systems dla serii komputerów domowych opartych na 6502, sprzedawanych w latach 80-tych, głównie w Europie. Wraz z sukcesem ZX Spectrum od Sinclair Research, zwolennicy Tangerine zasugerowali komputer domowy, a Tangerine utworzyło Oric Products International Ltd w celu opracowania Oric-1. Komputer został wprowadzony na rynek w 1982 r.[5] W 1983 r. sprzedano około 160 000 komputerów Oric-1 w Wielkiej Brytanii oraz kolejne 50 000 we Francji (gdzie był najlepiej sprzedającym się urządzeniem w roku). Spowodowało to, że firma Oric została przejęta i otrzymała fundusze na kolejny model, Oric Atmos z 1984 roku.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Komputer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_BR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Oric foi o nome usado pela Tangerine Computer Systems, sediada no Reino Unido, para uma série de computadores domésticos baseados em 6502 vendidos na década de 1980, principalmente na Europa. Com o sucesso do ZX Spectrum da Sinclair Research, os patrocinadores da Tangerine sugeriram um computador doméstico e a Tangerine formou a Oric Products International Ltd para desenvolver o Oric-1. O computador foi lançado em 1982.[5] Em 1983, aproximadamente 160.000 computadores Oric-1 foram vendidos no Reino Unido, além de outros 50.000 na França (onde foi a máquina mais vendida do ano). Isso fez com que a Oric fosse adquirida e recebesse financiamento para um modelo sucessor, o Oric Atmos, de 1984.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computador</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_PT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Oric era o nome usado pelos sistemas de computadores de tangerina no Reino Unido para uma série de computadores domésticos baseados em 6502, vendidos na década de 1980, principalmente na Europa. Com o sucesso do ZX Spectrum da Sinclair Research, os apoiadores da Tangerine sugeriram um computador doméstico e a Tangerine formou a ORIC Products International Ltd para desenvolver o ORIC-1. O computador foi introduzido em 1982. [5]Durante 1983, aproximadamente 160.000 computadores ORIC-1 foram vendidos no Reino Unido, além de outros 50.000 na França (onde era a máquina mais vendida do ano). Isso resultou na adquirir o Oric e receber financiamento para um modelo sucessor, o Oric Atmos de 1984.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computador</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ro_RO">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Oric a fost numele folosit de Tangerine Computer Systems, cu sediul în Marea Britanie, pentru o serie de computere de uz casnic bazate pe 6502 vândute în anii 1980, în special în Europa. Odată cu succesul ZX Spectrum de la Sinclair Research, susținătorii Tangerine au sugerat un computer pentru acasă, iar Tangerine a format Oric Products International Ltd pentru a dezvolta Oric-1. Computerul a fost introdus pe piață în 1982[5]. În cursul anului 1983, aproximativ 160 000 de computere Oric-1 au fost vândute în Regatul Unit, plus alte 50 000 în Franța (unde a fost cel mai bine vândut computer al anului). Acest lucru a dus la achiziționarea Oric și la acordarea de fonduri pentru un model succesor, Oric Atmos din 1984.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ru_RU">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Oric - это название, которым британская компания Tangerine Computer Systems назвала серию домашних компьютеров на базе 6502, продававшихся в 1980-х годах, в основном в Европе. После успеха ZX Spectrum от Sinclair Research сторонники Tangerine предложили создать домашний компьютер, и Tangerine основала компанию Oric Products International Ltd для разработки Oric-1. Компьютер был представлен в 1982 г.[5] В 1983 г. в Великобритании было продано около 160 000 компьютеров Oric-1, еще 50 000 - во Франции (где он стал самым продаваемым в этом году). В результате компания Oric была приобретена и получила финансирование на создание преемника, Oric Atmos 1984 года.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Компьютер</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sr_RS">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Орић је било име које користи Тангерине у Великој Британији за серију од 6502 кућних рачунара који се продају у 1980-има, пре свега у Европи.Уз успех ЗКС спектра из Синцлаир-а, Танцларинови потписници су предложили кућни рачунар и мандарину формирали Орић Продуцтс Интернатионал ЛТД за развој Ориц-1.Рачунар је представљен 1982. [5]Током 1983. године у Великој Британији је продато око 160 000 Ориц-1 рачунара, плус још 50.000 у Француској (где је то била горња продаја машина).То је резултирало да се Орић стекне и дате средства за модел наследника, Ориц Атмос из 1984. године.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Рачунар</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sv_SE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Oric var namnet som användes av brittiska Tangerine Computer Systems för en serie 6502-baserade hemdatorer som såldes under 1980-talet, främst i Europa. Med framgången för ZX Spectrum från Sinclair Research föreslog Tangerines finansiärer en hemdator och Tangerine bildade Oric Products International Ltd för att utveckla Oric-1. Datorn introducerades 1982[5]. 1983 såldes cirka 160.000 Oric-1-datorer i Storbritannien och ytterligare 50.000 i Frankrike (där den var årets mest sålda dator). Detta ledde till att Oric blev uppköpt och fick finansiering för en efterföljare, Oric Atmos från 1984.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Dator</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_CN">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Oric 是英国 Tangerine Computer Systems 公司在 20 世纪 80 年代主要在欧洲销售的一系列基于 6502 的家用电脑的名称。随着辛克莱研究公司的 ZX Spectrum 取得成功，Tangerine 的支持者建议推出家用电脑，于是 Tangerine 成立了 Oric Products International Ltd，开发出 Oric-1。1983 年，Oric-1 电脑在英国售出约 160,000 台，在法国售出 50,000 台（是当年最畅销的电脑）。因此，Oric 被收购并获得资金，用于生产后继型号，即 1984 年的 Oric Atmos。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>计算机</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_TW">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Oric 是英國 Tangerine Computer Systems 在 1980 年代使用的名稱，代表一系列以 6502 為基礎的家用電腦，主要在歐洲銷售。由於 Sinclair Research 的 ZX Spectrum 大獲成功，Tangerine 的支持者建議推出家用電腦，於是 Tangerine 成立了 Oric Products International Ltd 來開發 Oric-1。這款電腦於 1982 年推出。[5] 1983 年間，大約有 160,000 台 Oric-1 電腦在英國售出，另外還有 50,000 台在法國售出（這款電腦是當年法國最暢銷的電腦）。這使得 Oric 被收購，並獲得資金推出後繼機型，即 1984 年的 Oric Atmos。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>電腦</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
</theme>
