<theme>
    <variables>
        <systemName>PC Engine CD-ROM²</systemName>
        <systemDescription>The CD-ROM² (pronounced CD-ROM-ROM) is an add-on attachment for the PC Engine that was released in Japan on December 4, 1988. The add-on allows the core versions of the console to play PC Engine games in CD-ROM format in addition to standard HuCards. This made the PC Engine the first video game console to use CD-ROMs as a storage media. The add-on consisted of two devices - the CD player itself and the interface unit, which connects the CD player to the console and provides a unified power supply and output for both.

It was later released as the TurboGrafx-CD in the United States in November 1989, with a remodeled interface unit in order to suit the different shape of the TurboGrafx-16 console. The TurboGrafx-CD had a launch price of $399.99 and did not include any bundled games. Fighting Street and Monster Lair were the TurboGrafx-CD launch titles; Ys Book I and II soon followed.</systemDescription>
        <systemManufacturer>NEC</systemManufacturer>
        <systemReleaseYear>1988</systemReleaseYear>
        <systemReleaseDate>1988-12-04</systemReleaseDate>
        <systemReleaseDateFormated>December 4, 1988</systemReleaseDateFormated>
        <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
        <systemCoverSizeType>square</systemCoverSizeType>
        <systemColor>5a8dca</systemColor>
        <systemColorPalette1>B2B2B2</systemColorPalette1>
        <systemColorPalette2>FE0000</systemColorPalette2>
        <systemColorPalette3>333333</systemColorPalette3>
        <systemColorPalette4>D9D9D9</systemColorPalette4>
        <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
    </variables>
    <language name="ar_SA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>إن CD-ROM² (تُنطق CD-ROM-ROM-ROM) هو ملحق إضافي لمحرك الكمبيوتر الشخصي تم إصداره في اليابان في 4 ديسمبر 1988. تسمح الوظيفة الإضافية للإصدارات الأساسية من وحدة التحكم بتشغيل ألعاب PC Engine بصيغة CD-ROM بالإضافة إلى بطاقات HuCards القياسية. وهذا جعل محرك الكمبيوتر الشخصي أول وحدة تحكم بألعاب الفيديو تستخدم الأقراص المدمجة كوسائط تخزين. تتألف الوظيفة الإضافية من جهازين - مشغل الأقراص المدمجة نفسه ووحدة الواجهة التي تربط مشغل الأقراص المدمجة بوحدة التحكم وتوفر مصدر طاقة ومخرج موحد لكليهما.

تم إصداره لاحقًا باسم TurboGrafx-CD في الولايات المتحدة في نوفمبر 1989، مع وحدة واجهة معاد تشكيلها لتتناسب مع الشكل المختلف لوحدة التحكم TurboGrafx-16. بلغ سعر إطلاق TurboGrafx-CD عند الإطلاق 399.99 دولارًا أمريكيًا ولم يتضمن أي ألعاب مجمعة. كانت لعبتا Fighting Street وMonster Lair هما لعبتا إطلاق TurboGrafx-CD؛ وسرعان ما تبعهما لعبتا Ys Book I وII.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>وحدة التحكم</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="bs_BA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>CD-ROM² (izgovoreni CD-ROM-ROM) je dodatak za PC motor koji je pušten u Japan 4. decembra 1988. godine. Dodatak omogućava suzgrenim verzijama konzole da igraju PC motorne igre u CD-ROM formatu pored standardnih HUCKS-a. To je učinilo PC motor prva konzola za video igre za upotrebu CD-ROM-ova kao medija za pohranu. Dodatak se sastojao od dva uređaja - Sam CD uređaj i jedinicu sučelja, koja povezuje CD uređaj na konzolu i pruža jedinstveno napajanje i izlaz za obje.

Kasnije je pušten kao Turbografx-CD u Sjedinjenim Državama u novembru 1989., s remodeljenim sučeljem u cilju odgovarajućeg oblika turbografx-16 konzole. Turbografx-CD imao je lansiranu cijenu od 399,99 USD i nije uključivao nijednu paketnu igre. Fighting Street i Monster Lair bili su naslovi lansiranja Turbografx-CD-a;Ubrzo su slijedili knjigu I i II.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Konzola</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ca_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>El CD-ROM² (pronunciat CD-ROM-ROM) és un complement addicional per al motor de PC que es va llançar al Japó el 4 de desembre de 1988. El complement permet que les versions bàsiques de la consola reprodueixin jocs de motor de PC aFormat CD-ROM A més de les hucards estàndard. Això va fer que el motor PC sigui la primera consola de videojocs que utilitzés CD-ROM com a suports d’emmagatzematge. El complement constava de dos dispositius: el propi reproductor de CD i la unitat d'interfície, que connecta el reproductor de CD a la consola i proporciona una font d'alimentació i una sortida unificada per a tots dos.

Posteriorment es va publicar com a turbografx-CD als Estats Units el novembre de 1989, amb una unitat d'interfície remodelada per adaptar-se a la diferent forma de la consola Turbografx-16. El Turbografx-CD tenia un preu de llançament de 399,99 dòlars i no va incloure cap joc agrupat. Fighting Street i Monster Lair van ser els títols de llançament Turbografx-CD;YS Book I i II aviat van seguir.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="de_DE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Die CD-ROM² (ausgesprochen CD-ROM-ROM) ist ein Zusatzgerät für die PC Engine, das am 4. Dezember 1988 in Japan veröffentlicht wurde. Das Add-on ermöglicht es den Kernversionen der Konsole, PC-Engine-Spiele im CD-ROM-Format zusätzlich zu den Standard-HuCards zu spielen. Damit war die PC Engine die erste Videospielkonsole, die CD-ROMs als Speichermedium verwendete. Das Add-on bestand aus zwei Geräten - dem CD-Player selbst und der Schnittstelleneinheit, die den CD-Player mit der Konsole verbindet und eine einheitliche Stromversorgung und einen einheitlichen Ausgang für beide bereitstellt.

Es wurde später als TurboGrafx-CD in den Vereinigten Staaten im November 1989 veröffentlicht, mit einer umgestalteten Interface-Einheit, um der unterschiedlichen Form der TurboGrafx-16-Konsole gerecht zu werden. Die TurboGrafx-CD hatte einen Einführungspreis von $399,99 und enthielt keine Spiele im Paket. Fighting Street und Monster Lair waren die TurboGrafx-CD-Einführungstitel; Ys Book I und II folgten bald.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Konsole</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="es_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>El CD-ROM² (pronunciado CD-ROM-ROM) es un complemento para la PC Engine que salió a la venta en Japón el 4 de diciembre de 1988. Este complemento permite que las versiones básicas de la consola reproduzcan juegos de PC Engine en formato CD-ROM, además de las HuCards estándar. Esto convirtió a la PC Engine en la primera videoconsola en utilizar CD-ROM como medio de almacenamiento. El complemento constaba de dos dispositivos: el reproductor de CD propiamente dicho y la unidad de interfaz, que conecta el reproductor de CD a la consola y proporciona una fuente de alimentación y una salida unificadas para ambos.

Posteriormente, en noviembre de 1989, salió a la venta en Estados Unidos como TurboGrafx-CD, con una unidad de interfaz remodelada para adaptarse a la forma diferente de la consola TurboGrafx-16. El TurboGrafx-CD tuvo un precio de lanzamiento de 399,99 dólares y no incluía ningún juego. Fighting Street y Monster Lair fueron los títulos de lanzamiento del TurboGrafx-CD; pronto le siguieron Ys Book I y II.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Consola</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="fr_FR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Le CD-ROM² (prononcé CD-ROM-ROM) est un module d'extension pour le PC Engine qui est sorti au Japon le 4 décembre 1988. Cet accessoire permet aux versions principales de la console de jouer à des jeux PC Engine au format CD-ROM en plus des cartes HuCards standard. La PC Engine est ainsi devenue la première console de jeux vidéo à utiliser des CD-ROM comme support de stockage. Le module complémentaire se compose de deux appareils : le lecteur de CD lui-même et l'unité d'interface, qui relie le lecteur de CD à la console et fournit une alimentation et une sortie unifiées pour les deux.

Il a été commercialisé sous le nom de TurboGrafx-CD aux États-Unis en novembre 1989, avec une unité d'interface remodelée pour s'adapter à la forme différente de la console TurboGrafx-16. Le TurboGrafx-CD a été lancé au prix de 399,99 dollars et n'incluait aucun jeu. Fighting Street et Monster Lair ont été les titres de lancement du TurboGrafx-CD ; Ys Book I et II ont suivi peu après.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="hr_HR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>CD-ROM² (izgovarani CD-ROM-ROM) dodatak je privitka za PC motor koji je u Japanu objavljen 4. prosinca 1988.. Dodatak omogućuje osnovne verzije konzole za igranje PC motora u CD-ROM formatu, osim standardnih hucarda. To je PC motor učinilo prvom konzolom za video igre za korištenje CD-ROM-a kao medija za pohranu. Dodatak se sastojao od dva uređaja - samog CD playera i jedinice sučelja, koji CD player povezuje na konzolu i pruža objedinjeni napajanje i izlaz za oba.

Kasnije je objavljen kao Turbografx-CD u Sjedinjenim Državama u studenom 1989. godine, s preuređenom jedinicom sučelja kako bi odgovarao različitom obliku konzole Turbografx-16. Turbografx-CD imao je lansirnu cijenu od 399,99 USD i nije uključio nijednu paketu. Fighting Street i Monster Lair bili su naslovi za pokretanje Turbografx-CD;Uskoro je uslijedila knjiga I i II.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Konzola</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="it_IT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Il CD-ROM² (pronuncia CD-ROM-ROM) è un componente aggiuntivo per il PC Engine, rilasciato in Giappone il 4 dicembre 1988. Il componente aggiuntivo consente alle versioni principali della console di riprodurre i giochi del PC Engine in formato CD-ROM, oltre alle HuCard standard. Questo rendeva il PC Engine la prima console per videogiochi a utilizzare i CD-ROM come supporto di memorizzazione. Il componente aggiuntivo è costituito da due dispositivi: il lettore CD stesso e l'unità di interfaccia, che collega il lettore CD alla console e fornisce un'alimentazione e un'uscita unificate per entrambi.

Il TurboGrafx-CD è stato successivamente rilasciato negli Stati Uniti nel novembre 1989, con un'unità di interfaccia modificata per adattarsi alla diversa forma della console TurboGrafx-16. Il TurboGrafx-CD aveva un prezzo di lancio di 399,99 dollari e non includeva alcun gioco in bundle. Fighting Street e Monster Lair furono i titoli di lancio del TurboGrafx-CD; Ys Book I e II seguirono presto.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ja_JP">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>CD-ROM²（読み：シーディーロムロム）は、1988年12月4日に日本で発売されたPCエンジン用のアドオンアタッチメントである。このアドオンにより、ゲーム機のコアバージョンは、標準のHuカードに加えて、CD-ROMフォーマットでPCエンジンのゲームをプレイできるようになった。これにより、PCエンジンは記憶媒体としてCD-ROMを使用する最初のゲーム機となった。このアドオンは、CDプレーヤー本体と、CDプレーヤーをゲーム機に接続し、両方の電源と出力を統一するインターフェイスユニットの2つのデバイスで構成されている。

その後、1989年11月にTurboGrafx-CDとして米国で発売され、TurboGrafx-16コンソールの形状の違いに合わせてインターフェイスユニットが改造された。TurboGrafx-CDの発売価格は399.99ドルで、同梱ゲームはなかった。Fighting Street』と『Monster Lair』がTurboGrafx-CDのローンチタイトルで、すぐに『Ys Book I』と『II』が続いた。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>コンソール</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ko_KR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>CD-ROM²(CD-ROM-ROM으로 발음)은 1988년 12월 4일에 일본에서 출시된 PC 엔진용 애드온입니다. 이 애드온을 사용하면 콘솔의 핵심 버전에서 표준 HuCard 외에 CD-ROM 형식의 PC Engine 게임을 플레이할 수 있습니다. 이로써 PC Engine은 CD-ROM을 저장 매체로 사용한 최초의 비디오 게임 콘솔이 되었습니다. 애드온은 CD 플레이어 자체와 CD 플레이어를 콘솔에 연결하고 두 장치에 통합된 전원 공급 및 출력을 제공하는 인터페이스 유닛의 두 가지 장치로 구성되었습니다.

이후 1989년 11월 미국에서 TurboGrafx-CD로 출시되었으며, TurboGrafx-16 콘솔의 다른 모양에 맞게 인터페이스 유닛을 개조하여 출시되었습니다. 출시 가격은 399.99달러였으며 번들 게임은 포함되지 않았습니다. 파이팅 스트리트와 몬스터 레어가 TurboGrafx-CD 출시 타이틀이었으며, 곧이어 Ys Book I과 II가 출시되었습니다.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>콘솔</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="nl_NL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>De CD-ROM² (uitgesproken als CD-ROM-ROM) is een uitbreiding voor de PC Engine die op 4 december 1988 in Japan werd uitgebracht. Met de add-on kunnen de kernversies van de console PC Engine-spellen afspelen in CD-ROM-formaat, naast de standaard HuCards. Dit maakte van de PC Engine de eerste videogameconsole die CD-ROM's als opslagmedium gebruikte. De add-on bestond uit twee apparaten - de cd-speler zelf en de interface-eenheid, die de cd-speler met de console verbindt en voor een uniforme voeding en uitgang voor beide zorgt.

Het werd later uitgebracht als de TurboGrafx-CD in de Verenigde Staten in november 1989, met een aangepaste interface-eenheid om te passen bij de andere vorm van de TurboGrafx-16 console. De TurboGrafx-CD had een lanceringsprijs van 399,99 dollar en bevatte geen gebundelde spellen. Fighting Street en Monster Lair waren de TurboGrafx-CD launchtitels; Ys Book I en II volgden snel.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pl_PL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>CD-ROM² (wymawiane jako CD-ROM-ROM) to dodatek do konsoli PC Engine, który został wydany w Japonii 4 grudnia 1988 roku. Dodatek umożliwia podstawowym wersjom konsoli odtwarzanie gier PC Engine w formacie CD-ROM oprócz standardowych kart HuCard. Dzięki temu PC Engine stała się pierwszą konsolą do gier wideo wykorzystującą CD-ROM jako nośnik pamięci. Dodatek składał się z dwóch urządzeń - samego odtwarzacza CD i modułu interfejsu, który łączył odtwarzacz CD z konsolą i zapewniał zunifikowane zasilanie i wyjście dla obu urządzeń.

Został on później wydany jako TurboGrafx-CD w Stanach Zjednoczonych w listopadzie 1989 roku, z przebudowanym modułem interfejsu w celu dopasowania do innego kształtu konsoli TurboGrafx-16. Cena premierowa TurboGrafx-CD wynosiła 399,99 USD i nie zawierała żadnych dołączonych gier. Fighting Street i Monster Lair były tytułami startowymi TurboGrafx-CD; Ys Book I i II wkrótce potem.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Konsola</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_BR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O CD-ROM² (pronuncia-se CD-ROM-ROM) é um acessório complementar para o PC Engine que foi lançado no Japão em 4 de dezembro de 1988. O complemento permite que as versões principais do console reproduzam jogos do PC Engine no formato de CD-ROM, além dos HuCards padrão. Isso tornou o PC Engine o primeiro console de videogame a usar CD-ROMs como mídia de armazenamento. O complemento consistia em dois dispositivos: o próprio CD player e a unidade de interface, que conecta o CD player ao console e fornece uma fonte de alimentação e saída unificadas para ambos.

Posteriormente, foi lançado como TurboGrafx-CD nos Estados Unidos em novembro de 1989, com uma unidade de interface remodelada para se adequar ao formato diferente do console TurboGrafx-16. O TurboGrafx-CD tinha um preço de lançamento de US$ 399,99 e não incluía nenhum jogo. Fighting Street e Monster Lair foram os títulos de lançamento do TurboGrafx-CD; Ys Book I e II vieram logo em seguida.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_PT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O CD-ROM² (pronunciado CD-ROM-ROM) é um acessório adicional para o mecanismo de PC que foi lançado no Japão em 4 de dezembro de 1988. O complemento permite que as versões principais do console joguem jogos de mecanismo de PC em formato de CD-ROM, além de hucards padrão. Isso fez do mecanismo de PC o primeiro console de videogame a usar CD-ROMs como mídia de armazenamento. O complemento consistia em dois dispositivos - o próprio CD player e a unidade de interface, que conecta o CD player ao console e fornece uma fonte de alimentação e saída unificadas para ambos.

Mais tarde, foi lançado como o Turbografx-CD nos Estados Unidos em novembro de 1989, com uma unidade de interface remodelada para se adequar à forma diferente do console TurboGrafx-16. O Turbografx-CD tinha um preço de lançamento de US $ 399,99 e não incluiu jogos em pacote. Fighting Street e Monster Lair foram os títulos de lançamento do TurboGrafx-CD;O livro YS I e II logo seguiram.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ro_RO">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>CD-ROM² (pronunțat CD-ROM-ROM) este un accesoriu suplimentar pentru PC Engine care a fost lansat în Japonia pe 4 decembrie 1988. Accesoriul permite versiunilor de bază ale consolei să redea jocuri PC Engine în format CD-ROM în plus față de cardurile HuCard standard. Acest lucru a făcut din PC Engine prima consolă de jocuri video care a utilizat CD-ROM-uri ca suport de stocare. Componenta suplimentară a constat din două dispozitive - CD playerul în sine și unitatea de interfață, care conectează CD playerul la consolă și asigură o sursă de alimentare și o ieșire unificate pentru ambele.

Acesta a fost lansat ulterior în Statele Unite în noiembrie 1989 sub numele de TurboGrafx-CD, cu o unitate de interfață remodelată pentru a se potrivi formei diferite a consolei TurboGrafx-16. TurboGrafx-CD a avut un preț de lansare de 399,99 $ și nu a inclus niciun joc la pachet. Fighting Street și Monster Lair au fost titlurile de lansare TurboGrafx-CD; Ys Book I și II au urmat în curând.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Consolă</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ru_RU">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>CD-ROM² (произносится как CD-ROM-ROM) - это дополнение для PC Engine, которое было выпущено в Японии 4 декабря 1988 года. Это дополнение позволяет основным версиям консоли воспроизводить игры PC Engine в формате CD-ROM в дополнение к стандартным картам HuCards. Таким образом, PC Engine стала первой игровой консолью, использующей CD-ROM в качестве носителя информации. Дополнение состоит из двух устройств - самого CD-плеера и интерфейсного блока, который соединяет CD-плеер с консолью и обеспечивает единый источник питания и выход для обоих.

Позже, в ноябре 1989 года, оно было выпущено в США под названием TurboGrafx-CD, с измененным интерфейсным блоком, чтобы соответствовать другой форме консоли TurboGrafx-16. Стартовая цена TurboGrafx-CD составляла $399,99, и в комплект поставки не входило ни одной игры. Стартовыми играми для TurboGrafx-CD стали Fighting Street и Monster Lair; вскоре за ними последовали Ys Book I и II.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Консоль</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sr_RS">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>ЦД-РОМ² (изражен ЦД-РОМ-РОМ) је додатак за ПЦ мотор који је објављен 4. децембра 1988. године. Додатак омогућава основне верзије конзоле да играју Игре за ПЦ мотора у ЦД-РОМ формату поред стандардних култура.То је учинило ПЦ Енгине, прву видео игру са видео игаром да користи ЦД-РОМ-ове као медиј за складиштење.Додатак састојао се од два уређаја - сама ЦД плејер и јединицу интерфејса, која повезује ЦД плејер у конзолу и пружа јединствени напајање и излаз и за оба.

Касније је објављен као Турбографк-ЦД у Сједињеним Државама у новембру 1989., са преуређеном јединицом сучеља како би одговарао различитом облику турбографк-16 конзоле.Турбографк-ЦД је имао покретну цену од 399,99 УСД и није укључивао никакве пакетне игре.Борбена улица и монструм лаир били су турбографк-цд титуле за покретање;ИС књига И и ИИ убрзо су следиле.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Конзола</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sv_SE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>CD-ROM² (uttalas CD-ROM-ROM) är en tilläggsutrustning för PC Engine som släpptes i Japan den 4 december 1988. Tillägget gör det möjligt för konsolens grundversioner att spela PC Engine-spel i CD-ROM-format utöver vanliga HuCards. Detta gjorde PC Engine till den första videospelskonsolen som använde CD-ROM som lagringsmedium. Tillägget består av två enheter - själva CD-spelaren och gränssnittsenheten, som ansluter CD-spelaren till konsolen och ger en enhetlig strömförsörjning och utgång för båda.

Den släpptes senare som TurboGrafx-CD i USA i november 1989, med en ombyggd gränssnittsenhet för att passa den annorlunda formen på TurboGrafx-16-konsolen. TurboGrafx-CD hade ett lanseringspris på 399,99 dollar och innehöll inte några medföljande spel. Fighting Street och Monster Lair var lanseringstitlarna för TurboGrafx-CD; Ys Book I och II följde snart efter.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Konsol</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_CN">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>CD-ROM²（读作 CD-ROM-ROM）是 PC 引擎的一个附加附件，于 1988 年 12 月 4 日在日本发布。除了标准的 HuCard 外，该附件还允许控制台的核心版本以 CD-ROM 格式播放 PC 引擎游戏。这使得 PC 引擎成为第一款使用光盘作为存储介质的视频游戏机。该插件包括两个设备--CD 播放器本身和接口装置，后者将 CD 播放器连接到控制台，并为两者提供统一的电源和输出。

它后来于 1989 年 11 月在美国以 TurboGrafx-CD 的名义发布，接口装置经过改造，以适应 TurboGrafx-16 控制台的不同形状。TurboGrafx-CD 的上市价格为 399.99 美元，不包括任何捆绑游戏。Fighting Street》和《Monster Lair》是 TurboGrafx-CD 的首发游戏；《Ys Book I》和《Ys Book II》很快就上市了。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>控制台</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_TW">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>CD-ROM²（讀作 CD-ROM-ROM）是 PC Engine 的附加附件，於 1988 年 12 月 4 日在日本發售。此附加元件可讓核心版本的控制台除了標準的 HuCard 外，還能播放 CD-ROM 格式的 PC Engine 遊戲。這使得 PC Engine 成為第一台使用 CD-ROM 作為儲存媒體的視訊遊戲主機。該附加元件由兩個裝置組成 - CD 播放器本身和介面裝置，介面裝置可將 CD 播放器與控制台連接起來，並為兩者提供統一的電源和輸出。

其後在 1989 年 11 月以 TurboGrafx-CD 的名義在美國發售，為了配合 TurboGrafx-16 控制台的不同形狀，介面裝置也經過改裝。TurboGrafx-CD 的發售價格為 399.99 美元，並且不包含任何捆綁遊戲。Fighting Street 和 Monster Lair 是 TurboGrafx-CD 的發售遊戲；Ys Book I 和 II 隨即推出。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>控制台</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
</theme>
