<theme>
    <variables>
        <systemName>SAM Coupé</systemName>
        <systemDescription>The SAM Coupé (pronounced /sæm ku:peɪ/ from its original British English branding) is an 8-bit British home computer that was first released in late 1989. It was based on and designed to have compatibility with the ZX Spectrum 48K and marketed as a logical upgrade from the Spectrum. It was originally manufactured by Miles Gordon Technology (MGT), based in Swansea in the United Kingdom.</systemDescription>
        <systemManufacturer>MGT</systemManufacturer>
        <systemReleaseYear>1989</systemReleaseYear>
        <systemReleaseDate>1989</systemReleaseDate>
        <systemReleaseDateFormated>1989</systemReleaseDateFormated>
        <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        <systemCoverSize>3-4</systemCoverSize>
        <systemCoverSizeType>portrait</systemCoverSizeType>
        <systemColor>597FC1</systemColor>
        <systemColorPalette1>2A46A5</systemColorPalette1>
        <systemColorPalette2>C60000</systemColorPalette2>
        <systemColorPalette3>D3D8D3</systemColorPalette3>
        <systemColorPalette4>96958C</systemColorPalette4>
        <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
    </variables>
    <language name="ar_SA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>إن SAM Coupé (تُنطق /sæm ku:peɪ/ من علامتها التجارية البريطانية الأصلية باللغة الإنجليزية) هو كمبيوتر منزلي بريطاني من 8 بت تم إصداره لأول مرة في أواخر عام 1989. وقد استند إلى حاسوب ZX Spectrum 48K وصُمم ليكون متوافقاً مع حاسوب ZX Spectrum 48K وتم تسويقه كترقية منطقية من Spectrum. وقد تم تصنيعه في الأصل من قبل شركة مايلز جوردون تكنولوجي (MGT)، ومقرها في سوانسي في المملكة المتحدة.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>الحاسب الآلي</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="bs_BA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>The Sam Coupé (izgovara / Sæm ku: Peɪ / iz njegove izvorne britanske english brendiranje) je 8-bitni britanski kućni računar koji je prvi put objavljen krajem 1989. godine. Zasnovan je na i dizajniranom da ima kompatibilnost sa ZX spektrom 48k i na tržištem kao logička nadogradnja iz spektra. Prvobitno je proizvedena od miljelske milje, Gordon tehnologija (MGT), sa sjedištem u Swanseiu u Velikoj Britaniji.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Računar</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ca_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>El Sam Coupé (pronunciat / sæm ku: Peɪ / de la seva original marca britànica anglesa) és un ordinador de casa britànic de 8 bits que es va publicar per primeracom a actualització lògica de l’espectre. Va ser fabricat originalment per Miles Gordon Technology (MGT), amb seu a Swansea al Regne Unit.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="de_DE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Der SAM Coupé (ausgesprochen /sæm ku:peɪ/ nach seinem ursprünglichen britischen Namen) ist ein britischer 8-Bit-Heimcomputer, der Ende 1989 auf den Markt kam. Er basierte auf dem ZX Spectrum 48K, war mit diesem kompatibel und wurde als logische Weiterentwicklung des Spectrum vermarktet. Er wurde ursprünglich von Miles Gordon Technology (MGT) mit Sitz in Swansea im Vereinigten Königreich hergestellt.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="es_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>El SAM Coupé (pronunciado /sæm ku:peɪ/ por su marca original en inglés británico) es un ordenador doméstico británico de 8 bits que salió a la venta a finales de 1989. Estaba basado y diseñado para ser compatible con el ZX Spectrum 48K y se comercializó como una actualización lógica del Spectrum. Fue fabricado originalmente por Miles Gordon Technology (MGT), con sede en Swansea (Reino Unido).</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Ordenador</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="fr_FR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Le SAM Coupé (prononcé /sæm ku:peɪ/ à partir de son nom anglais original) est un ordinateur domestique britannique 8 bits qui a été commercialisé pour la première fois à la fin de l'année 1989. Il était basé sur le ZX Spectrum 48K et conçu pour être compatible avec celui-ci, et il a été commercialisé comme une évolution logique du Spectrum. Il a été fabriqué à l'origine par Miles Gordon Technology (MGT), basé à Swansea au Royaume-Uni.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Ordinateur</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="hr_HR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Sam Coupé (izgovoren / Sæm KU: PEɪ / Iz svog originalnog britanskog engleskog brendiranja) je 8-bitno britansko kućno računalo koje je prvi put objavljeno krajem 1989. godine. Zasnovan je i zamišljeno je da ima kompatibilnost sa ZX Spectrum 48K i plasira se kao logična nadogradnja iz spektra. Prvobitno ga je proizveo Miles Gordon Technology (MGT) sa sjedištem u Swanseaju u Velikoj Britaniji.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Računalo</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="it_IT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Il SAM Coupé (pronunciato /sæm ku:peɪ/ dal suo marchio originale in inglese britannico) è un home computer britannico a 8 bit rilasciato per la prima volta alla fine del 1989. Era basato e progettato per essere compatibile con lo ZX Spectrum 48K e commercializzato come un logico upgrade dello Spectrum. Fu originariamente prodotto da Miles Gordon Technology (MGT), con sede a Swansea, nel Regno Unito.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ja_JP">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>SAMクーペ（発音：/sæm ku:pe↪Ll_26A/元のイギリス英語のブランド名から）は、1989年後半に発売されたイギリスの8ビット家庭用コンピュータである。ZX Spectrum 48Kをベースに設計され、Spectrumからの論理的なアップグレードとして販売された。当初はイギリスのスワンシーに本社を置くマイルズ・ゴードン・テクノロジー（MGT）が製造していた。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>コンピューター</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ko_KR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>샘 쿠페(원래 영국식 영어 브랜드에서 /sæm ku:peɪ/로 발음)는 1989년 말에 처음 출시된 8비트 영국 가정용 컴퓨터입니다. ZX Spectrum 48K를 기반으로 하고 호환성을 갖도록 설계되었으며 Spectrum의 논리적 업그레이드로 판매되었습니다. 원래는 영국 스완지에 본사를 둔 마일즈 고든 테크놀로지(MGT)에서 제조했습니다.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>컴퓨터</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="nl_NL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>De SAM Coupé (uitgesproken als /sæm ku:peɪ/ van de originele Brits-Engelse merknaam) is een 8-bit Britse thuiscomputer die eind 1989 voor het eerst werd uitgebracht. Hij was gebaseerd op en ontworpen om compatibel te zijn met de ZX Spectrum 48K en werd op de markt gebracht als een logische upgrade van de Spectrum. Hij werd oorspronkelijk gemaakt door Miles Gordon Technology (MGT), gevestigd in Swansea in het Verenigd Koninkrijk.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pl_PL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>SAM Coupé (wymawiane jako /sæm ku:peɪ/ od oryginalnego brytyjskiego angielskiego brandingu) to 8-bitowy brytyjski komputer domowy, który został po raz pierwszy wydany pod koniec 1989 roku. Był on oparty i zaprojektowany tak, aby był kompatybilny z ZX Spectrum 48K i sprzedawany jako logiczne ulepszenie Spectrum. Pierwotnie został wyprodukowany przez Miles Gordon Technology (MGT) z siedzibą w Swansea w Wielkiej Brytanii.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Komputer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_BR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O SAM Coupé (pronuncia-se /sæm ku:peɪ/ de sua marca original em inglês britânico) é um computador doméstico britânico de 8 bits que foi lançado pela primeira vez no final de 1989. Ele foi baseado e projetado para ser compatível com o ZX Spectrum 48K e comercializado como uma atualização lógica do Spectrum. Foi originalmente fabricado pela Miles Gordon Technology (MGT), com sede em Swansea, no Reino Unido.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computador</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_PT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O Sam Coupé (pronunciado / Sæm Ku: PEɪ / de sua marca britânica original em inglês) é um computador doméstico britânico de 8 bits que foi lançado pela primeira vez no final de 1989. Foi baseado e projetado para ter compatibilidade com o ZX Spectrum 48K e comercializado como uma atualização lógica do espectro. Foi originalmente fabricado pela Miles Gordon Technology (MGT), com sede em Swansea, no Reino Unido.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computador</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ro_RO">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>SAM Coupé (pronunțat /sæm ku:peɪ/ de la brandingul său original din engleza britanică) este un computer de casă britanic pe 8 biți care a fost lansat pentru prima dată la sfârșitul anului 1989. Acesta a fost bazat pe și proiectat pentru a avea compatibilitate cu ZX Spectrum 48K și comercializat ca un upgrade logic de la Spectrum. Acesta a fost inițial fabricat de Miles Gordon Technology (MGT), cu sediul în Swansea, Regatul Unit.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ru_RU">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>SAM Coupé (произносится /sæm ku:peɪ/ от оригинального британского английского названия) - это 8-битный британский домашний компьютер, впервые выпущенный в конце 1989 года. Он был основан на ZX Spectrum 48K и разработан для совместимости с ним, а также продавался как логическое обновление Spectrum. Изначально он производился компанией Miles Gordon Technology (MGT), расположенной в городе Суонси в Великобритании.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Компьютер</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sr_RS">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Сам Цоупе (изговорено / сӕм ку: пеɪ / с њеног оригиналног британског енглеског брендирања) је 8-битни британски кућни рачунар који је први пут објављен крајем 1989. године. Био је засновано на и дизајниран да има компатибилност са ЗКС спектром 48К и пласира се као логична надоградња.Првобитно га је произвело од Милес Гордон технологија (МГТ), са седиштем у Свонсији у Великој Британији.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Рачунар</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sv_SE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>SAM Coupé (uttalas /sæm ku:peɪ/ från dess ursprungliga brittisk-engelska varumärke) är en brittisk 8-bitars hemdator som först släpptes i slutet av 1989. Den var baserad på och utformad för att vara kompatibel med ZX Spectrum 48K och marknadsfördes som en logisk uppgradering från Spectrum. Den tillverkades ursprungligen av Miles Gordon Technology (MGT), baserat i Swansea i Storbritannien.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Dator</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_CN">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>SAM Coupé（发音为/sæm ku:peɪ/，源自其最初的英式英语品牌）是一款 8 位英国家用电脑，于 1989 年底首次发布。它以 ZX Spectrum 48K 为基础设计，与 ZX Spectrum 48K 兼容，是 Spectrum 的合理升级版。它最初由位于英国斯旺西的迈尔斯-戈登技术公司（MGT）生产。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>计算机</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_TW">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>SAM Coupé（發音為 /sæm ku:peɪ/，源自其原始的英式英文品牌）是一款 8 位元英國家用電腦，於 1989 年末首次推出。它以 ZX Spectrum 48K 為基礎，並與 ZX Spectrum 48K 相容，是 Spectrum 的邏輯升級產品。它最初由位於英國斯旺西的 Miles Gordon Technology (MGT) 製造。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>電腦</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
</theme>
