<theme>
    <variables>
        <systemName>Satellaview</systemName>
        <systemDescription>The Satellaview is a satellite modem peripheral for Nintendo's Super Famicom system that was released in Japan in 1995. Available for pre-release orders beginning February 13, 1995, the Satellaview retailed for between ¥14,000 and 18,000 (at the time between USD$141 and 182) and came bundled with the BS-X Game Pak and an 8M Memory Pak. The Satellaview system was developed and released by Nintendo to receive signals broadcast from satellite TV station WOWOW's satellite radio subsidiary, St.GIGA. St.GIGA was responsible for file server management, maintenance, and vocalization for "SoundLink" games. Nintendo data broadcasts were given a fixed time slot known as the Super Famicom Hour during which scrambled Satellaview-related data was streamed via radio waves to be unscrambled by St.GIGA's "BS digital hi-vision TV." As a subscription-based station for ambient and New Age music, St.GIGA listeners were already equipped with "BS tuners" prior to St.GIGA's contract with Nintendo. Satellaview owners who lacked a "BS tuner" had to purchase one separately from St.GIGA at a price of ¥33,000, as well as sign up for Nintendo's and St.GIGA's monthly joint membership fees. Alternatively, users could rent "BS tuners" from St.GIGA for a 6-month period at a price of ¥5,400. Even at this premium price, St.GIGA reported subscriptions peaking at 116,378 households by March 1997, and dropping to around 46,000 by June 2001.</systemDescription>
        <systemManufacturer>Nintendo</systemManufacturer>
        <systemReleaseYear>1995</systemReleaseYear>
        <systemReleaseDate>1995-04-23</systemReleaseDate>
        <systemReleaseDateFormated>April 23, 1995</systemReleaseDateFormated>
        <systemHardwareType>Peripheral</systemHardwareType>
        <systemCoverSize>3-5</systemCoverSize>
        <systemCoverSizeType>portrait</systemCoverSizeType>
        <systemColor>d9ac3b</systemColor>
        <systemColorPalette1>37336C</systemColorPalette1>
        <systemColorPalette2>CD2943</systemColorPalette2>
        <systemColorPalette3>FFDF68</systemColorPalette3>
        <systemColorPalette4>647A54</systemColorPalette4>
        <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
    </variables>
    <language name="ar_SA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Satellaview عبارة عن جهاز مودم مودم للأقمار الصناعية لنظام سوبر فاميكوم من نينتندو الذي تم إصداره في اليابان في عام 1995. كان ساتيلافيو متاحًا لطلبات ما قبل الإصدار ابتداءً من 13 فبراير 1995، وكان سعره يتراوح بين 14000 ين ياباني و18000 ين ياباني (في ذلك الوقت بين 141 و182 دولارًا أمريكيًا) وكان يأتي مرفقًا مع BS-X Game Pak وذاكرة 8M Memory Pak. تم تطوير نظام Satellaview وإصداره من قبل Nintendo لاستقبال الإشارات التي تبثها محطة WOWOW التابعة لمحطة WOWOW الفضائية التابعة لشركة St.GIGA. كانت St.GIGA مسؤولة عن إدارة خادم الملفات والصيانة والصوت لألعاب "ساوندلينك". تم تخصيص فترة زمنية ثابتة لبث بيانات نينتندو تُعرف باسم ساعة سوبر فاميكوم، حيث كان يتم خلالها بث البيانات المتعلقة بالساتل "ساتلافيو" عبر موجات الراديو ليتم فك تشفيرها بواسطة "تلفزيون BS الرقمي عالي الرؤية" التابع لشركة St.GIGA. وباعتبارها محطة قائمة على الاشتراكات للموسيقى المحيطة وموسيقى العصر الجديد، كان مستمعو St.GIGA مجهزين بالفعل بأجهزة "موالفات BS" قبل تعاقد St.GIGA مع Nintendo. كان على مالكي Satellaview الذين يفتقرون إلى "موالف BS" شراء واحد بشكل منفصل من St.GIGA بسعر 33,000 ين، بالإضافة إلى الاشتراك في رسوم العضوية الشهرية المشتركة بين نينتندو وSt.GIGA. وبدلًا من ذلك، يمكن للمستخدمين استئجار "موالفات BS" من St.GIGA لمدة 6 أشهر بسعر 5400 ين. وحتى مع هذا السعر المرتفع، أفادت شركة St.GIGA أن الاشتراكات بلغت ذروتها عند 116,378 أسرة بحلول مارس 1997، وانخفضت إلى حوالي 46,000 بحلول يونيو 2001.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>محيطي</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="bs_BA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Satelit je satelitski modem periferni za Nintendov super porodijski sistem koji je objavljen u Japanu 1995. godine. Dostupno za naređenja pred izdavanjem početkom 13. februara 1995. godine, na malo-14.000 i 18.000 (u vrijeme između 14.000 USD) i u paketu BS-X Igra Pak i 8M memorijski pak. Nintendo je razvio i objavio je SatellaView sistem za primanje signala emitovanje sa satelitske TV stanice Wowow-ove satelitske radio podružnice, St. Giga. St. Giga je bila odgovorna za upravljanje, održavanje, održavanje i vokalizaciju poslužitelja datoteka za "SoundLink" igre. Nintendo emisije podataka dobili su fiksni vremenski utor koji su poznati kao Super Famicom sat tokom kojih su prekršeni podaci vezani za satelit prenoseći radio valovima koji bi mogli biti nevezirani "" BS digitalni TV televizor "BS digitalni TV televizor."Kao stanica zasnovana na pretplati za ambijentalnu i novu dobnu muziku, slušatelji St. Giga već su bili opremljeni "BS tjuneri" prije nego što je St. Giga ugovor sa Nintendoom. Vlasnici satelitskiew-a kojima je nedostajao "BS tuner", morali su kupiti jedan odvojeno od St. Giga po cijeni ¥ 33 000, kao i prijava za mjesečnu članarinu Nintendo i St. Giga. Alternativno, korisnici su mogli unajmiti "BS tjunere" iz St. Giga za 6-mesečni period po ceni ¥ 5.400.Čak i u ovoj premium ceni, St. Giga je prijavila pretplate koje su vršile na 116.378 domaćinstava do marta 1997. godine i napustili oko 46.000 do juna 2001. godine.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Periferni</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ca_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>The SatellaView és un perifèric de mòdem per satèl·lit per al sistema Super Famicom de Nintendo que es va publicar al Japó el 1995. Disponible per a les comandes pre-llançament a partir del 13 de febrer de 1995, el SatellaView es venia entre 14.000 i 18.000 ¥ (en aquell moment entre 141 i 182 dòlars USD i 182 USD) i es va incloure amb el joc BS-X Pak i un Pak de 8 m de memòria. El sistema SatellaView va ser desenvolupat i llançat per Nintendo per rebre senyals emeses de la filial de ràdio Satellite de Satellite TV Wowow, St. Giga. St. Giga es va fer responsable de la gestió, el manteniment i la vocalització del servidor de fitxers per als jocs "SoundLink". Les emissions de dades de Nintendo van rebre una ranura fixa coneguda com la Super Famicom Hour durant la qual es van transmetre les dades relacionades amb SatellaView a través de les ones de ràdio que es van desfer per la "BS Digital Hi-Vision TV" de St. Giga. Com a estació basada en subscripcions per a la música ambiental i la nova era, els oients de St. Giga ja estaven equipats amb "sintonitzadors BS" abans del contracte de St. Giga amb Nintendo. Els propietaris de SatellaView que no tenien un "sintonitzador BS" van haver de comprar -ne un per separat de St. Giga a un preu de 33.000 ¥, a més de registrar -se en les taxes mensuals de membres mensuals de Nintendo i St. Giga. De forma alternativa, els usuaris podrien llogar "sintonitzadors BS" de St. Giga per un període de 6 mesos a un preu de 5.400 ¥. Fins i tot a aquest preu premium, St. Giga va informar de subscripcions a 116.378 llars el març de 1997 i va caure a uns 46.000 al juny del 2001.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Peripheral</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="de_DE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Das Satellaview ist ein Satellitenmodem-Peripheriegerät für Nintendos Super Famicom-System, das 1995 in Japan veröffentlicht wurde. Der Satellaview war ab dem 13. Februar 1995 für Vorbestellungen erhältlich und kostete zwischen ¥14.000 und 18.000 (damals zwischen USD$141 und 182) und wurde zusammen mit dem BS-X Game Pak und einem 8M Memory Pak ausgeliefert. Das Satellaview-System wurde von Nintendo entwickelt und herausgegeben, um Signale zu empfangen, die vom Satellitenfernsehsender WOWOW, der Satellitenradio-Tochtergesellschaft von St.GIGA, ausgestrahlt wurden. St.GIGA war für die Verwaltung der Dateiserver, die Wartung und die Vertonung der "SoundLink"-Spiele zuständig. Nintendo-Datensendungen erhielten ein festes Zeitfenster, die so genannte Super Famicom Hour, in der verschlüsselte Satellaview-bezogene Daten über Radiowellen gestreamt wurden, um von St.GIGAs "BS digital hi-vision TV" entschlüsselt zu werden. Als Abonnement-Sender für Ambient- und New-Age-Musik waren die Hörer von St.GIGA bereits vor dem Vertrag von St.GIGA mit "BS-Tunern" ausgestattet. Satellaview-Besitzer, die keinen "BS-Tuner" hatten, mussten einen solchen separat von St.GIGA zum Preis von 33.000 Yen kaufen und sich für die monatlichen gemeinsamen Mitgliedsbeiträge von Nintendo und St.GIGA anmelden. Alternativ können Nutzer BS-Tuner von St.GIGA für einen Zeitraum von 6 Monaten zum Preis von 5.400 Yen mieten. Selbst bei diesem Höchstpreis meldete St.GIGA, dass die Zahl der Abonnements im März 1997 mit 116.378 Haushalten ihren Höchststand erreichte und bis Juni 2001 auf etwa 46.000 zurückging.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Peripherie</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="es_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>El Satellaview es un periférico de módem por satélite para la consola Super Famicom de Nintendo que salió a la venta en Japón en 1995. Disponible para pedidos anticipados a partir del 13 de febrero de 1995, el Satellaview se vendía por un precio de entre 14.000 y 18.000 yenes (en aquel momento, entre 141 y 182 dólares) y venía con el cartucho BS-X y un cartucho de memoria de 8 millones. La consola Satellaview fue desarrollada y comercializada por Nintendo para recibir las señales emitidas por la filial de radio por satélite de WOWOW, St.GIGA. St.GIGA se encargaba de la gestión del servidor de archivos, el mantenimiento y la vocalización de los juegos "SoundLink". Las emisiones de datos de Nintendo tenían una franja horaria fija conocida como la "hora de la Super Famicom", durante la cual se emitían por ondas de radio datos codificados relacionados con Satellaview para ser descifrados por la "BS digital hi-vision TV" de St.GIGA. Como emisora de música ambiental y New Age por suscripción, los oyentes de St.GIGA ya estaban equipados con "sintonizadores BS" antes del contrato de St.GIGA con Nintendo. Los propietarios de Satellaview que carecían de un "sintonizador BS" tenían que comprar uno por separado a St.GIGA a un precio de 33.000 yenes, además de suscribirse a las cuotas mensuales conjuntas de Nintendo y St.GIGA. Como alternativa, los usuarios pueden alquilar los "BS tuners" de St.GIGA durante 6 meses a un precio de 5.400 yenes. Incluso a este precio superior, St.GIGA informó de que las suscripciones alcanzaron un máximo de 116.378 hogares en marzo de 1997, y cayeron a unos 46.000 en junio de 2001.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Periférico</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="fr_FR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Le Satellaview est un modem satellite périphérique pour la console Super Famicom de Nintendo, sorti au Japon en 1995. Disponible en pré-commande à partir du 13 février 1995, le Satellaview se vendait entre 14 000 et 18 000 ¥ (à l'époque entre 141 et 182 USD) et était livré avec la cartouche de jeu BS-X et une cartouche de mémoire de 8M. La console Satellaview a été développée et commercialisée par Nintendo pour recevoir les signaux diffusés par la filiale radio par satellite de la chaîne de télévision WOWOW, St.GIGA. St.GIGA était responsable de la gestion des serveurs de fichiers, de la maintenance et de la vocalisation des jeux "SoundLink". Les diffusions de données Nintendo ont bénéficié d'un créneau horaire fixe connu sous le nom de "Super Famicom Hour" pendant lequel des données brouillées liées à Satellaview ont été diffusées par ondes radio pour être décodées par la "BS digital hi-vision TV" de St.GIGA. Les auditeurs de St.GIGA, station de musique ambiante et New Age par abonnement, étaient déjà équipés de "tuners BS" avant le contrat de St.GIGA avec Nintendo. Les propriétaires de Satellaview qui n'avaient pas de "BS tuner" devaient en acheter un séparément auprès de St.GIGA au prix de 33 000 ¥, et s'inscrire aux cotisations mensuelles communes de Nintendo et de St.GIGA. GIGA pour une période de 6 mois au prix de 5 400 ¥. Même à ce prix élevé, St.GIGA a indiqué que les abonnements avaient atteint un maximum de 116 378 ménages en mars 1997, pour retomber à environ 46 000 en juin 2001.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Périphérique</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="hr_HR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Satellaview je satelitski modem periferni sustav za Nintendov Super Famicom sustav koji je objavljen u Japanu 1995. godine. Dostupno za naredbe za prije puštanja početka 13. veljače 1995., Satellaview je prodao između 14.000 i 18.000 (u vrijeme između 141 i 182 USD, pamćeo je i 8. i 8m PS-X. Nintendo je razvio i objavio sustav Satellaview kako bi primao signale emitirane iz satelitske TV stanice Wowow -ove podružnice satelitskog radio -a, St. Giga. St. Giga je bila odgovorna za upravljanje datotekama, održavanje i vokalizaciju za igre "Soundlink". Nintendo podaci dobili su fiksni vremenski utor poznat kao Super Famicom Hour tijekom kojeg su se podaci povezani sa Satelaviewom emitirali putem radio valova koji će ih odmrznuti St. Giga "BS Digital Hi-Vision TV". Kao stanica koja se temelji na pretplati za ambijentalnu i New Age glazbu, St. Giga slušatelji već su bili opremljeni "BS tunerima" prije ugovora St. Gige s Nintendom. Vlasnici satelaview -a kojima je nedostajao "BS tuner" morali su ga kupiti odvojeno od St. Gige po cijeni od 33 000 ¥, kao i prijaviti se za mjesečne članove Nintendoa i St. Gige. Alternativno, korisnici su mogli unajmiti "BS TUNERS" iz St. Gige za 6-mjesečno razdoblje po cijeni od 5.400 ¥.Čak i po ovoj vrhunskoj cijeni, St. Giga je prijavila da su pretplate na vrhunac u 116.378 kućanstava do ožujka 1997. i pali na oko 46.000 do lipnja 2001. godine.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Periferni</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="it_IT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Il Satellaview è una periferica per modem satellitare per la console Super Famicom di Nintendo, rilasciata in Giappone nel 1995. Disponibile per gli ordini di pre-release a partire dal 13 febbraio 1995, il Satellaview era venduto a un prezzo compreso tra 14.000 e 18.000 ¥ (all'epoca tra 141 e 182 dollari USA) e veniva fornito in bundle con il BS-X Game Pak e un 8M Memory Pak. La console Satellaview fu sviluppata e rilasciata da Nintendo per ricevere i segnali trasmessi dalla filiale radiofonica satellitare della stazione televisiva WOWOW, St.GIGA. St.GIGA era responsabile della gestione dei file server, della manutenzione e della vocalizzazione dei giochi "SoundLink". Le trasmissioni di dati Nintendo avevano una fascia oraria fissa, nota come Super Famicom Hour, durante la quale i dati criptati relativi a Satellaview venivano trasmessi via onde radio per essere decodificati dalla "BS digital hi-vision TV" di St.GIGA. Essendo una stazione in abbonamento per musica ambient e New Age, gli ascoltatori di St.GIGA erano già dotati di "sintonizzatori BS" prima del contratto di St.GIGA con Nintendo. I possessori di Satellaview che non disponevano di un "sintonizzatore BS" dovevano acquistarne uno separatamente da St.GIGA al prezzo di 33.000 ¥, oltre a sottoscrivere un abbonamento mensile congiunto con Nintendo e St.GIGA. In alternativa, gli utenti possono noleggiare i "sintonizzatori BS" da St.GIGA per un periodo di 6 mesi al prezzo di 5.400 ¥. Anche a questo prezzo maggiorato, St.GIGA ha riferito che gli abbonamenti hanno raggiunto un picco di 116.378 famiglie nel marzo 1997, per poi scendere a circa 46.000 nel giugno 2001.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Periferica</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ja_JP">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Satellaviewは、1995年に日本で発売された任天堂のスーパーファミコン用の衛星モデム周辺機器である。1995年2月13日から先行予約販売され、価格は14,000円から18,000円（当時141ドルから182ドル）で、BS-Xゲームパックと8Mメモリーパックが同梱されていた。衛星放送WOWOWの衛星ラジオ子会社St.GIGAから放送される信号を受信するために任天堂が開発・発売したシステム。St.GIGAはファイルサーバーの管理、メンテナンス、「サウンドリンク」ゲームの発声を担当した。任天堂のデータ放送は、「スーパーファミコンアワー」と呼ばれる決まった時間帯に、スクランブルされたサテラビュー関連のデータを電波で流し、St.GIGAの "BSデジタルハイビジョンTV "でスクランブルを解除していた。St.GIGAはアンビエントやニューエイジの音楽を扱う定額制の放送局であるため、St.GIGAのリスナーは任天堂と契約する以前から "BSチューナー "を持っていた。BSチューナー」を持っていないサテラビューオーナーは、St.GIGAから別途33,000円の「BSチューナー」を購入し、任天堂とSt.GIGAの月額共同会費に加入する必要があった。また、St.GIGAから「BSチューナー」を6ヶ月間、5,400円でレンタルすることもできる。この割高な価格でも、St.GIGAによれば1997年3月までに116,378世帯が加入し、2001年6月には46,000世帯にまで減少した。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>ペリフェラル</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ko_KR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Satellaview는 1995년 일본에서 출시된 닌텐도의 슈퍼 패미컴 시스템용 위성 모뎀 주변기기입니다. 1995년 2월 13일부터 사전 예약 주문이 가능했던 Satellaview는 14,000~18,000엔(당시 미화 141~182달러)에 판매되었으며, BS-X 게임 팩과 8M 메모리 팩이 번들로 제공되었습니다. 위성 TV 방송국 WOWOW의 위성 라디오 자회사인 St.GIGA에서 방송하는 신호를 수신하기 위해 닌텐도가 개발하여 출시한 시스템이 바로 Satellaview 시스템입니다. 세인트가가는 파일 서버 관리, 유지보수, '사운드링크' 게임의 음성화 작업을 담당했습니다. 닌텐도 데이터 방송은 '슈퍼 패미컴 아워'라는 고정된 시간대를 지정하여 이 시간대에 스크램블된 위성방송 관련 데이터를 전파를 통해 스트리밍하여 St.GIGA의 "BS 디지털 하이비전 TV"에서 스크램블을 해제하는 방식으로 진행되었습니다. 앰비언트 및 뉴에이지 음악에 대한 구독 기반 방송국으로서 St.GIGA 청취자들은 St.GIGA가 Nintendo와 계약하기 전에 이미 "BS 튜너"를 장착하고 있었습니다. 'BS 튜너'가 없는 Satellaview 소유자는 33,000엔의 가격으로 St.GIGA에서 별도로 구매해야 했고, Nintendo와 St.GIGA의 월 공동 회비에도 가입해야 했습니다. 또는 6개월 동안 5,400엔의 가격으로 St.GIGA에서 'BS 튜너'를 대여할 수도 있습니다. 이러한 프리미엄 가격에도 불구하고 St.GIGA는 1997년 3월에 116,378가구로 정점을 찍고 2001년 6월에는 약 46,000가구로 감소했습니다.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>주변기기</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="nl_NL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>De Satellaview is een satellietmodem-randapparaat voor Nintendo's Super Famicom-systeem dat in 1995 in Japan werd uitgebracht. De Satellaview was vanaf 13 februari 1995 verkrijgbaar voor pre-release bestellingen en kostte tussen de 14.000 en 18.000 yen (destijds tussen de 141 en 182 USD). De Satellaview werd geleverd met het BS-X Game Pak en een 8M Memory Pak. Het Satellaview-systeem werd ontwikkeld en uitgebracht door Nintendo om signalen te ontvangen die werden uitgezonden door de satellietradio-dochteronderneming van WOWOW, St.GIGA. St.GIGA was verantwoordelijk voor het beheer van de bestandsserver, het onderhoud en de vocalisatie voor "SoundLink"-spellen. De gegevensuitzendingen van Nintendo kregen een vast tijdslot dat bekend stond als het Super Famicom Uur. Tijdens dit uur werden gecodeerde Satellaview-gerelateerde gegevens via radiogolven gestreamd om te worden gedecodeerd door St.GIGA's "BS digital hi-vision TV". Als abonneestation voor ambient en New Age muziek waren St.GIGA-luisteraars al uitgerust met "BS-tuners" voordat St.GIGA een contract sloot met Nintendo. Satellaview-eigenaars die geen BS-tuner hadden, moesten er een kopen bij St.GIGA voor een prijs van 33.000 yen en zich inschrijven voor de maandelijkse gezamenlijke lidmaatschapskosten van Nintendo en St.GIGA. Als alternatief kunnen gebruikers voor een periode van 6 maanden BS-tuners huren bij St.GIGA voor een prijs van 5.400 yen. Zelfs tegen deze hoge prijs meldde St.GIGA abonnementen met een piek van 116.378 huishoudens in maart 1997, om vervolgens te dalen tot ongeveer 46.000 in juni 2001.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Perifeer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pl_PL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Satellaview to modem satelitarny do systemu Super Famicom firmy Nintendo, który został wydany w Japonii w 1995 roku. Dostępny w przedsprzedaży od 13 lutego 1995 roku, Satellaview sprzedawany był w cenie od 14 000 do 18 000 jenów (w tamtym czasie od 141 do 182 USD) i był dostarczany w zestawie z BS-X Game Pak i 8M Memory Pak. System Satellaview został opracowany i wydany przez Nintendo w celu odbierania sygnałów nadawanych przez satelitarną stację telewizyjną WOWOW, spółkę zależną radia satelitarnego St.GIGA. St.GIGA była odpowiedzialna za zarządzanie serwerami plików, konserwację i wokalizację dla gier "SoundLink". Transmisje danych Nintendo miały ustalony przedział czasowy znany jako Godzina Super Famicom, podczas której zakodowane dane związane z Satellaview były przesyłane strumieniowo za pośrednictwem fal radiowych w celu ich odkodowania przez "BS digital hi-vision TV" St.GIGA. Jako oparta na subskrypcji stacja muzyki ambient i New Age, słuchacze St.GIGA byli już wyposażeni w "tunery BS" przed zawarciem umowy St.GIGA z Nintendo. Właściciele Satellaview, którzy nie posiadali "tunera BS", musieli zakupić go oddzielnie od St.GIGA w cenie 33 000 jenów, a także zapisać się na comiesięczne wspólne opłaty członkowskie Nintendo i St.GIGA. Alternatywnie, użytkownicy mogą wypożyczyć "tunery BS" od St.GIGA na okres 6 miesięcy w cenie 5 400 jenów. Nawet przy tak wysokiej cenie, St.GIGA zgłosiła, że liczba subskrypcji osiągnęła szczytowy poziom 116 378 gospodarstw domowych w marcu 1997 roku i spadła do około 46 000 w czerwcu 2001 roku.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Peryferyjne</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_BR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O Satellaview é um periférico de modem via satélite para o sistema Super Famicom da Nintendo, lançado no Japão em 1995. Disponível para pedidos de pré-lançamento a partir de 13 de fevereiro de 1995, o Satellaview era vendido no varejo por ¥14.000 a 18.000 (na época, entre US$ 141 e 182) e vinha com o BS-X Game Pak e um 8M Memory Pak. O sistema Satellaview foi desenvolvido e lançado pela Nintendo para receber sinais transmitidos pela subsidiária de rádio por satélite da estação de TV WOWOW, a St.GIGA. A St.GIGA era responsável pelo gerenciamento, manutenção e vocalização do servidor de arquivos para os jogos "SoundLink". As transmissões de dados da Nintendo recebiam um intervalo de tempo fixo conhecido como Super Famicom Hour, durante o qual os dados codificados relacionados ao Satellaview eram transmitidos por ondas de rádio para serem descodificados pela "BS digital hi-vision TV" da St.GIGA. Como uma estação baseada em assinatura para música ambiente e New Age, os ouvintes da St.GIGA já estavam equipados com "sintonizadores BS" antes do contrato da St.GIGA com a Nintendo. Os proprietários de Satellaview que não tinham um "sintonizador BS" precisavam comprar um separadamente da St.GIGA ao preço de ¥33.000, além de se inscreverem nas taxas mensais de associação conjunta da Nintendo e da St.GIGA. Como alternativa, os usuários poderiam alugar "sintonizadores BS" da St.GIGA por um período de 6 meses ao preço de ¥5.400. Mesmo com esse preço premium, a St.GIGA informou que as assinaturas atingiram o pico de 116.378 residências em março de 1997 e caíram para cerca de 46.000 em junho de 2001.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Periférico</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_PT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O Satellaview é um modem periférico de Satellite para o sistema Super Famicom da Nintendo, lançado no Japão em 1995. Disponível para pedidos de pré-lançamento a partir de 13 de fevereiro de 1995, o SatellaView foi vendido entre 14.000 e 18.000 (na época entre US $ 141 e 182) e veio com o BS-X. O sistema SatellaView foi desenvolvido e lançado pela Nintendo para receber sinais transmitidos da subsidiária de rádio por satélite de Satellite TV, St. Giga. O St. Giga foi responsável pelo gerenciamento, manutenção e vocalização de servidores de arquivos para jogos "Soundlink". As transmissões de dados da Nintendo receberam um intervalo de tempo fixo conhecido como Hora Super Famicom, durante a qual os dados relacionados à SatellaView foram transmitidos por meio de ondas de rádio para serem divulgadas pela "TV de alta visita da Visão Digital BS de St. Giga. Como uma estação baseada em assinatura para a música ambiental e da nova era, os ouvintes de St. Giga já estavam equipados com "BS Tuners" antes do contrato de St. Giga com a Nintendo. Os proprietários da SatellaView que não tinham um "sintonizador de BS" tiveram que comprar um separadamente de St. Giga a um preço de ¥ 33.000, além de se inscrever nas taxas de associação mensal da Nintendo's e St. Giga. Como alternativa, os usuários podem alugar "sintonizadores de BS" de St. Giga por um período de 6 meses a um preço de ¥ 5.400. Mesmo a esse preço premium, a St. Giga registrou assinaturas atingidas em 116.378 famílias até março de 1997 e caindo para cerca de 46.000 em junho de 2001.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Peripheral</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ro_RO">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Satellaview este un modem de satelit periferic pentru sistemul Super Famicom al Nintendo care a fost lansat în Japonia în 1995. Disponibil pentru comenzi de pre-lansare începând cu 13 februarie 1995, Satellaview a fost vândut la un preț cuprins între ¥14,000 și 18,000 (la acea vreme între USD$141 și 182) și a venit la pachet cu BS-X Game Pak și un 8M Memory Pak. Sistemul Satellaview a fost dezvoltat și lansat de Nintendo pentru a recepționa semnalele transmise de filiala de radio prin satelit a postului de televiziune prin satelit WOWOW, St.GIGA. St.GIGA a fost responsabilă pentru gestionarea serverului de fișiere, întreținere și vocalizare pentru jocurile "SoundLink". Emisiunile de date Nintendo au beneficiat de un interval de timp fix, cunoscut sub numele de Ora Super Famicom, în timpul căruia datele codificate legate de Satellaview au fost transmise prin unde radio pentru a fi decriptate de "BS digital hi-vision TV" al St.GIGA. Fiind un post pe bază de abonament pentru muzică ambientală și New Age, ascultătorii St.GIGA erau deja dotați cu "tunere BS" înainte de contractul St.GIGA cu Nintendo. Proprietarii Satellaview care nu aveau un "BS tuner" trebuiau să achiziționeze unul separat de la St.GIGA, la un preț de 33 000 ¥, precum și să se înscrie la cotizațiile lunare comune ale Nintendo și St.GIGA. Ca alternativă, utilizatorii pot închiria "BS tuners" de la St.GIGA pentru o perioadă de 6 luni, la un preț de 5.400 de yeni. Chiar și la acest preț premium, St.GIGA a raportat că abonamentele au atins un maxim de 116 378 de gospodării până în martie 1997 și au scăzut la aproximativ 46 000 până în iunie 2001.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Periferic</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ru_RU">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Satellaview - периферийное устройство со спутниковым модемом для системы Super Famicom от Nintendo, выпущенное в Японии в 1995 году. Satellaview был доступен для предварительного заказа с 13 февраля 1995 года и продавался по цене от 14 000 до 18 000 иен (в то время от 141 до 182 долларов США) в комплекте с игровым пакетом BS-X и пакетом памяти 8M. Система Satellaview была разработана и выпущена Nintendo для приема сигналов, транслируемых спутниковой телестанцией WOWOW, дочерней компанией St.GIGA, занимающейся спутниковым радио. St.GIGA отвечала за управление файловым сервером, техническое обслуживание и озвучивание игр "SoundLink". Трансляции данных Nintendo отводился фиксированный временной интервал, известный как "Час Super Famicom", в течение которого скремблированные данные, связанные с Satellaview, передавались по радиоволнам, чтобы затем быть дешифрованными "BS digital hi-vision TV" St.GIGA. Слушатели St.GIGA, являющейся станцией эмбиент- и нью-эйдж-музыки по подписке, уже были оснащены "BS-тюнерами" до заключения контракта St.GIGA с Nintendo. Владельцы Satellaview, у которых не было "BS-тюнера", должны были приобретать его отдельно у St.GIGA по цене ¥33 000, а также подписываться на ежемесячные совместные членские взносы Nintendo и St.GIGA. В качестве альтернативы пользователи могут арендовать "BS-тюнеры" у St.GIGA на 6 месяцев по цене ¥5 400. Даже при такой высокой цене St.GIGA сообщила, что к марту 1997 года число подписчиков достигло 116 378, а к июню 2001 года снизилось примерно до 46 000.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Периферийное устройство</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sr_RS">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Сателит је сателитски модемски периферна периферна система Нинтендо-овог Супер Фамицом система који је 1995. године објављен у Јапану. На располагању за наређења пре ослобађања, са Сателлавиев-ом, са Сателлавиев је нашао између ¥ 14.000 и 18.000 (у време између УСД 141 и 182) и дошао је у пакетиран са БС-Кс играма и у пакетирању.Систем Сателлавиев је Нинтендо развио и објавио да прими сигнале емитује се са сателитске ТВ станице Вововов сателитска радио-подружница, Ст.Гига.Ст.Гига је био одговоран за управљање, одржавање и вокализацију датотека за "Соундлинк".Емитовање података Нинтендо дата су утор за одређено време познато као Супер Фамиком сата током којих су се промукли подаци повезани са сателитским сателавијом преносећи путем радио таласа да их нервирају Ст.Гига'с "БС Дигитал Хи-Висио"Као претплатничка станица за амбијенталну и новобуску музику, Ст.Гига слушатељи су већ били опремљени са "БС тјунерима" пре уговора о Ст.гигији са Нинтендо-ом.Власници сателиив који је недостајало "БС тјунера" морали су да купују једно одвојено од Ст.Гига по цени од ¥ 33.000, као и региструју се месечне чланице Нинтендо -она и Ст.Гиге.Алтернативно, корисници би могли да изнајме "БС тјунере" са Ст.гига на период од 6 месеци по цени од ¥ 5.400.Чак и на овој премиум цени, Ст.Гига је пријавила претплате на врхунцу на 116.378 домаћинстава до марта 1997. године и пала на око 46.000 до јуна 2001. године.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Периферни</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sv_SE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Satellaview är en satellitmodemutrustning för Nintendos Super Famicom-system som släpptes i Japan 1995. Satellaview kunde förbeställas från och med den 13 februari 1995 och såldes för mellan 14 000 och 18 000 yen (vid den tiden mellan 141 och 182 USD) och levererades tillsammans med BS-X Game Pak och ett 8M Memory Pak. Satellaview-systemet utvecklades och släpptes av Nintendo för att ta emot signaler som sändes från satellit-TV-stationen WOWOW:s satellitradiodotterbolag St.GIGA. St.GIGA ansvarade för hantering av filservern, underhåll och sång för "SoundLink"-spelen. Nintendos datasändningar gavs en fast tidslucka som kallades Super Famicom Hour under vilken krypterad Satellaview-relaterad data strömmade via radiovågor för att avkrypteras av St.GIGAs "BS digital hi-vision TV". Som en abonnemangsbaserad station för ambient och New Age-musik var St.GIGAs lyssnare redan utrustade med "BS-tuners" före St.GIGAs kontrakt med Nintendo. Satellaview-ägare som saknade en "BS-tuner" var tvungna att köpa en separat från St.GIGA till ett pris av 33.000 yen, samt anmäla sig till Nintendos och St.GIGAs gemensamma månatliga medlemsavgifter. Alternativt kunde användare hyra "BS-tuners" från St.GIGA under en 6-månadersperiod till ett pris av 5 400 yen. Även till detta premiumpris rapporterade St.GIGA att abonnemangen nådde en topp på 116.378 hushåll i mars 1997 och sjönk till cirka 46.000 i juni 2001.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Tillbehör</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_CN">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Satellaview 是任天堂超级 Famicom 系统的卫星调制解调器外设，于 1995 年在日本发售。Satellaview 于 1995 年 2 月 13 日开始接受预售订单，零售价在 14,000 日元至 18,000 日元之间（当时为 141 美元至 182 美元），与 BS-X 游戏包和 8M 内存包捆绑销售。任天堂开发并发布的 Satellaview 系统可接收卫星电视台 WOWOW 的卫星广播子公司 St.GIGA 播放的信号。St.GIGA 负责 "SoundLink "游戏的文件服务器管理、维护和发声。任天堂的数据广播有一个固定的时段，被称为 "超级 Famicom 小时"，在此期间，与卫星电视相关的加解密数据通过无线电波串流，由 St.GIGA 的 "BS 数字高清电视 "解码。作为一个提供氛围音乐和新世纪音乐的收费电台，St.GIGA 的听众在 St.GIGA 与任天堂签约之前就已经配备了 "BS 调谐器"。没有 "BS 调谐器 "的 Satellaview 用户必须以 3.3 万日元的价格向 St.GIGA 单独购买一个，并每月缴纳任天堂和 St.GIGA 的联合会员费。另外，用户也可以向 St.GIGA 租用为期 6 个月的 "BS 调谐器"，价格为 5400 日元。据 St.GIGA 报告，即使按这一高价计算，到 1997 年 3 月，用户数量也达到了 116,378 户，到 2001 年 6 月，用户数量下降到 46,000 户左右。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>外围设备</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_TW">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Satellaview 是任天堂 Super Famicom 系統的衛星數據機周邊設備，於 1995 年在日本發售。Satellaview 於 1995 年 2 月 13 日開始接受預購，零售價介於 14,000 日圓至 18,000 日圓（當時介於 141 美元至 182 美元之間）之間，並隨附 BS-X 遊戲包和 8M 記憶包。Satellaview 系統是任天堂為了接收衛星電視台 WOWOW 旗下衛星廣播子公司 St.GIGA 播放的訊號而開發推出的。St.GIGA 負責檔案伺服器的管理、維護，以及「SoundLink」遊戲的發聲。任天堂的資料廣播有一個固定的時段，稱為 Super Famicom Hour，在這段時間內，與 Satellaview 相關的擾碼資料會透過無線電波串流，由 St.GIGA 的 「BS 數位高畫質電視」 解碼。作為一個以訂閱為基礎的環境和新時代音樂電台，St.GIGA 的聽眾在 St.GIGA 與任天堂簽訂合約之前就已經配備了 「BS 調諧器」。沒有「BS tuner」的 Satellaview 使用者必須另外向 St.GIGA 購買，價格為 33,000 日圓，同時還必須加入任天堂與 St.GIGA 的聯合會員月費計劃。另外，使用者也可以向 St.GIGA 租用「BS tuner」，租期為 6 個月，價格為 5,400 日圓。即使以這個高價，St.GIGA報告的訂閱量在1997年3月達到116,378戶的高峰，到2001年6月則降至約46,000戶。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>周邊設備</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
</theme>
