<theme>
    <variables>
        <systemName>ZX81</systemName>
        <systemDescription>The ZX81 is a home computer that was produced by Sinclair Research and manufactured in Dundee, Scotland, by Timex Corporation. It was launched in the United Kingdom in March 1981 as the successor to Sinclair's ZX80 and designed to be a low-cost introduction to home computing for the general public. It was hugely successful; more than 1.5 million units were sold. In the United States it was initially sold as the ZX-81 under licence by Timex. Timex later produced its own versions of the ZX81: the Timex Sinclair 1000 and Timex Sinclair 1500. Unauthorized ZX81 clones were produced in several countries.

The ZX81 was designed to be small, simple, and above all, inexpensive, with as few components as possible. Video output is to a television set rather than a dedicated monitor. Programs and data are loaded and saved onto compact audio cassettes. It uses only four silicon chips and a mere 1 KB of memory. There is no power switch or any moving parts with the exception of a VHF TV channel selector switch present in some models. It has a pressure-sensitive membrane keyboard. The ZX81's limitations prompted a market in third-party peripherals to improve its capabilities. Its distinctive case and keyboard brought designer Rick Dickinson a Design Council award.

The ZX81 could be bought by mail order preassembled or, for a lower price, in kit form. It was the first inexpensive mass-market home computer to be sold by high street stores, led by W. H. Smith and soon many other retailers. The ZX81 marked the point when computing in Britain became an activity for the general public rather than the preserve of businessmen and electronics hobbyists. It produced a huge community of enthusiasts, some of whom founded their own businesses producing software and hardware for the ZX81. Many went on to play major roles in the British computer industry. The ZX81's commercial success made Sinclair Research one of Britain's leading computer manufacturers and earned a fortune and an eventual knighthood for the company's founder Sir Clive Sinclair.</systemDescription>
        <systemManufacturer>Sinclair</systemManufacturer>
        <systemReleaseYear>1981</systemReleaseYear>
        <systemReleaseDate>1981-03-05</systemReleaseDate>
        <systemReleaseDateFormated>March 5, 1981</systemReleaseDateFormated>
        <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        <systemCoverSize>3-4</systemCoverSize>
        <systemCoverSizeType>portrait</systemCoverSizeType>
        <systemColor>B92E34</systemColor>
        <systemColorPalette1>EF5857</systemColorPalette1>
        <systemColorPalette2>403E4B</systemColorPalette2>
        <systemColorPalette3>D2CECD</systemColorPalette3>
        <systemColorPalette4>191222</systemColorPalette4>
        <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
    </variables>
    <language name="ar_SA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>ZX81 هو كمبيوتر منزلي أنتجته شركة سنكلير للأبحاث وصنعته شركة تايمكس في دندي باسكتلندا. وقد تم إطلاقه في المملكة المتحدة في مارس 1981 كخليفة لسنكلير ZX80، وصُمم ليكون مقدمة منخفضة التكلفة للحوسبة المنزلية لعامة الناس. وقد حقق نجاحًا كبيرًا؛ حيث تم بيع أكثر من 1.5 مليون وحدة منه. في الولايات المتحدة تم بيعه في البداية باسم ZX-81 بموجب ترخيص من Timex. أنتجت Timex لاحقًا إصداراتها الخاصة من ZX81: Timex Sinclair 1000 وTimex Sinclair 1500. وتم إنتاج نسخ غير مرخصة من ZX81 في عدة بلدان.

صُممت ZX81 لتكون صغيرة وبسيطة وفوق كل ذلك غير مكلفة، مع أقل عدد ممكن من المكونات. يتم إخراج الفيديو إلى جهاز تلفاز بدلاً من شاشة مخصصة. يتم تحميل البرامج والبيانات وحفظها على أشرطة صوتية مدمجة. ويستخدم أربع شرائح سيليكون فقط وذاكرة بسعة 1 كيلوبايت فقط. لا يوجد مفتاح طاقة أو أي أجزاء متحركة باستثناء مفتاح اختيار قناة تلفزيونية ذات تردد عالٍ جداً موجود في بعض الطرازات. ويحتوي على لوحة مفاتيح غشائية حساسة للضغط. دفعت محدودية ZX81 إلى ظهور سوق في الأجهزة الطرفية الخارجية لتحسين قدراته. وقد جلبت غلافه المميز ولوحة المفاتيح المميزة للمصمم ريك ديكنسون جائزة مجلس التصميم.

يمكن شراء ZX81 عن طريق طلب الشراء بالبريد مُجمَّعًا مسبقًا أو بسعر أقل في شكل مجموعة أدوات. وقد كان أول كمبيوتر منزلي رخيص الثمن يباع في المتاجر الكبرى وعلى رأسها W. H. Smith، وسرعان ما تم بيعه من قبل العديد من تجار التجزئة الآخرين. كان حاسوب ZX81 علامة على النقطة التي أصبحت فيها الحوسبة في بريطانيا نشاطًا لعامة الناس بدلاً من أن تكون حكرًا على رجال الأعمال وهواة الإلكترونيات. فقد أنتجت مجتمعاً ضخماً من المتحمسين، الذين أسس بعضهم شركاتهم الخاصة لإنتاج البرمجيات والأجهزة الخاصة بال ZX81. واستمر العديد منهم في لعب أدوار رئيسية في صناعة الكمبيوتر البريطانية. جعل النجاح التجاري الذي حققه جهاز ZX81 من شركة Sinclair Research إحدى الشركات الرائدة في بريطانيا في مجال تصنيع الحواسيب وحقق ثروة كبيرة وحصل مؤسس الشركة السير كلايف سينكلير على لقب فارس.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>الحاسب الآلي</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="bs_BA">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>The ZX81 is a home computer that was produced by Sinclair Research and manufactured in Dundee, Scotland, by Timex Corporation. It was launched in the United Kingdom in March 1981 as the successor to Sinclair's ZX80 and designed to be a low-cost introduction to home computing for the general public. It was hugely successful; more than 1.5 million units were sold. In the United States it was initially sold as the ZX-81 under licence by Timex. Timex later produced its own versions of the ZX81: the Timex Sinclair 1000 and Timex Sinclair 1500. Unauthorized ZX81 clones were produced in several countries.

The ZX81 was designed to be small, simple, and above all, inexpensive, with as few components as possible. Video output is to a television set rather than a dedicated monitor. Programs and data are loaded and saved onto compact audio cassettes. It uses only four silicon chips and a mere 1 KB of memory. There is no power switch or any moving parts with the exception of a VHF TV channel selector switch present in some models. It has a pressure-sensitive membrane keyboard. The ZX81's limitations prompted a market in third-party peripherals to improve its capabilities. Its distinctive case and keyboard brought designer Rick Dickinson a Design Council award.

The ZX81 could be bought by mail order preassembled or, for a lower price, in kit form. It was the first inexpensive mass-market home computer to be sold by high street stores, led by W. H. Smith and soon many other retailers. The ZX81 marked the point when computing in Britain became an activity for the general public rather than the preserve of businessmen and electronics hobbyists. It produced a huge community of enthusiasts, some of whom founded their own businesses producing software and hardware for the ZX81. Many went on to play major roles in the British computer industry. The ZX81's commercial success made Sinclair Research one of Britain's leading computer manufacturers and earned a fortune and an eventual knighthood for the company's founder Sir Clive Sinclair.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ca_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>El ZX81 és un ordinador domèstic produït per Sinclair Research i fabricat a Dundee, Escòcia, per Timex Corporation. Va ser llançat al Regne Unit el març de 1981 com a successor de la ZX80 de Sinclair i dissenyat per ser una introducció de baix cost a la informàtica domèstica per al públic en general. Va tenir un gran èxit;Es van vendre més d’1,5 milions d’unitats. Als Estats Units es va vendre inicialment com a ZX-81 sota llicència per TIMEX. Timex va produir més tard les seves pròpies versions del ZX81: Timex Sinclair 1000 i Timex Sinclair 1500. Els clons ZX81 no autoritzats es van produir en diversos països.

El ZX81 va ser dissenyat per ser petit, senzill i sobretot, barat, amb el mínim de components possibles. La sortida de vídeo és a un televisor en lloc d’un monitor dedicat. Els programes i les dades es carreguen i es guarden en cassets d'àudio compactes. Utilitza només quatre xips de silici i només 1 kb de memòria. No hi ha cap interruptor de potència ni parts mòbils a excepció d’un commutador de selecció de canals VHF TV present en alguns models. Té un teclat de membrana sensible a la pressió. Les limitacions del ZX81 van provocar un mercat en perifèrics de tercers a millorar les seves capacitats. El seu estoig i el teclat distintiu van portar al dissenyador Rick Dickinson un premi del Consell de Disseny.

El ZX81 es podria comprar per ordre de correu previsat o, per un preu més baix, en forma de kit. Va ser el primer ordinador domèstic de mercat massiu barat que va ser venut per botigues de carrer, dirigit per W. H. Smith i aviat molts altres minoristes. El ZX81 va marcar el punt en què la informàtica a Gran Bretanya es va convertir en una activitat per al públic en general en lloc de la preservació dels empresaris i els aficionats a l'electrònica. Va produir una enorme comunitat d'entusiastes, alguns dels quals van fundar els seus propis negocis produint programari i maquinari per al ZX81. Molts van continuar jugant a un paper important en la indústria informàtica britànica. L’èxit comercial del ZX81 va fer que Sinclair Research fos un dels principals fabricants d’ordinadors britànics i va obtenir una fortuna i un eventual cavaller per al fundador de la companyia, Sir Clive Sinclair.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="de_DE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Der ZX81 ist ein Heimcomputer, der von Sinclair Research produziert und in Dundee, Schottland, von der Timex Corporation hergestellt wurde. Er wurde im März 1981 im Vereinigten Königreich als Nachfolger des Sinclair ZX80 auf den Markt gebracht und war als preiswerter Einstieg in die Heimcomputertechnik für die breite Öffentlichkeit gedacht. Er war ein großer Erfolg; mehr als 1,5 Millionen Geräte wurden verkauft. In den Vereinigten Staaten wurde er zunächst als ZX-81 unter Lizenz von Timex verkauft. Später produzierte Timex seine eigenen Versionen des ZX81: den Timex Sinclair 1000 und den Timex Sinclair 1500. In mehreren Ländern wurden nicht autorisierte ZX81-Klone hergestellt.

Der ZX81 wurde so konzipiert, dass er klein, einfach und vor allem preiswert ist und möglichst wenige Komponenten enthält. Die Videoausgabe erfolgt über ein Fernsehgerät und nicht über einen eigenen Monitor. Programme und Daten werden auf kompakte Audiokassetten geladen und gespeichert. Es werden nur vier Siliziumchips und ein Speicher von nur 1 KB verwendet. Es gibt keinen Netzschalter und keine beweglichen Teile, mit Ausnahme eines UKW-Fernsehkanal-Wahlschalters, der bei einigen Modellen vorhanden ist. Er hat eine druckempfindliche Membrantastatur. Die Einschränkungen des ZX81 führten dazu, dass ein Markt für Peripheriegeräte von Drittanbietern entstand, um seine Fähigkeiten zu verbessern. Das unverwechselbare Gehäuse und die Tastatur brachten dem Designer Rick Dickinson eine Auszeichnung des Design Council ein.

Der ZX81 konnte im Versandhandel vormontiert oder zu einem niedrigeren Preis als Bausatz erworben werden. Er war der erste preisgünstige Heimcomputer für den Massenmarkt, der von großen Einzelhändlern verkauft wurde, allen voran von W. H. Smith und bald auch von vielen anderen Einzelhändlern. Der ZX81 markierte den Punkt, an dem der Computer in Großbritannien zu einer Aktivität für die breite Öffentlichkeit wurde und nicht mehr nur Geschäftsleuten und Elektronikhobbyisten vorbehalten war. Es entstand eine große Gemeinschaft von Enthusiasten, von denen einige ihre eigenen Unternehmen gründeten, die Software und Hardware für den ZX81 produzierten. Viele von ihnen spielten später eine wichtige Rolle in der britischen Computerindustrie. Der kommerzielle Erfolg des ZX81 machte Sinclair Research zu einem der führenden Computerhersteller Großbritanniens und brachte dem Firmengründer Sir Clive Sinclair ein Vermögen und schließlich den Ritterschlag ein.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="es_ES">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>El ZX81 es un ordenador doméstico producido por Sinclair Research y fabricado en Dundee, Escocia, por Timex Corporation. Fue lanzado en el Reino Unido en marzo de 1981 como sucesor del ZX80 de Sinclair y diseñado para ser una introducción de bajo coste a la informática doméstica para el público en general. Tuvo un gran éxito: se vendieron más de 1,5 millones de unidades. En Estados Unidos se vendió inicialmente como ZX-81 bajo licencia de Timex. Posteriormente, Timex fabricó sus propias versiones del ZX81: el Timex Sinclair 1000 y el Timex Sinclair 1500. En varios países se fabricaron clones no autorizados del ZX81.

El ZX81 fue diseñado para ser pequeño, sencillo y, sobre todo, barato, con el menor número de componentes posible. La salida de vídeo se realiza a un televisor en lugar de a un monitor dedicado. Los programas y los datos se cargan y guardan en cintas de audio compactas. Sólo utiliza cuatro chips de silicio y 1 KB de memoria. No tiene interruptor de encendido ni piezas móviles, a excepción de un selector de canales de TV VHF presente en algunos modelos. Dispone de un teclado de membrana sensible a la presión. Las limitaciones del ZX81 impulsaron un mercado de periféricos de terceros para mejorar sus capacidades. Su distintiva carcasa y teclado valieron al diseñador Rick Dickinson un premio del Consejo de Diseño.

El ZX81 podía adquirirse por correo ya montado o, por un precio inferior, en forma de kit. Fue el primer ordenador doméstico de bajo coste para el gran público que se vendió en las grandes superficies, encabezadas por W. H. Smith y pronto por muchos otros minoristas. El ZX81 marcó el momento en que la informática en Gran Bretaña se convirtió en una actividad para el público en general, en lugar de ser el coto privado de empresarios y aficionados a la electrónica. Generó una enorme comunidad de entusiastas, algunos de los cuales fundaron sus propias empresas para producir software y hardware para el ZX81. Muchos de ellos llegaron a desempeñar un papel importante en la industria informática británica. El éxito comercial del ZX81 convirtió a Sinclair Research en uno de los principales fabricantes británicos de ordenadores y le valió una fortuna y el título de caballero a su fundador, Sir Clive Sinclair.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Ordenador</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="fr_FR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Le ZX81 est un ordinateur domestique produit par Sinclair Research et fabriqué à Dundee, en Écosse, par Timex Corporation. Il a été lancé au Royaume-Uni en mars 1981 comme successeur du ZX80 de Sinclair et a été conçu pour être une introduction peu coûteuse à l'informatique domestique pour le grand public. Il a connu un énorme succès : plus de 1,5 million d'unités ont été vendues. Aux États-Unis, il a d'abord été vendu sous le nom de ZX-81, sous licence de Timex. Timex a ensuite produit ses propres versions du ZX81 : le Timex Sinclair 1000 et le Timex Sinclair 1500. Des clones non autorisés du ZX81 ont été produits dans plusieurs pays.

Le ZX81 a été conçu pour être petit, simple et surtout bon marché, avec le moins de composants possible. La sortie vidéo se fait vers un téléviseur plutôt que vers un moniteur dédié. Les programmes et les données sont chargés et sauvegardés sur des cassettes audio compactes. Il n'utilise que quatre puces de silicium et seulement 1 Ko de mémoire. Il n'y a pas d'interrupteur d'alimentation ni de pièces mobiles, à l'exception d'un sélecteur de canal TV VHF présent sur certains modèles. Il est doté d'un clavier à membrane sensible à la pression. Les limites du ZX81 ont suscité l'apparition d'un marché de périphériques tiers destinés à améliorer ses capacités. Son boîtier et son clavier distinctifs ont valu au concepteur Rick Dickinson un prix du Design Council.

Le ZX81 pouvait être acheté par correspondance préassemblé ou, pour un prix inférieur, en kit. Il a été le premier ordinateur domestique bon marché à être vendu dans les magasins à grande surface, à commencer par W. H. Smith et bientôt de nombreux autres détaillants. Le ZX81 a marqué le moment où l'informatique en Grande-Bretagne est devenue une activité pour le grand public plutôt que la chasse gardée des hommes d'affaires et des amateurs d'électronique. Il a donné naissance à une vaste communauté de passionnés, dont certains ont fondé leur propre entreprise de production de logiciels et de matériel pour le ZX81. Nombre d'entre eux ont ensuite joué un rôle majeur dans l'industrie informatique britannique. Le succès commercial du ZX81 a fait de Sinclair Research l'un des principaux fabricants britanniques d'ordinateurs et a permis à son fondateur, Sir Clive Sinclair, de gagner une fortune et d'être fait chevalier.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Ordinateur</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="hr_HR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>The ZX81 is a home computer that was produced by Sinclair Research and manufactured in Dundee, Scotland, by Timex Corporation. It was launched in the United Kingdom in March 1981 as the successor to Sinclair's ZX80 and designed to be a low-cost introduction to home computing for the general public. It was hugely successful; more than 1.5 million units were sold. In the United States it was initially sold as the ZX-81 under licence by Timex. Timex later produced its own versions of the ZX81: the Timex Sinclair 1000 and Timex Sinclair 1500. Unauthorized ZX81 clones were produced in several countries.

The ZX81 was designed to be small, simple, and above all, inexpensive, with as few components as possible. Video output is to a television set rather than a dedicated monitor. Programs and data are loaded and saved onto compact audio cassettes. It uses only four silicon chips and a mere 1 KB of memory. There is no power switch or any moving parts with the exception of a VHF TV channel selector switch present in some models. It has a pressure-sensitive membrane keyboard. The ZX81's limitations prompted a market in third-party peripherals to improve its capabilities. Its distinctive case and keyboard brought designer Rick Dickinson a Design Council award.

The ZX81 could be bought by mail order preassembled or, for a lower price, in kit form. It was the first inexpensive mass-market home computer to be sold by high street stores, led by W. H. Smith and soon many other retailers. The ZX81 marked the point when computing in Britain became an activity for the general public rather than the preserve of businessmen and electronics hobbyists. It produced a huge community of enthusiasts, some of whom founded their own businesses producing software and hardware for the ZX81. Many went on to play major roles in the British computer industry. The ZX81's commercial success made Sinclair Research one of Britain's leading computer manufacturers and earned a fortune and an eventual knighthood for the company's founder Sir Clive Sinclair.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="it_IT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>Lo ZX81 è un home computer prodotto da Sinclair Research e fabbricato a Dundee, in Scozia, da Timex Corporation. Fu lanciato nel Regno Unito nel marzo 1981 come successore dello ZX80 di Sinclair e progettato per essere un'introduzione a basso costo all'home computing per il grande pubblico. Il successo fu enorme: ne furono vendute più di 1,5 milioni di unità. Negli Stati Uniti fu inizialmente venduto come ZX-81 su licenza di Timex. In seguito Timex produsse le proprie versioni dello ZX81: il Timex Sinclair 1000 e il Timex Sinclair 1500. In diversi paesi furono prodotti cloni non autorizzati dello ZX81.

Lo ZX81 fu progettato per essere piccolo, semplice e soprattutto economico, con il minor numero possibile di componenti. L'uscita video è destinata a un televisore piuttosto che a un monitor dedicato. I programmi e i dati vengono caricati e salvati su cassette audio compatte. Utilizza solo quattro chip di silicio e una memoria di appena 1 KB. Non ci sono interruttori di accensione né parti mobili, ad eccezione di un selettore di canali televisivi VHF presente in alcuni modelli. Ha una tastiera a membrana sensibile alla pressione. Le limitazioni dello ZX81 hanno stimolato un mercato di periferiche di terze parti per migliorarne le capacità. Il suo caratteristico case e la sua tastiera sono valsi al progettista Rick Dickinson un premio del Design Council.

Lo ZX81 poteva essere acquistato per corrispondenza già assemblato o, a un prezzo inferiore, in kit. Fu il primo home computer economico di massa a essere venduto nei negozi di strada, guidati da W. H. Smith e presto da molti altri rivenditori. Lo ZX81 segnò il momento in cui l'informatica in Gran Bretagna divenne un'attività per il grande pubblico, anziché essere appannaggio di uomini d'affari e hobbisti dell'elettronica. Si creò un'enorme comunità di appassionati, alcuni dei quali fondarono le proprie aziende producendo software e hardware per lo ZX81. Molti di loro hanno poi ricoperto ruoli importanti nell'industria informatica britannica. Il successo commerciale dello ZX81 rese Sinclair Research uno dei principali produttori di computer della Gran Bretagna e fece guadagnare una fortuna e un cavalierato al fondatore dell'azienda, Sir Clive Sinclair.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ja_JP">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>ZX81は、シンクレア・リサーチ社が製造し、タイメックス社がスコットランドのダンディーで製造した家庭用コンピュータである。1981年3月、シンクレアのZX80の後継機として英国で発売され、一般消費者向けの低価格なホームコンピューティング入門機として設計された。大成功を収め、150万台以上が販売された。米国では当初、タイメックスのライセンスによりZX-81として販売された。その後、タイメックスはZX81の独自バージョンであるTimex Sinclair 1000とTimex Sinclair 1500を製造した。いくつかの国でZX81のクローンが製造された。

ZX81は、小型でシンプル、そして何よりも安価で、部品点数をできるだけ少なくするように設計された。ビデオ出力は専用モニターではなくテレビに接続する。プログラムとデータはコンパクト・オーディオ・カセットにロードして保存する。使用するシリコンチップは4つだけで、メモリはわずか1KB。電源スイッチや可動部品はなく、一部のモデルにあるVHFテレビ・チャンネル・セレクタ・スイッチを除いては、何もない。キーボードは感圧式のメンブレン式である。ZX81の限界は、その機能を向上させるためにサードパーティの周辺機器市場を促した。その特徴的なケースとキーボードは、デザイナーのリック・ディッキンソンにデザイン・カウンシル賞をもたらした。

ZX81は通信販売で組み立てた状態で購入できたが、低価格のキット形式でも購入できた。ZX81は、W.H.スミスを筆頭とするハイストリートストアが販売した最初の安価な大衆向け家庭用コンピュータであり、やがて他の多くの小売店でも販売されるようになった。ZX81は、英国でコンピュータがビジネスマンや電子工学の趣味愛好家だけのものでなく、一般大衆の活動として定着するきっかけとなった。ZX81は巨大な熱狂的ファンを生み出し、その中にはZX81用のソフトウェアやハードウェアを製造するビジネスを立ち上げた者もいた。その多くは、英国のコンピューター産業で大きな役割を果たすようになった。ZX81の商業的成功により、シンクレア・リサーチは英国を代表するコンピューター・メーカーのひとつとなり、巨万の富を築き、創業者のクライヴ・シンクレア卿は爵位を授与された。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>コンピューター</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ko_KR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>ZX81은 싱클레어 리서치에서 생산하고 스코틀랜드 던디에 있는 티멕스 코퍼레이션에서 제조한 가정용 컴퓨터입니다. 1981년 3월 영국에서 Sinclair의 ZX80의 후속 제품으로 출시되었으며, 일반 대중을 위한 저렴한 가정용 컴퓨터 입문용으로 설계되었습니다. 이 제품은 150만 대 이상 판매되며 큰 성공을 거두었습니다. 미국에서는 처음에는 Timex의 라이선스를 받아 ZX-81이라는 이름으로 판매되었습니다. 이후 Timex는 자체적으로 ZX81 버전인 Timex Sinclair 1000과 Timex Sinclair 1500을 생산했습니다. 여러 국가에서 승인되지 않은 ZX81 복제품이 생산되었습니다.

ZX81은 가능한 한 적은 수의 부품으로 작고 단순하며 무엇보다도 저렴하게 설계되었습니다. 비디오 출력은 전용 모니터가 아닌 텔레비전 세트에 연결됩니다. 프로그램과 데이터는 소형 오디오 카세트에 로드 및 저장됩니다. 4개의 실리콘 칩과 단 1KB의 메모리만 사용합니다. 일부 모델에 있는 VHF TV 채널 선택 스위치를 제외하고는 전원 스위치나 움직이는 부품이 없습니다. 감압식 멤브레인 키보드가 있습니다. ZX81의 한계로 인해 타사 주변기기 시장에서 기능을 개선한 제품이 출시되었습니다. 독특한 케이스와 키보드로 디자이너 릭 디킨슨은 디자인 위원회에서 상을 받았습니다.

ZX81은 사전 조립된 상태로 우편 주문하거나 더 저렴한 가격으로 키트 형태로 구입할 수 있었습니다. 이 제품은 W. H. Smith를 필두로 곧 다른 많은 소매업체에서 판매하기 시작한 최초의 저렴한 대중 시장 가정용 컴퓨터였습니다. ZX81은 영국에서 컴퓨터가 사업가나 전자제품 애호가들의 전유물이 아닌 일반 대중을 위한 활동이 된 시점이었습니다. 이 제품은 거대한 매니아 커뮤니티를 형성했고, 그 중 일부는 ZX81용 소프트웨어와 하드웨어를 생산하는 회사를 설립했습니다. 많은 사람들이 영국 컴퓨터 산업에서 중요한 역할을 맡게 되었습니다. ZX81의 상업적 성공으로 Sinclair Research는 영국을 대표하는 컴퓨터 제조업체 중 하나가 되었고, 회사 설립자인 클라이브 싱클레어 경은 많은 부를 얻었으며 결국 기사 작위를 받았습니다.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>컴퓨터</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="nl_NL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>De ZX81 is een thuiscomputer die werd geproduceerd door Sinclair Research en vervaardigd in Dundee, Schotland, door Timex Corporation. Hij werd in maart 1981 in het Verenigd Koninkrijk gelanceerd als opvolger van de ZX80 van Sinclair en was bedoeld als een goedkope introductie tot thuiscomputers voor het grote publiek. Het was een enorm succes; er werden meer dan 1,5 miljoen exemplaren van verkocht. In de Verenigde Staten werd het in eerste instantie verkocht als de ZX-81 onder licentie door Timex. Timex produceerde later zijn eigen versies van de ZX81: de Timex Sinclair 1000 en Timex Sinclair 1500. Niet-geautoriseerde ZX81 klonen werden geproduceerd in verschillende landen.

De ZX81 was ontworpen om klein, eenvoudig en vooral goedkoop te zijn, met zo weinig mogelijk componenten. De video-uitgang gaat naar een televisietoestel in plaats van naar een speciale monitor. Programma's en gegevens worden geladen en opgeslagen op compacte audiocassettes. Er worden slechts vier siliciumchips gebruikt en slechts 1 KB geheugen. Er zijn geen aan/uit-schakelaar of bewegende delen, met uitzondering van een VHF TV kanaalkeuzeschakelaar in sommige modellen. Het heeft een drukgevoelig membraantoetsenbord. De beperkingen van de ZX81 leidden tot een markt van randapparatuur van derden om de mogelijkheden te verbeteren. De opvallende behuizing en het toetsenbord leverden de ontwerper Rick Dickinson een Design Council award op.

De ZX81 kon per postorder worden gekocht, voorgemonteerd of, voor een lagere prijs, in kitvorm. Het was de eerste goedkope thuiscomputer voor de massamarkt die door winkels in winkelstraten werd verkocht, aangevoerd door W. H. Smith en al snel door vele andere retailers. De ZX81 markeerde het punt waarop computergebruik in Groot-Brittannië een activiteit voor het grote publiek werd in plaats van het domein van zakenmensen en elektronicahobbyisten. Er ontstond een enorme gemeenschap van enthousiastelingen, waarvan sommigen hun eigen bedrijf oprichtten om software en hardware voor de ZX81 te produceren. Velen gingen een belangrijke rol spelen in de Britse computerindustrie. Het commerciële succes van de ZX81 maakte van Sinclair Research een van de belangrijkste computerfabrikanten van Groot-Brittannië en leverde de oprichter van het bedrijf, Sir Clive Sinclair, een fortuin en uiteindelijk een ridderorde op.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pl_PL">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>ZX81 to komputer domowy wyprodukowany przez Sinclair Research i wyprodukowany w Dundee w Szkocji przez Timex Corporation. Został wprowadzony na rynek w Wielkiej Brytanii w marcu 1981 roku jako następca ZX80 firmy Sinclair i zaprojektowany jako niedrogie wprowadzenie do komputerów domowych dla ogółu społeczeństwa. Odniósł ogromny sukces; sprzedano ponad 1,5 miliona sztuk. W Stanach Zjednoczonych był początkowo sprzedawany jako ZX-81 na licencji Timex. Później Timex wyprodukował własne wersje ZX81: Timex Sinclair 1000 i Timex Sinclair 1500. Nieautoryzowane klony ZX81 były produkowane w kilku krajach.

ZX81 został zaprojektowany tak, aby był mały, prosty, a przede wszystkim niedrogi, z jak najmniejszą liczbą komponentów. Wyjście wideo jest kierowane do telewizora, a nie do dedykowanego monitora. Programy i dane są ładowane i zapisywane na kompaktowych kasetach audio. Wykorzystuje tylko cztery krzemowe chipy i zaledwie 1 KB pamięci. Nie ma wyłącznika zasilania ani żadnych ruchomych części, z wyjątkiem przełącznika wyboru kanału telewizyjnego VHF obecnego w niektórych modelach. Posiada czułą na nacisk klawiaturę membranową. Ograniczenia ZX81 doprowadziły do powstania rynku urządzeń peryferyjnych innych producentów, które poprawiły jego możliwości. Jego charakterystyczna obudowa i klawiatura przyniosły projektantowi Rickowi Dickinsonowi nagrodę Design Council.

ZX81 można było kupić w sprzedaży wysyłkowej w postaci wstępnie zmontowanej lub, za niższą cenę, w formie zestawu. Był to pierwszy niedrogi komputer domowy przeznaczony na rynek masowy, który był sprzedawany przez sklepy wielkopowierzchniowe, na czele z W. H. Smith, a wkrótce także przez wielu innych sprzedawców detalicznych. ZX81 wyznaczył punkt, w którym informatyka w Wielkiej Brytanii stała się aktywnością dla ogółu społeczeństwa, a nie domeną biznesmenów i hobbystów elektroniki. Stworzyło to ogromną społeczność entuzjastów, z których niektórzy założyli własne firmy produkujące oprogramowanie i sprzęt dla ZX81. Wielu z nich odegrało następnie znaczące role w brytyjskim przemyśle komputerowym. Komercyjny sukces ZX81 sprawił, że Sinclair Research stał się jednym z wiodących brytyjskich producentów komputerów i dorobił się fortuny oraz tytułu szlacheckiego dla założyciela firmy, Sir Clive'a Sinclaira.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Komputer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_BR">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>O ZX81 é um computador doméstico produzido pela Sinclair Research e fabricado em Dundee, Escócia, pela Timex Corporation. Foi lançado no Reino Unido em março de 1981 como o sucessor do ZX80 da Sinclair e projetado para ser uma introdução de baixo custo à computação doméstica para o público em geral. Foi um enorme sucesso; mais de 1,5 milhão de unidades foram vendidas. Nos Estados Unidos, ele foi inicialmente vendido como ZX-81 sob licença da Timex. Posteriormente, a Timex produziu suas próprias versões do ZX81: o Timex Sinclair 1000 e o Timex Sinclair 1500. Clones não autorizados do ZX81 foram produzidos em vários países.

O ZX81 foi projetado para ser pequeno, simples e, acima de tudo, barato, com o menor número possível de componentes. A saída de vídeo é para um aparelho de televisão em vez de um monitor dedicado. Os programas e dados são carregados e salvos em cassetes de áudio compactos. Ele usa apenas quatro chips de silício e apenas 1 KB de memória. Não há chave liga/desliga nem peças móveis, com exceção de uma chave seletora de canais de TV VHF presente em alguns modelos. Ele tem um teclado de membrana sensível à pressão. As limitações do ZX81 levaram a um mercado de periféricos de terceiros para melhorar seus recursos. Seu gabinete e teclado diferenciados renderam ao designer Rick Dickinson um prêmio do Design Council.

O ZX81 podia ser comprado por correio, pré-montado ou, por um preço menor, em forma de kit. Foi o primeiro computador doméstico de baixo custo para o mercado de massa a ser vendido em lojas de rua, lideradas pela W. H. Smith e, em breve, por muitos outros varejistas. O ZX81 marcou o momento em que a computação na Grã-Bretanha se tornou uma atividade para o público em geral, em vez de ser uma exclusividade de empresários e entusiastas da eletrônica. Ele gerou uma enorme comunidade de entusiastas, alguns dos quais fundaram suas próprias empresas produzindo software e hardware para o ZX81. Muitos passaram a desempenhar papéis importantes no setor britânico de computadores. O sucesso comercial do ZX81 fez da Sinclair Research um dos principais fabricantes de computadores da Grã-Bretanha e rendeu uma fortuna e um título de cavaleiro ao fundador da empresa, Sir Clive Sinclair.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computador</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="pt_PT">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>The ZX81 is a home computer that was produced by Sinclair Research and manufactured in Dundee, Scotland, by Timex Corporation. It was launched in the United Kingdom in March 1981 as the successor to Sinclair's ZX80 and designed to be a low-cost introduction to home computing for the general public. It was hugely successful; more than 1.5 million units were sold. In the United States it was initially sold as the ZX-81 under licence by Timex. Timex later produced its own versions of the ZX81: the Timex Sinclair 1000 and Timex Sinclair 1500. Unauthorized ZX81 clones were produced in several countries.

The ZX81 was designed to be small, simple, and above all, inexpensive, with as few components as possible. Video output is to a television set rather than a dedicated monitor. Programs and data are loaded and saved onto compact audio cassettes. It uses only four silicon chips and a mere 1 KB of memory. There is no power switch or any moving parts with the exception of a VHF TV channel selector switch present in some models. It has a pressure-sensitive membrane keyboard. The ZX81's limitations prompted a market in third-party peripherals to improve its capabilities. Its distinctive case and keyboard brought designer Rick Dickinson a Design Council award.

The ZX81 could be bought by mail order preassembled or, for a lower price, in kit form. It was the first inexpensive mass-market home computer to be sold by high street stores, led by W. H. Smith and soon many other retailers. The ZX81 marked the point when computing in Britain became an activity for the general public rather than the preserve of businessmen and electronics hobbyists. It produced a huge community of enthusiasts, some of whom founded their own businesses producing software and hardware for the ZX81. Many went on to play major roles in the British computer industry. The ZX81's commercial success made Sinclair Research one of Britain's leading computer manufacturers and earned a fortune and an eventual knighthood for the company's founder Sir Clive Sinclair.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ro_RO">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>ZX81 este un computer de casă produs de Sinclair Research și fabricat în Dundee, Scoția, de Timex Corporation. Acesta a fost lansat în Regatul Unit în martie 1981 ca succesor al lui Sinclair ZX80 și a fost conceput pentru a fi o introducere la un cost redus la calculatoarele de acasă pentru publicul larg. A avut un succes enorm; au fost vândute mai mult de 1,5 milioane de unități. În Statele Unite a fost vândut inițial ca ZX-81 sub licență Timex. Timex a produs ulterior propriile sale versiuni ale ZX81: Timex Sinclair 1000 și Timex Sinclair 1500. Clone neautorizate ale ZX81 au fost produse în mai multe țări.

ZX81 a fost proiectat să fie mic, simplu și, mai presus de toate, ieftin, cu cât mai puține componente posibil. Ieșirea video se face către un televizor și nu către un monitor dedicat. Programele și datele sunt încărcate și salvate pe casete audio compacte. Utilizează doar patru cipuri de siliciu și doar 1 KB de memorie. Nu are întrerupător de alimentare sau părți mobile, cu excepția unui comutator de selectare a canalului TV VHF prezent la unele modele. Are o tastatură cu membrană sensibilă la presiune. Limitările ZX81 au generat o piață a perifericelor terțe pentru îmbunătățirea capacităților sale. Carcasa distinctivă și tastatura i-au adus designerului Rick Dickinson un premiu Design Council.

ZX81 putea fi cumpărat prin poștă preasamblat sau, pentru un preț mai mic, sub formă de kit. A fost primul computer de masă ieftin vândut de magazinele de top, conduse de W. H. Smith și, în curând, de mulți alți comercianți. ZX81 a marcat momentul în care calculul în Marea Britanie a devenit o activitate pentru publicul larg, mai degrabă decât apanajul oamenilor de afaceri și al pasionaților de electronică. Acesta a generat o comunitate imensă de entuziaști, dintre care unii și-au fondat propriile afaceri care produceau software și hardware pentru ZX81. Mulți au ajuns să joace roluri importante în industria britanică a calculatoarelor. Succesul comercial al ZX81 a făcut din Sinclair Research unul dintre cei mai importanți producători de computere din Marea Britanie și i-a adus fondatorului companiei, Sir Clive Sinclair, o avere și un titlu de cavaler.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="ru_RU">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>ZX81 - это домашний компьютер, выпущенный компанией Sinclair Research и произведенный в Данди, Шотландия, корпорацией Timex. Он был выпущен в Великобритании в марте 1981 года как преемник Sinclair ZX80 и был задуман как недорогое введение в домашние компьютеры для широкой публики. Он пользовался огромным успехом; было продано более 1,5 миллиона устройств. В Соединенных Штатах он первоначально продавался под названием ZX-81 по лицензии компании Timex. Позже компания Timex выпустила свои собственные версии ZX81: Timex Sinclair 1000 и Timex Sinclair 1500. В некоторых странах выпускались неавторизованные клоны ZX81.

ZX81 был разработан, чтобы быть маленьким, простым и, прежде всего, недорогим, с как можно меньшим количеством компонентов. Видеовыход выводится на телевизор, а не на специальный монитор. Программы и данные загружаются и сохраняются на компактных аудиокассетах. В устройстве используется всего четыре кремниевых чипа и всего 1 КБ памяти. Нет ни выключателя питания, ни каких-либо движущихся частей, за исключением переключателя селектора каналов УКВ-телевидения, присутствующего в некоторых моделях. Клавиатура выполнена в виде чувствительной к нажатию мембраны. Ограничения ZX81 привели к появлению рынка периферийных устройств сторонних производителей, призванных расширить его возможности. Его характерный корпус и клавиатура принесли дизайнеру Рику Дикинсону награду Совета по дизайну.

ZX81 можно было купить по почте в собранном виде или, по более низкой цене, в виде набора. Это был первый недорогой домашний компьютер массового спроса, который продавался в магазинах на улицах, возглавляемых компанией W. H. Smith, а вскоре и многими другими ритейлерами. ZX81 ознаменовал собой момент, когда компьютерная техника в Британии стала занятием для широкой публики, а не уделом бизнесменов и любителей электроники. Она породила огромное сообщество энтузиастов, некоторые из которых основали собственные предприятия по производству программного и аппаратного обеспечения для ZX81. Многие из них в дальнейшем сыграли важную роль в британской компьютерной индустрии. Коммерческий успех ZX81 сделал Sinclair Research одним из ведущих британских производителей компьютеров и принес основателю компании сэру Клайву Синклеру состояние и рыцарское звание.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Компьютер</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sr_RS">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>The ZX81 is a home computer that was produced by Sinclair Research and manufactured in Dundee, Scotland, by Timex Corporation. It was launched in the United Kingdom in March 1981 as the successor to Sinclair's ZX80 and designed to be a low-cost introduction to home computing for the general public. It was hugely successful; more than 1.5 million units were sold. In the United States it was initially sold as the ZX-81 under licence by Timex. Timex later produced its own versions of the ZX81: the Timex Sinclair 1000 and Timex Sinclair 1500. Unauthorized ZX81 clones were produced in several countries.

The ZX81 was designed to be small, simple, and above all, inexpensive, with as few components as possible. Video output is to a television set rather than a dedicated monitor. Programs and data are loaded and saved onto compact audio cassettes. It uses only four silicon chips and a mere 1 KB of memory. There is no power switch or any moving parts with the exception of a VHF TV channel selector switch present in some models. It has a pressure-sensitive membrane keyboard. The ZX81's limitations prompted a market in third-party peripherals to improve its capabilities. Its distinctive case and keyboard brought designer Rick Dickinson a Design Council award.

The ZX81 could be bought by mail order preassembled or, for a lower price, in kit form. It was the first inexpensive mass-market home computer to be sold by high street stores, led by W. H. Smith and soon many other retailers. The ZX81 marked the point when computing in Britain became an activity for the general public rather than the preserve of businessmen and electronics hobbyists. It produced a huge community of enthusiasts, some of whom founded their own businesses producing software and hardware for the ZX81. Many went on to play major roles in the British computer industry. The ZX81's commercial success made Sinclair Research one of Britain's leading computer manufacturers and earned a fortune and an eventual knighthood for the company's founder Sir Clive Sinclair.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Computer</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="sv_SE">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>ZX81 är en hemdator som producerades av Sinclair Research och tillverkades i Dundee, Skottland, av Timex Corporation. Den lanserades i Storbritannien i mars 1981 som efterföljare till Sinclairs ZX80 och var utformad för att vara en billig introduktion till hemdatorer för den breda allmänheten. Den blev en stor framgång; mer än 1,5 miljoner enheter såldes. I USA såldes den ursprungligen som ZX-81 under licens av Timex. Timex tillverkade senare sina egna versioner av ZX81: Timex Sinclair 1000 och Timex Sinclair 1500. Oauktoriserade ZX81-kloner tillverkades i flera länder.

ZX81 var konstruerad för att vara liten, enkel och framför allt billig, med så få komponenter som möjligt. Videoutgången går till en TV-apparat i stället för till en särskild bildskärm. Program och data laddas och sparas på kompakta ljudkassetter. Den använder endast fyra kiselchip och ett minne på endast 1 KB. Det finns ingen strömbrytare eller några rörliga delar med undantag för en VHF TV-kanalväljare som finns i vissa modeller. Den har ett tryckkänsligt membrantangentbord. ZX81:ans begränsningar ledde till att det uppstod en marknad för kringutrustning från tredje part för att förbättra dess kapacitet. Dess distinkta hölje och tangentbord gav designern Rick Dickinson en utmärkelse från Design Council.

ZX81 kunde köpas via postorder färdigmonterad eller, till ett lägre pris, i byggsatser. Det var den första billiga hemdatorn för massmarknaden som såldes av stora butiker, med W. H. Smith i spetsen och snart även många andra återförsäljare. ZX81 markerade den punkt då databehandling i Storbritannien blev en aktivitet för allmänheten snarare än förbehållen affärsmän och elektronikhobbyister. Den gav upphov till en stor skara entusiaster, varav en del grundade egna företag som producerade mjukvara och hårdvara för ZX81. Många kom att spela en viktig roll inom den brittiska datorindustrin. ZX81:ans kommersiella framgångar gjorde Sinclair Research till en av Storbritanniens ledande datortillverkare och gav företagets grundare Sir Clive Sinclair en förmögenhet och så småningom en adelstitel.</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>Dator</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_CN">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>ZX81 是一款家用电脑，由辛克莱研究公司生产，Timex 公司在苏格兰邓迪制造。它于 1981 年 3 月在英国推出，是辛克莱 ZX80 的后继机，旨在以低成本向普通大众介绍家用电脑。该产品大获成功，销量超过 150 万台。在美国，它最初是作为 ZX-81 由 Timex 许可销售的。天美时后来生产了自己的 ZX81 版本：天美时 Sinclair 1000 和天美时 Sinclair 1500。一些国家生产了未经授权的 ZX81 克隆版。

ZX81 设计小巧、简单，最重要的是价格低廉，使用的组件越少越好。视频输出到电视机，而不是专用显示器。程序和数据加载并保存在小型录音磁带上。它仅使用四个硅芯片和 1 KB 的内存。除了某些型号的 VHF 电视频道选择开关外，没有电源开关或任何活动部件。它有一个压敏薄膜键盘。ZX81 的局限性催生了第三方外设市场，以提高其性能。其独特的外壳和键盘为设计者 Rick Dickinson 带来了设计委员会奖。

ZX81 可以通过邮购预先组装好，或者以较低的价格以套件形式购买。ZX81 是第一款由 W. H. Smith 和许多其他零售商主导的高街商店销售的廉价大众市场家用电脑。ZX81 标志着在英国，计算机已不再是商人和电子爱好者的专利，而成为一项大众活动。它造就了一个庞大的发烧友群体，其中一些人创办了自己的企业，为 ZX81 生产软件和硬件。许多人后来在英国计算机行业发挥了重要作用。ZX81 在商业上的成功使辛克莱研究公司成为英国领先的计算机制造商之一，并为公司创始人克莱夫-辛克莱爵士（Sir Clive Sinclair）赢得了一大笔财富和最终的爵士称号。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>计算机</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
    <language name="zh_TW">
        <variables>
            <systemDescription>ZX81 是一款家用電腦，由 Sinclair Research 製造，並由 Timex Corporation 在蘇格蘭 Dundee 生產。它於 1981 年 3 月在英國推出，是 Sinclair ZX80 的後繼機種，旨在以低成本向一般大眾介紹家用電腦。它大獲成功；銷售量超過 150 萬台。在美國，它最初以 ZX-81 的名義由 Timex 授權銷售。Timex 後來生產了自己的 ZX81 版本：Timex Sinclair 1000 和 Timex Sinclair 1500。一些國家生產了未經授權的 ZX81 克隆版。

ZX81 在設計上力求小巧、簡單，最重要的是價格低廉，使用的元件越少越好。視訊輸出至電視機，而非專用的螢幕。程式和資料會載入並儲存到小型音訊卡帶中。它只使用四顆矽晶片和僅 1 KB 的記憶體。除了某些型號的 VHF 電視頻道選擇開關之外，它沒有電源開關或任何移動零件。它有一個壓力感應薄膜鍵盤。ZX81 的限制促使第三方外圍設備市場來改善它的功能。其獨特的外殼和鍵盤為設計師 Rick Dickinson 帶來了設計委員會獎。

ZX81 可以通過郵購預先組裝好，或者以更低的價格以套件形式購買。它是第一台在高街商店銷售的廉價大眾市場家用電腦，以 W. H. Smith 為首，很快就有許多其他零售商銷售。ZX81 標誌著電腦在英國開始成為一般大眾的活動，而不再是商人和電子愛好者的專利。它造就了一個龐大的電腦愛好者社群，其中有些人成立了自己的公司，為 ZX81 製作軟體和硬體。許多人在英國電腦產業中扮演重要角色。ZX81 在商業上的成功使 Sinclair Research 成為英國領先的電腦製造商之一，並為公司創始人 Clive Sinclair 爵士贏得了一大筆財富和最終的爵士銜。</systemDescription>
            <systemHardwareType>電腦</systemHardwareType>
        </variables>
    </language>
</theme>
